本周的客人无需介绍，无需提前介绍。
This week's guest does not need any introduction, any advance.
El invitado esta semana no necesita ninguna presentación, ningún adelanto.
本周在 Clang，我们将与 Cunabuero 的爸爸聊天。
This week in Clang we are going to chat with the Cunabuero dad.
Esta semana en Clang vamos a charlar con el cunabuero papá.
很高兴您来到 Klan-Kun！
What a pleasure to have you here at Klan-Kun!
¡Qué placer tenerte acá en Klan-Kun!
很荣幸，感谢您的光临。
A pleasure, thanks for coming.
Un placer, gracias por venir.
不，不客气。
No, you're welcome.
No, de nada.
和你说话总是很有趣。
It's always fun talking to you.
Siempre es divertido hablar con vos.
让我们玩？
Let's Play?
¿Vamos a jugar?
我们会玩一会儿，叮叮当当，你知道为什么，当然我会向你解释一下
for a while we are going to play and clank clank you can know why of course I'm going to explain it to you
un rato vamos a jugar y clank clank se puede saber por qué claro te voy a te voy a explicar
这是球击中横梁时发出的声音。
It is the noise the ball makes when it hits the crossbar.
es el ruido que hace la pelota cuando pegan el travesaño.
这实际上来自篮球，我从他那里偷来的
that actually comes from basketball and I stole it from him
que en realidad viene del basket y se lo robé
向乔丹的队友透露，92年NBA在一个视频中发布了冠军球队的官方视频。
to a teammate of Jordan's that in the year 92 in a video the NBA released official videos of the champion teams.
a un compañero de Jordan que en el año 92 en un video la NBA sacaba videos oficiales de los equipos campeones.
公牛队以 92 分的成绩夺得第二个冠军，鲍比·汉森 (Bobby Hansen)
Bulls come out less in 92 for the second title and Bobby Hansen who was the
Bulls salen a menos en el 92 el segundo título y Bobby Hansen que era el
在芝加哥参加训练的12名球员中三分球命中率最差的球员
worst player of the 12 who played in Chicago in training shoots a three-point attempt
peor jugador de los 12 que jugaban en Chicago en un entrenamiento lanza un intento de triple
球击中篮筐，他说那是一个糟糕的投篮。
It hits the rim and he says That's a bad shot.
Pega en el aro y él dice That's a bad shot.
《叮当》是一个糟糕的镜头。
Clank is a bad shot.
Clank es un mal tiro.
我从那里偷了它。
And from there I stole it.
Y de ahí se lo robé.
30多岁了，老兄。
Over 30 years, man.
Más de 30 años, tío.
和那个绿色的小东西。
With the little green thing.
Con el cosito verde.
不，事实是它非常好，非常有趣。
No, the truth is that it is very good, fun.
No, la verdad es que es muy bueno, divertido.
嗯，很高兴，很高兴你来到这里。
Well, a pleasure, a pleasure to have you here.
Bueno, un placer, un placer tenerte acá.
干杯。
Cheers.
Felicidades.
谢谢。
Gracias.
你想象过35岁的自己是这样的吗？
Did you imagine yourself at 35 like this?
¿Te imaginabas a los 35 así?
不。
No.
你是怎么想象的？
How did you imagine?
¿Cómo te imaginabas?
嗯，我大概已经 29 岁、30 岁了，而且我
and well, I'm more or less at 29, 30 and I'm
y bueno yo más o menos ya los 29, 30 me está
想象一下
imagining that
imaginando que
最终以 32 分、33 分的成绩加盟曼城，这一点可以从那里看到。
to end up at City at 32, 33 that could be seen there.
para terminar en el City a los 32, 33 que por ahí se podía ver.
更新了，我不知道，一年，又两年，好吧，完成了。
renewed, I don't know, one year, two more years and well, it was done.
renovado, no sé, un año, dos años más y que bueno, que se hizo.
好吧，事情就到此结束，并在欧洲继续。
And well, that was where it ended, continuing in Europe.
Y bueno, ahí era terminar, seguir en Europa.
2022 年世界杯及之后
for the 2022 world cup and then after
por el mundial 2022 y luego después
世界杯结束后，也就是12月。
after the World Cup ended, which was precisely in December.
después que terminara el Mundial, que justamente ese Mundial era en diciembre.
在卡塔尔，然后将在六月结束，假设所有欧洲联赛都在六月结束。
in Qatar and then it would end in June, let's say that all European leagues end in June.
en Qatar y después terminaría en junio, digamos que todas las ligas europeas terminan en junio.
在那里我们将看看是否可以再继续一年，这取决于我的身体状况。
There we will see if we can continue for another year depending physically on how I am.
ahí ver si seguir un año más dependiendo físicamente cómo esté
那时我只是膝盖有问题，但身体状况很好
that at that time I only had a knee problem but physically I was quite well
que por ese momento sólo tenía un problema en la rodilla pero físicamente estaba bastante bien
好吧，我的想法是尝试看看我是否会回到阿根廷。
And well, the idea there was to try to see if I would return here to Argentina.
Y bueno, ahí la idea era tratar de ver si volvía acá a Argentina.
走向独立。
To Independent.
A Independiente.
显然是独立的，但我也不想
clearly independent but well I didn't want to either
claramente sea independiente pero bueno no tampoco quería
那一刻我想说，因为那是
At that moment I wanted to say because it was something that
en ese momento quería decir porque era algo que
这就是让那里的人们兴奋的地方。
That's what excites people there.
que por ahí es ilusionar a la gente por ahí.
能够让我在像以前那样的团队中多呆一年。
with something that is capable of giving me one more year in a team like it was.
con algo que capaz que se me da un año más en un equipo como fue.
巴萨，那个巴萨突然出现，更是不可能说不。
Barcelona, ​​that Barça suddenly appeared, it is impossible to say no and more.
el Barcelona, que de repente apareció el Barça, es imposible decir que no y más.
那时他即将和里奥一起踢球，并且即将参加世界杯。
that at that moment he was about to play with Leo and was coming to the World Cup.
que en ese momento estaba por jugar con Leo y venía al Mundial.
显然它是最近才能够出现的。
Obviously it was being able to come in recent times.
Obviamente era poder venir en los últimos tiempos.
显然，独立人士没有去，至少六个月，一年。
Six months, a year was, at least, obviously, independent people didn't go.
Seis meses, un año era, por lo menos, obviamente, la gente independiente no iba.
要我得到三四个，对吗？
to want me to get three or four, right?
a querer que me metiera tres o cuatro, ¿no?
是的，视情况而定。
Yes, depending.
Sí, dependiendo.
他们总是要求很高。
They are always quite demanding.
Siempre son bastante exigentes.
但是嘿，没关系。
But hey, that's fine.
Pero bueno, eso está bien.
但是，嘿，我们的想法是能够来这里玩。
But hey, the idea was to be able to come here and play.
Pero bueno, la idea era poder venir acá y jugar.
最后一场比赛，然后就扔掉球鞋。
the last games and from there throw away the boots.
los últimos partidos y a partir de ahí tirar los botines.
但好吧，那并没有发生。
But well, that didn't happen.
Pero bueno, no pasó eso.
2021 年是伟大的一年，因为你赢得了奖杯
The year 2021 is tremendous because you win the cup
el año 2021 es tremendo porque ganás la copa
美国队与巴西队的小伙子们一起，安杰利托在马拉卡纳球场进球。
America with the boys in Brazil, with Angelito's goal at the Maracaná.
América con los chicos en Brasil, con el gol de Angelito en el Maracaná.
在经历了 10 年不平凡的岁月后，您离开了这个网站，您以专业人士的身份离开了。
You leave the site after 10 extraordinary years, you leave as a pro.
te vas del sitio después de 10 años extraordinarios, te vas como como pro.
作为俱乐部历史上最重要的球员。
as the most important player in the club's history.
como el jugador más importante de la historia del club.
现在我们要谈谈您在曼彻斯特的生活以及您要去巴塞罗那
Now we are going to talk a little about your life in Manchester and you are going to Barcelona
Ahora vamos a hablar un poco de tu vida en Manchester y te vas a Barcelona
据说是和Leo一起玩。
Supposedly to play with Leo.
Supuestamente a jugar con Leo.
精确的。
Exact.
Exacto.
是啊，好吧，当...
Yeah, well, when...
Sí, bueno, cuando...
大约一月底的时候
when more or less the end of January
cuando ya en más o menos fines de enero
2021 年
of 2021
del 2021
贝壳城告诉我那边...
Shell City tells me that over there...
Shell City me dice que por ahí...
他们不会续约我
They were not going to renew me
no me iban a renovar
到了二月，他们最终或多或少地在二月中旬向我确认了这一点，你是否预料到了这一点，或者你是否预计他们会续签你的合同？
In February they end up confirming it to me more or less in the middle of February, let's make a point there. Did you expect that or did you expect that they would renew your contract?
en febrero me lo terminan confirmando más o menos a mitad de febrero hagamos un punto ahí esperabas eso o esperabas que te renovaran
不，我在等……其实我想再待一年……
No, I was waiting... actually I wanted to hang around for another year for...
No, yo estaba esperando... en realidad yo quería por ahí un año más por...
大多数情况下，这并不重要，我愿意坐在替补席上。
Mostly it doesn't matter, I was willing to be on the bench.
Sobre todo no importa, yo estaba dispuesto a estar en el banco.
因为显然佩普去年就已经来了
because obviously Pep was already coming last year
porque obviamente Pep ya el último año ya venía
时不时地打球，所以他显然愿意从另一个方面提供帮助
playing from time to time so he is obviously willing to help from another side
jugando de vez en cuando entonces está dispuesto obviamente a ayudar de otro lado
因为我觉得再在英超待一年
because I felt that being in the Premier for another year
porque sentía que estando un año más en la Premier
比方说，坐在替补席上，打得很少会对我有帮助
Being on the bench and playing little was going to help me, let's say
estando en el banco y jugando poco me iba a servir me daba digamos
作为一名物理学家能够参加世界杯。
as a physicist to be able to play in the World Cup.
como físico para poder jugar el mundial.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
这就是现实。
That was the reality.
Esa era la realidad.
不，当他们告诉我，好吧，没什么，显然这个想法是为了能够在欧洲继续下去
and no, when they told me, well, nothing, obviously the idea was to be able to continue in Europe
y no, cuando me dijeron bueno nada obviamente la idea era poder seguir en Europa
为了世界杯，一切都想着世界杯
for the world cup, everything was thinking about the world cup and
por el mundial, todo era pensando por el mundial y
好吧，接到电话，我的代表告诉我很好
and well a call comes up and my representative tells me well
y bueno surge una llamada y que mi repre bueno me dice
巴萨询问是否
Barça asked if
El Barça preguntó si
如果您愿意去那里，但在经济上他们无法支付给您城市支付给您的费用。
If you are willing to go there but financially they cannot pay you what the city pays you.
si estás dispuesto a ir para allá pero bueno económicamente no pueden pagarte lo que te paga el city
我告诉他，好吧，这对我来说并不重要，我不知道。
And I told him, well, it doesn't matter to me, I don't know.
Y yo le dije, bueno, a mí me da igual, no sé.
我的意思是，我知道花旗支付的费用......
I mean, I know that what Citi pays...
O sea, sé que lo que paga el Citi...
我的合同不会由任何大球队支付。
The contract I had was not going to be paid by any big team.
El contrato que tenía no lo iba a pagar ningún equipo grande.
因为他的年龄
because of the age he was
por la edad que tenía
所以我告诉他，让他们输入他们想要的任何数字并尝试修复它，这就是我告诉他的。
So I told him well, let them put whatever numbers they want and try to fix it, that's what I told him.
entonces le dije bueno que pongan ellos los números que quieran y trata de arreglarlo eso es lo que le dije a
对我来说，我代表什么都没有，很快就分成两部分，因为......
To me I repre and nothing, do it in two very quickly because...
a mi repre y nada, hacerlo en dos muy rápido porque...
好吧，最后不是我说我想要这个，他们说我们有这个，而且情况变得更好了。
Well, in the end it's not that I said I want this, they said we have this and well, and it got a little better.
Pues al final no es que yo dije quiero esto, ellos dijeron tenemos esto y bueno, y se mejoró un poquito más.
由于税务问题，有些事情我们不得不......
with some things due to tax issues because we had to...
con algunas cosas por tema impositivo porque había que...
昨天在西班牙付款，价格相当高，然后很快就修好了
to pay yesterday in Spain, which is quite high, and then it was fixed very quickly
que pagar ayer en España, que es bastante alto, y después se arregló muy rápido
好吧，当我快要结束巴萨的工作时，我告诉里奥，你看到了吗？
And well, when I was almost done with Barça, I told Leo, did you see?
Y bueno, cuando ya casi tenía cerrado con Barça, le digo a Leo, ¿viste?
然后当我告诉利奥他很高兴时，发生的一切就发生了。
And then when I told Leo he was happy and then everything that happened happened.
Y ahí cuando le digo a Leo estaba contento y después pasó todo lo que pasó.
没什么，我该怎么办？
Nothing, what am I going to do?
Que nada, ¿qué voy a hacer?
这是我...
It was something that I...
Era algo que yo...
我想象并很高兴能和他一起踢球，但这就是足球。
I imagined and was excited to play with him, but that's how football is.
Imaginé y me ilusionaba jugar con él, pero el fútbol es así.
事情的发生是你必须接受的。
and things happen that you have to accept.
y pasan cosas que hay que aceptarlo.
另外，7月份他们一起成为了美洲杯的冠军，8月份我们不见了，我们一起开始了另一个故事。
In addition, they become champions of the Copa América together in July, in August we don't see each other and we start another story together.
Además salen campeones juntos de la Copa América en julio, en agosto no vemos y empezamos otra historia juntos.
在巴塞罗那的俱乐部级别。
at club level in Barcelona.
a nivel club en Barcelona.
你怎么知道？
How do you find out?
¿Cómo te enterás vos?
狮子座不跟随，他告诉你，你从新闻中发现。
that Leo doesn't follow, he tells you, you find out from the news.
de que Leo no sigue, te lo cuenta él, te enterás por las noticias.
因为当我到达时，我已经在训练了，只是小腿不舒服
because when I arrived, well I was already training, I just had a discomfort in my calf
porque yo cuando llegué, bueno yo ya estaba entrenando, justo tuve una molestia en el gemelo
y
我不记得那是星期四还是星期三还是星期四。
I don't remember if it was a Thursday or Wednesday or Thursday.
no me acuerdo si fue un jueves o miércoles o jueves
我想那是星期四，当时...
I think it was Thursday when...
Creo que fue jueves cuando...
巴萨于周二宣布，他将于周一抵达巴塞罗那。
Barça announces and on Tuesday, he arrives in Barcelona on Monday.
el Barça anuncia y el martes, el lunes llega a Barcelona.
去训练，他告诉我他还不打算训练，因为他还没有准备好
to train and he told me that he wasn't going to train yet because he hadn't gotten ready
ya para entrenar y me dice que todavía no iba a entrenar porque no se había arreglado
周二我告诉他在他住的地方附近将会有一座房子
and on Tuesday I told him that there was going to be a house there near where he lived
y el martes yo le dije que iba a haber una casa por ahí por cerca de donde vivía él
他告诉我，我会陪你，我们一起去了，但仅此而已
and he told me well I'll accompany you and well we went together but that's it
y me dijo bueno te acompaño y bueno fuimos juntos pero hasta ahí
想象一下，他告诉我，我会陪你，因为我想象它现在就会修好。
Imagine, he tells me, I'll accompany you, because I imagined that it was going to be fixed by now.
Imagínate, me dice, te acompaño, porque yo me imaginaba que ya se iba a arreglar.
周三，也就是那件事发生的前一天，我们正在聊天，看看是否能见面。
And on Wednesday, the day before that happened, we were chatting to see if we would see each other.
Y el miércoles, un día antes de que pase eso, estuvimos charlando a ver si nos veíamos.
或者当我训练时，他告诉我是的，是的，几乎可以肯定这些天我训练，我不知道是明天还是后天，但我已经训练了。
or when I was training and he told me yes, yes, almost certainly these days I train, I don't know if tomorrow or the day after, but I already train.
o cuando entrenaba y me dijo si si ya casi seguro en estos días entreno no se si de mañana o pasado pero ya entreno
嗯，第二天下午，西班牙是下午六七点左右。
Well, the next day in the afternoon it was around 6 or 7 in the afternoon in Spain.
y bueno y al otro día a la tarde fue como 6 o 7 de la tarde de España
嗯，我和 Ibai 在一起，我正在教他如何喝马黛茶。
Well, I was with Ibai, I was teaching him how to drink mate.
Bueno, yo estaba con Ibai, le estaba enseñando a tomar mate.
我们都在那里发现了。
And we both found out there.
Y nos enteramos ahí los dos.
当然，想象一下 Ibai 整天都在那儿......
Of course, imagine that Ibai is there all day...
Claro, imagínate que Ibai está todo el día...
开玩笑，我不相信他，我想
Joking, I didn't believe him, I thought
bromeando, yo no le creí, pensé que
他还告诉我，我认为这就像假的，我们都说这是一个谎言
and he also told me I think it's like fake, we all said it was a lie
y él también me decía yo creo que es como que fake, todos decíamos que era mentira
好吧，在我问他之前，我只是说，这是真的吗？
And well, until I asked him, I just said, is it true?
Y bueno, hasta que le pregunté a él, le puse solamente ¿es verdad?
他说是的。
And he said yes.
Y me dijo sí.
我没有回答任何其他问题，因为我不知道该说什么。
I didn't answer anything else because I didn't know what to say.
No le contesté más nada porque no sabía qué decirle.
什么也没有，但是好吧，前几天之后......
And nothing, but well, after the other day...
Y nada, pero bueno, ya después del otro día...
我写信给他，然后我们就见面了。
I wrote to him and then we saw each other.
Le escribí y después el sado nos vimos.
嗯，那是相当
and well there it was quite
y bueno ahí estaba bastante
虽然情况很糟糕，但最终还是好的
quite bad for the situation but good in the end
bastante mal por la situación pero bueno al final
我，就像我一样，一如既往地试图以糟糕的方式看到里奥在国家队的表现。
I, as I am, try, as always, to have seen Leo in the national team in a bad way.
Yo, como soy yo, trate de, como siempre, haber visto mal a Leo en la selección.
我本来想跟他开玩笑，让他...
I was trying to make jokes with him, get him...
Trataba de hacerle bromas, sacarle...
别的事情让我们谈谈巴萨以外的事情
something else let's say talk about something other than Barça to
otra cosa digamos hablar de otra cosa que no sea el barça para
因为他脑子里会出现一些事情，当然，他会生病。
because things would come to him in his head and of course, he would get sick.
porque se le venían cosas a él en la cabeza y claro, se ponía mal.
好吧，我试图用这种方式分散他的注意力
and well I was trying to distract him that way
y bueno estaba intentada de distraerlo por ese lado
如果他随后召开新闻发布会，他也会开始哭泣，我是说，也会这样。
If he then holds a press conference, he starts crying, I mean, like that too.
si después hace una conferencia de prensa, se larga a llorar, o sea, como que también.
世界对他来说已经改变，他必须做出离开的决定。
The world changes for him, he has to make the decision to leave.
A él se le cambia el mundo, tiene que tomar la decisión de irse.
可用的位置并不多，除了历史上最好的之外，雷达上也没有太多俱乐部。
There weren't many places available, beyond being all-time best, there weren't many clubs on the radar.
No había muchos lugares disponibles, más allá de ser mejores todos los tiempos, no había muchos clubes en el radar.
不，不，事实是曼城就在那里，优秀的曼城永远在他身后。
No, no, the truth is City was there, the good City was always behind him.
No, no, la verdad igual estaba el City, el City bueno siempre estuvo atrás de él.
但好吧，他总是...
but well, he always...
pero bueno, él siempre...
他说这非常困难，因为对他来说巴塞罗那就是他的家。
He said that it was very difficult because for him Barcelona was his home.
Decía que era muy difícil porque para él el Barcelona era su casa.
他总是告诉我，来吧。
And he always told me, come on.
Y él me decía siempre, vení vos.
我告诉了他，我不记得我告诉了他什么，但对我来说，曼城也是我的家。
And I told him, and I don't remember what I told him, but for me City is also my home.
Y yo le decía, y yo no recuerdo qué le decía, pero para mí el City también es mi casa.
这非常复杂，因为我们总是试图一起玩。
which was very complicated because we both always sought to play together.
que era muy complicado porque los dos siempre buscábamos jugar juntos.
但是，是的，当他去巴萨的那一刻......
But yes, at that moment when he goes to Barça...
Pero sí, en ese momento que él se va al Barça...
或者是曼城、巴黎圣日耳曼，...以及...
or it was City, PSG, which... and...
o era el City, el PSG, que... y...
也许有些年轻人通常会这样做
maybe that's where the youth usually does
quizás por ahí la juventud que suele hacer
那些令人惊讶的事情
quite those surprise things
bastante esas cosas de sorpresa
但无论如何，他还是去了巴黎。
But anyway, he went to Paris.
Pero bueno, se fue al París.
好吧，那是一年半、两年。
And well, it was a year and a half, two years.
Y bueno, que estuvo un año y medio, dos años.
是的，两年，两年。
Yes, two years, two years.
Sí, dos años, dos años.
但好吧，没什么。
But well, nothing.
Pero bueno, nada.
你必须接受它，仅此而已。
You had to accept it and that's it.
Había que aceptarlo y ya está.
和他一起打球很令人兴奋，但是哦，好吧。
It's exciting to play with him, but oh well.
Es ilusionado jugar con él, pero bueno.
最终，在我打了三个半月、四个月之后，最让我心痛的事情发生在我身上。
In the end, after I played for three and a half, four months, the heart thing happened to me.
Al final después jugué tres meses y medio, cuatro meses y me pasó lo del corazón.
我在巴萨的时间很短，但事实是我度过了一段美好的时光。
My time at Barça was very short, but the truth is that I had a great time.
Fue muy cortito lo mío en el Barça, pero la verdad que la pasé muy bien.
非常好，他们对我很好，在这么大的俱乐部里起步并不容易
very good, they treated me very well, it is not easy at the beginning of a club this big
muy bien, me trataron muy bien que no es fácil que al principio de un club así grande
接受你本来的样子，然后……
accept you as you are and...
te acepte como sos y...
人们很快就对我产生了热情，这真是令人难以置信，看起来……
and how quickly people warmed to me, which was incredible, it seemed like...
y lo rápido que la gente tomó el cariño conmigo, que fue increíble, parecía que...
在梅西之后我来了，也许在里奥离开的那一刻
that after Messi I came and at one point perhaps at that moment when Leo leaves
que después Messi venía yo y en un punto quizás en ese momento cuando Leo se va
你看起来就像是那些亲密的人之一，很有魅力，不仅仅是拥有……
You looked like one of those close ones like that, charismatic, more than having...
quedaste como una de esas estrechas así, carismáticas, más de tener...
以前与巴塞罗那没有任何联系，人们也对你很着迷。
No previous link with Barcelona and people also clung to you.
Nulo vínculo previo con Barcelona y la gente también se aferró a vos.
不一样，但是……不，是的，除了同一个俱乐部……
It's not the same, but... No, yes, apart from the same club...
No es lo mismo, pero... No, sí, aparte el mismo club...
当 Leo 离开时，他给了我 10。
When Leo leaves he offers me the 10.
cuando se va Leo me ofrece la 10.
当然是10个。
The 10, of course.
La 10, claro.
我说，不，不，我会坚持我所拥有的。
And I said, no, no, I'm sticking with what I have.
Y yo dije, no, no, yo sigo con el que tengo.
我继续19。
I continued with 19.
Yo seguía con la 19.
他们给你10个。
They offer you 10.
Te ofrecen la 10.
他们给了我 10 个，我拒绝了，因为……
They offered me the 10 and I said no because not...
Me ofrecen la 10 y yo le dije que no porque no...
不是因为我不想使用它。
Not because I didn't want to use it.
No porque no quería usarla.
想象一下我在马竞、巴萨、独立队都使用过它。
Imagine that I used it at Atlético, at Barça, at Independiente.
Yo imagínate que la usé en el Atlético, en el Barça, en el Independiente.
在城市，但不是...
at City, but not...
en el City, pero no...
我不知道，我的意思是，这就像...
I don't know, I mean, it's like...
No sé, o sea, es como que...
我以为他稍后会回来，所以我说不，不让别人使用它，然后
I thought that later he was going to come back so like no I said no no let someone else use it and
creía que después él iba a volver entonces como que no no dije no no que la use otro y
他很安全，但好吧，他是巴萨唯一的一个人
He is safe, but well, the only one here at Barça
Está seguro, pero bueno, el único que acá en el Barça
我可以使用它，就是你，没有其他人......
I can use it, it's you, there is no other out there...
la puedo usar, sos vos, no hay otro, por ahí...
我们必须去安苏法蒂，我本来要去安苏法蒂，我......
We have to go to Ansu Fati and well I was going to Ansu Fati and I...
tenemos que ir a Ansu Fati y bueno andaba a Ansu Fati y yo...
我不去，我告诉他。
I'm not going, I tell him.
Yo no voy, le digo.
不是我，别打扰我，对我来说这是狮子座的第十宫，而且……
Not me, leave me alone here, for me it's the 10th of Leo and...
Yo no, déjame acá tranquilo, para mí la 10 de Leo y…
如果 Leo 在这里，我就不会使用它，所以也是一样的。
And if Leo is here, I'm not going to use it, so it was the same.
Y si Leo está acá, yo no la voy a usar, así que era lo mismo.
如果他不在那里，就不要让他最后被利用。
And if he is not there, let him not be used last.
Y si no está él, que no se use de última.
2021 年 10 月 30 日，一次巨大、激烈的 38 分钟，巴塞罗那。
October 30, 2021, tremendous, intense, 38 minutes, Barcelona at a time.
30 de octubre de ese 2021, tremendo, intenso, 38 minutos, Barcelona a la vez.
你的胸部开始疼痛。
Your chest starts to hurt.
te empieza a doler el pecho.
就是这样。
That's the thing.
Así es la cosa.
嗯，不疼。
Well, it doesn't hurt.
Bueno, no doler.
那里很多人都认为...
Many people there thought that...
Por ahí mucha gente pensaba que...
或者认为是胸部疼痛
or think it's a pain in the chest
o piensa que es un dolor en el pecho
我感觉自己快要被淹死了，不是痛，而是……
I felt like I was just drowning, it's not that I felt pain, I felt like...
Yo sentía como una sensación de que me estaba ahogando nomás, no es que sentía dolor, sentía como que...
我的心里压力很大。
I had a lot of pressure in my head.
tenía mucha presión en la cabeza.
所以我认为这是因为他...我不知道...
So I thought it was because of him... I don't know...
Entonces yo pensaba que era por el... no sé...
因为我刚刚回来参加比赛，我想这是我受伤后回来的第三场比赛。
because I just came back to play, it was my third game back after the injury, I think.
porque recién volví a jugar, era mi tercer partido que volvía después de la lesión, creo.
你在经典赛对阵阿拉马里的比赛中进球了吗？
Had you scored a goal in the Classic against Aramari?
¿Habías hecho un gol en el Clásico contra Aramari?
是的，而且我之前也参加过一场友谊赛。
Yes, and I also played in a friendly match before.
Sí, y jugué antes también en un partido amistoso.
一场欧冠比赛，然后是首发比赛。
a match in the Champions League and then a starting game.
un partido en Champions y después juego de titular.
是的，这是第三场比赛。
Yes, it was the third game.
Sí, era el tercer partido.
所以我想这是因为我身体有病。
So I figured it was because I was physically ill.
Entonces yo me imaginé que era porque estaba mal físicamente.
妈的，我太糟糕了，他说。
Shit, I'm so bad, he said.
La mierda, yo qué mal que estoy, decía.
因为我说，我累了，我的意思是，我感觉……
And because I say, I'm getting tired, I mean, I felt like...
Y porque digo, me estoy cansando, o sea, yo sentía que...
我再也受不了了，上气不接下气。
I couldn't take it anymore, I was out of breath.
no podía más, que me faltaba el aire
我恢复了，但就像我再次潜水，然后再次溺水，我感到头部有压力。
I recovered but it's like I took a dive again and I drowned again and I felt pressure in my head.
Recuperaba pero es como que volví a hacer un pique y volví a ahogarme y sentía presión en la cabeza.
好吧，现在到了最后......
And well, now reaching the end...
Y bueno, ya llegando al final...
我对作者感到恼火，但我更多地思考他为什么......
I felt annoyance at the author, but I thought more about why he was...
Sentía una molestia en el autor, pero pensaba más en el por qué me estaba...
对头部造成压力，并且在跳跃然后跳到头部的戏剧中表现得很好
causing that pressure on the head and well in a play that jumped then jumped to head
causando esa presión en la cabeza y bueno en una jugada que salto después salto a cabecear
好吧，他们同时接住球，球会与对方对抗，就在那时我开始寻找
and well, they catch the ball at the same time and it goes against the other and that's when I start looking to
y bueno la pelota la agarran a la vez y se va de contra y ahí es cuando yo empiezo a mirar para
为了我团队的目标，我就这样开始
for my team's goal and I start like that
para el arco de mi equipo y empiezo como que
头晕然后我就开始头晕
to get dizzy and then I started to get dizzy like that
a marearme y ahí sí empecé a marearme como que
我快要晕倒了，但我说，好吧，一定是……
I was going to faint, but I was like, well, it must be...
Me iba a desmayar, pero yo decía, bueno, debe ser que...
我必须放慢一切，所以我有点想冷静下来......
I have to slow down, everything, so I kind of wanted to calm down and...
tengo que bajar el ritmo, todo, entonces como que me quise tranquilizar y...
什么也没有，就在我想说点什么的时候，却没能说出来，只是
and nothing, and that's when I wanted to say something and the words didn't come out and just
y nada, y ahí fue que quería decir algo y no me salían las palabras y justo
他是在保卫阿拉伯人，我认为他是队长
He was in defense of the Arab, I think he was the captain
estaba en defensa del arabe, creo que era el capitán
他抓住了她的手，当然，他抓住了她的手
and he grabbed her hand, of course and he grabbed her hand
y le agarró la mano, claro y le agarró la mano
仿佛告诉他停止比赛，他开始尖叫
and as if telling him to stop the game and he started to scream
y como diciéndole para el partido y él bueno empezó a gritar
因为比赛还在继续，他开始尖叫、大喊大叫，直到裁判看到我，比赛就出现在那里，我就停了下来。
Because the play continued, he started screaming and yelling and until the referee saw me and the play just appeared there and I stopped.
porque la jugada seguía, empezó a gritar y a gritar y hasta que el árbitro me ve y justo la jugada aparece por ahí y paro.
就在它停止的时候，我感觉到了……好吧，直到那时我才感觉到任何东西。
and that's when it stops is where I feel... well until then I didn't feel anything.
y ahí cuando para es donde siento... pues yo hasta ahí no sentía nada.
我感到头晕目眩，然后就倒在了地板上。
I felt that I was getting dizzy and that's when I fell to the floor.
yo lo sentía que me estaba mareando y ahí cuando me tiro al piso
突然我的压力下降了
suddenly my pressure goes down
de repente como que me baja esa presión
我平静下来，然后我的心跳开始加快。
I calm down and just then my heart starts beating faster.
me tranquilizo y ahí no más empieza a latir el corazón más rápido.
心律失常袭击了我。
that the attack of arrhythmia seizes me.
que me agarra el ataque de la arritmia.
我，嗯，医生刚刚过来，碰了碰我说，哎呀。
And I, well, the doctor just came, touched me and said, oops.
Y yo, bueno, justo el médico viene, me toca y me dice, uy.
别担心，它会停止的，我说好吧，好吧，我已经说过了，我已经有过这样的一集了。
Don't worry, it's going to stop and I said well, well, I already said, I already had an episode like that.
tranquilo que se va a parar y yo dije bueno pues yo ya dije yo ya tenía algún episodio así
作为一个男孩和公平
as a boy and fair
de chico y justo
一周半之前，我在训练中也曾遇到过这种情况，但那只是 20 秒。
A week and a half before it had happened to me in training, but it was 20 seconds.
Una semana y media antes me había pasado en el entreno, pero fueron 20 segundos.
这件事持续了一分钟，我说哎呀，但他说不
and this was going on a minute and I said oops, but he said no
y esta iba a un minuto y yo decía uy, pero él decía no
他停下来告诉我冷静，冷静，好吧，过了一会儿他停了下来，冷静了下来。
He stopped and told me calm down, calm down and well, after a moment he stopped and calmed down.
para y me decía tranquilo tranquilo y bueno después de un momento para y se calmó
我不知道是一分半钟还是两分钟，但好像有二十分钟左右，明白吗？
I don't know if it was a minute and a half or two minutes, but it seems like it was like 20 minutes, see?
Yo no sé si fue un minuto y medio o dos minutos, pero parece que eran como 20 minutos, ¿viste?
什么都没有，好吧，我说好吧，就这样我会停下来
and nothing and there well I say well that's it I'll stop
y nada y ahí bueno yo digo bueno ya está me paro
他们带走了我，但我仍然感觉喉咙里有什么东西困扰着我，这就是为什么我那样抚摸自己。
and they took me but I still felt like something was bothering me here in my throat, that's why I touched myself like that.
y me llevan pero yo todavía sentía como que algo me molestaba acá en la garganta, por eso yo me tocaba así.
但并不是说很痛，就像你吃东西时看到的那样
but it wasn't that it hurt, it was like you saw when you eat something and it
pero no era que me dolía sino como que viste cuando comes algo y que se te
好吧，类似的事情也出现在这里，医生告诉我不，我们不要去。
Well, something similar came in here and the doctor told me no, let's not go.
se te entraba acá bueno algo parecido y el médico me dice no no vamos
不，他没有进来，我告诉他，不，但如果他问完时间，我告诉他，我可以打第二吗？
No, he doesn't come in and I tell him, no, but if he finishes asking for time I tell him, can I play second?
No, no entra y le digo, no, pero si ya termina de pedir el tiempo le digo, ¿puedo jugar el segundo?
他说，不，不，你不能玩第二个。
He says, no, no, you can't play the second one.
Dice, no, no, que no puedes jugar el segundo.
我说过，但它已经过去了。
I said, but it's already gone.
Yo decía, pero si ya se me fue.
不，不，我...
And no, no, and I...
Y no, no, y me...
他们带我去看医生，然后又带我去医院，当他们告诉我医院时，我说，哦，我认为情况很严重。
They took me to the doctor and from there to the hospital and when they told me hospital I said, oh, I think it's serious.
Me llevaron al médico y de ahí nomás al hospital y cuando me dijeron hospital yo dije, uy me parece que es grave.
碰巧直到那时我也采取了一切，这是一种心律失常，它消失了
It happens that until then I took everything as well, it was an arrhythmia and it goes away
pasa que yo hasta ahí lo tomaba todo como bueno fue una arritmia y se me va
治愈，仅此而已。
to cure and that's it.
a curar y ya está.
之后我住院4天。
Afterwards I was hospitalized for 4 days.
Después estuve 4 días internado.
医生告诉我，不行，你明天就走。
The doctor told me, no, you will leave tomorrow.
El médico me decía, no, mañana salís.
第二天我醒来
And the next day I woke up
Y al otro día me levantaba
他告诉我，好吧，我们必须在下午在某个地方再做一次检查......
and he told me, well, we have to do one more check in the afternoon, somewhere...
y me decía, bueno, tenemos que hacer un control más a la tarde, por ahí...
今晚你最好拥有它。
Tonight you better have it.
Esta noche mejor que te quede.
第二天也是同样的事情。
And the next day the same thing.
Y al otro día lo mismo.
然后我开始担心，开始变得有点紧张。
Then I started to worry and started to get a little nervous.
Entonces ya me empecé a preocupar y me empecé a poner un poco nervioso.
他告诉我不，别担心，一切都更有控制力
and he told me no, don't worry, it's all more control
y me decía no no tranquilo que es todo más control
然后他们将我从医院转移到诊所并进行所有治疗。
and then there they transfer me from the hospital to a clinic and do all the treatment.
y después ahí me trasladan del hospital a una clínica y me hacen todo el tratamiento
内心深处比
deeper inside than
de más profundo por dentro que
他们又对我做了一些检查，他们发现了一些东西，但他们必须继续。
They checked me a little more and there they were able to detect something, but they had to continue.
Me revisaron un poco más y ahí pudieron detectar algo, pero tenían que seguir.
让它贬值，然后花了大约一个半月两个月的时间他们才告诉我
devaluing it and well it took about a month and a half two months until they told me
desvaluándolo y bueno tardé unos un mes y medio dos meses hasta que me dijeron
他不可能继续打球了。
that it was impossible for him to continue playing.
que era imposible que siga jugando.
诊断或第一份声明说休息三个月然后返回。
diagnosis or the first statement says three months off and then returns.
diagnóstico o el primer comunicado dice tres meses de baja y después vuelve.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
12 月 15 日到了会议召开的时间，但是当他们告诉你，看看塞尔吉奥，你不能再踢足球了吗？
And that December 15th arrives at the time of the conference, but when they tell you, look Sergio, you can't play football anymore?
Y llega ese 15 de diciembre en el momento de la conferencia, pero ¿cuándo a vos te dicen, mira Sergio, vos no puedes jugar más al fútbol?
不，他们已经告诉我了
And no, they were already telling me
Y no, ya me venían diciendo
第四天进手术室的时候，
When I entered the operating room on the fourth day,
Cuando entré al quirófano el cuarto día,
当这件事发生在我身上之后，他们告诉我这是一种非常危险的节奏。
After it happened to me they told me it was a pretty dangerous rhythm.
después de que me pasó me dijeron que era una ritmía bastante peligrosa
但让我们花点时间
but let's take time
pero tomémonos tiempo
让我们看看这两个半月或三个月内的某个时候
Let's see if at some point in these two and a half or three months
a ver si en algún momento de estos dos meses y medio o tres
你得到一个心律失常，我们可以检测它是否是我们认为的来自那里的。
You get an arrhythme and we can detect if it is what we think is coming from there.
te agarra un arritme y podemos detectar si es la que nosotros creemos que viene de ahí.
好吧，就在那里，我就是一切
and well and there it was then I was everything
y bueno y ahí fue entonces yo era todo
一切休息，我正在服用一些药物，我不能走路或做任何事情。
all rest, I was taking some medications, I couldn't walk much or anything.
todo reposo, estaba tomando unos medicamentos, no podía caminar mucho ni nada.
他们希望我在前 15 天里能够充分休息。
They wanted me to rest completely for the first 15 days.
querían que haga totalmente los primeros 15 días reposo
然后20天后，好吧，我要去安道尔几天，了解一下它，分散自己的注意力。
Then after 20 days, well I'm going to Andorra for a few days to get to know it to distract myself.
después a los 20 días, bueno yo me voy unos días a Andorra a conocer para distraerme
我回来了，我就在那里
I come back and there I am
vuelvo y ahí me
他们告诉我，我们会给你植入芯片，看看这几个月内是否可以完成。
They tell me well, we'll put a chip on you to see if it can be done in these months.
me dicen bueno te ponemos un chip para ver si en estos meses se puede
检测到某物
detect something
detectar algo
我说，好吧，那是什么样的？
And I said, well, what is it like?
Y yo dije, bueno, ¿cómo es?
我以为我必须进手术室，他们要在这里给我开刀。
I thought I had to go into the operating room, they are going to open me up here.
Yo pensé que tenía que entrar al quirófano, me van a abrir acá.
最好不要，明天来吧，我们把你扔到这里，你就什么感觉也没有了。
Better not, come tomorrow, we'll throw you here and you won't feel anything.
Mejor no, vení mañana, te tiramos acá y no sentís nada.
我就这样打开你。
I open you like this.
Te abro así.
我说去他妈的吧，然后我就去了俱乐部
and I said fuck it and well and there I went to the club
y dije a la mierda y bueno y ahí fui al club
我躺下，他们刺伤了我，他们打开了我的身体，我……
I lay down and they punctured me there, they opened me and I...
me acosté y me pincharon ahí, me abrieron y yo...
感觉就像很痒，我的意思是，就像屎一样，然后我看到了这样的伤口，我……
It felt like it was itching, I mean, like shit and then I see a gash like that and I had...
Se sentía como que me picaba, digo, de la mierda y después veo un tajo así y tenía...
我的芯片还在这里，我现在必须把它拿出来。
I still have the chip here and I have to take it out now.
Todavía tengo el chip acá y me lo tiene que sacar ahora.
一个月后我做了一个分析
After a month I do an analysis
después al mes me hago un análisis
他们告诉我
and there they tell me that
y ahí me dicen que
一看，似乎就是他们所相信的那样，那就是室性心律失常，这是最复杂的。
Looking at it, it seems that it is what they believed, which is the ventricular arrhythmia, which was the most complicated.
Mirándolo parece que es la que ellos creían, que es la arritmia ventricular, que era la más complicada.
他们告诉我大约 90%。
And they told me about 90%.
Y me decían ya como un 90%.
我说，好吧，但还剩下 10%。
And I said, well, but there's still 10% left.
Y yo decía, bueno, pero todavía queda un 10%.
但我认为他们不想告诉我 100，比方说。
But I think they didn't want to tell me 100, let's say.
Pero yo creo que ellos no me querían decir el 100, digamos.
好吧，我又继续了大约 15 天，我再次进行了另一次分析。
And well, I continued that for about 15 more days, I did another analysis again.
y bueno yo seguí ese unos 15 días más me hago otra vez otro análisis
他们在那里告诉我，看，医生告诉我很好，布鲁加达，他告诉我
and there they told me, look, and the doctor told me well, brugada, he told me
y ahí me dijeron, mira, y el médico me dijo bien, brugada, me dijo
如果是我儿子我会告诉他不要再玩了。
If it were my son I would tell him not to play anymore.
Yo si fuera mi hijo le diría que no juegue más.
但如果你想继续，你就有责任继续
But if you want to continue, it is your responsibility to continue.
pero si vos querés seguir es tu responsabilidad que sigas
但它可能会再次发生在你身上，它可能会再次发生在你身上。
but it can happen to you again, it can happen to you again.
pero que te puede llegar a volver a pasar, te puede volver a pasar.
这种事不会再发生在你身上了，呵呵。
That doesn't happen to you anymore, huh.
Por ahí no te pasa más, eh.
也许……但是……
Maybe... But...
Capaz que... Pero...
我必须告诉你会发生什么，这是最危险的，我认为......
I have to tell you what can happen and it is the most dangerous and I think that...
te tengo que decir que puede pasar y es la más peligrosa y yo creo que...
我不应该继续。
I shouldn't continue.
no debería seguir.
我说，好吧，就是这样。
And I said, well, that's it.
Y yo dije, bueno, ya está.
33、我说好吧，还有两年，我还剩三年，就这样了。
33, I said well, two more years, I had three years left and that was it.
33, dije bueno, dos años más, me quedaba tres años y ya estaba.
所以，如果我年轻的话，我会有不同的想法，或者采取其他治疗方法......
So if I was younger I thought about it differently or did other treatments than that...
por ahí si era más chico lo pensaba de otra manera o hacía otros tratamientos que por ahí...
今天，就像埃里克森那样，他安装了起搏器，做了其他事情，嗯，就是这样。
Today, like Ericksen did, he put in the pacemaker, did other things, and well, that's it.
Hoy, como Ericksen que hizo, se puso el marcapasos, hizo otras cosas, y bueno, pero ya.
我说，好吧，就是这样，好吧，我花了大约十天的时间来考虑。
and I said, well, that's it, and well, it took me about ten days to think about it.
y dije bueno listo ya está y bueno tardé unos diez días en pensarlo
直到我的全家，我的儿子，一切......
until my whole family, my son, everything...
hasta que toda mi familia, mi hijo, todo...
没有人希望我继续
and no one wanted me to continue
y nadie quería que siga
好吧，好吧，我内心说，好吧，但也许这不会发生在我身上，你看，这是你的头脑。
And well, well, inside I said, well, but maybe it doesn't happen to me, you see, it's your head.
Y bueno, pues yo por dentro decía, bueno, pero como, capaz que no me pasa, viste, es tu cabeza.
不，不，他要冒这个险，直到……
and no, no, he's going to take the risk and well, until...
y no, no, que va al pedo a arriesgar y bueno, hasta que...
一周前我说准备好了，就这样了，我和巴萨谈过并说
a week before I said ready, that's it and I spoke with Barça and said
una semana antes ya dije listo ya está y hablo con el Barça y digo
找到另一个前锋就可以了。
Find another striker and that's it.
busquen otro delantero y listo.
疼痛也是一个问题，如果你想象我说我想继续
and the pain was also a problem for that, if you imagine me saying I want to continue
y el barzo también para ello también era un problema que si imaginate que yo diga quiero seguir
但他们也都同意，包括医生在内的一切，继续下去并不理想。
But they also all agreed, the doctors, everything, that it was not ideal to continue.
pero ellos también estaban todos de acuerdo, los médicos, todo, que no era lo ideal seguir.
本贾是怎么告诉你的？
How did Benja tell you?
¿Cómo te lo dijo Benja?
不，本贾通过语音信息告诉我。
No, Benja told me by voice message.
No, Benja me lo dijo por mensaje de voz.
我的意思是，我们正在谈话，然后...
I mean, we were talking and...
O sea, estábamos hablando y...
他告诉我，不，爸爸，不，不要继续，这太糟糕了。
And he told me, no, pa, no, don't continue, it's too bad.
Y me dijo, no, pa, no, no sigas, es al pedo.
我告诉他，好吧，好吧，没关系。
And I told him, well, well, it's okay.
Y yo le decía, bueno, bueno, está bien.
但好吧，我...就像...也...
But well, I... it's like... also...
Pero bueno, yo... es como que... también...
我真的不想让他担心，你明白吗？
I didn't really want to worry him, you see?
No lo quería mucho preocupar a él, ¿viste?
我不想告诉他，伙计，不，不，是的，我会停下来，因为我可能会发生一些事情，我不知道会发生什么。
I didn't want to tell him, man, no, no, yes, I'll stop because something could happen to me, I don't know what.
No le quería decir, tipo, no, no, sí, dejo porque me puede pasar algo, no sé qué.
所以我说好吧，好吧，好吧，我会考虑一下，但是......
So I said well, well, okay, I'll think about it, but...
Entonces yo decía bueno, bueno, está bien, lo voy a pensar, pero...
不，但是和 Benja 在一起我们更像朋友一样交谈
No, but with Benja we talk much more like friends
No, pero con Benja hablamos bastante más como amigos
我对待他更像是朋友，我的儿子也很好，但是
I treat him more like a friend and also how good my son is but
yo lo trato más como como un amigo y además que bueno es mi hijo pero
我尝试建立一种非常好的关系，就像友谊一样。
I try to have a very good relationship in that sense like a friendship.
trato de tener muy buena relación en ese sentido como una amistad.
新闻发布会的时间到了，我想你已经准备好了演讲。
And the time comes for the press conference and I imagine you had a speech prepared.
y llega el momento de la conferencia de prensa que me imagino tenías preparado un discurso
但它落在你所有的牌上。
But it falls on all your cards.
Pero se te cae en todas las fichas.
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
我不知道，我没有发言。
I don't know, I didn't have any speech.
No sé, no tenía ningún discurso.
我不知道，我当时...
I don't know, I was...
No sé, yo fui...
好吧，他知道自己要说什么，假设是……
And well, he knew what he had to say, let's say it was...
Y bueno, se sabía lo que tenía que decir, digamos que era...
宣布我要离开，并且我将感激所发生的一切
announce that I was going to leave and that I was going to be grateful for everything that
anunciar que iba a dejar y que iba a estar agradecido con todo lo que
俱乐部，他们如何对待我，但是
the club, how they treated me, but
el club, como me trataron, pero
但自从那件事发生在我身上以来，我就一直在路上。
But I was well on my way, I had been since that happened to me.
Pero yo venía bien encima, venía desde que me pasó eso.
他很平静地对待这件事，还开玩笑。
He was taking it calmly, with jokes.
Venía tomándolo con tranquilidad, con bromas.
我时不时地会直播来分散自己的注意力。
From time to time I would stream and to distract myself.
De vez en cuando hacía stream y para distraerme.
但那天的情况就是这样，当然我……
But that day it was like that when, of course I had...
Pero ese día era como que ahí cuando, claro que tenía...
我必须公开说出来，这是我无法忍受的地方。
I had to say it publicly, it was where I couldn't stand it.
Lo tenía que decir públicamente, fue donde no aguanté.
这就是我一直坚持的，因为我无法停止哭泣，为什么不呢？
That was all I had been holding on to because I couldn't stop crying because why not?
por ahí era todo lo que venía aguantando pues no para de llorar porque porque no
我什至无法说话。
I couldn't even speak.
No podía ni hablar.
离开之前我开始哭泣。
Before I left I started crying.
Ya antes de salir ya me puse a llorar.
但我不能。
and I couldn't.
y no pude.
如果没有的话，我……我的意思是，我很难哭。
If not, I'm... I mean, I'm pretty tough at crying.
Si no yo soy... o sea, para llorar bastante duro soy.
那天你所有的屁股都会融化。
That day all your buttocks will melt.
Ese día se te cajeron todas las nalgas.
不，不，是的，我无法说话，我什至不知道该说什么。
No, no, yes, I couldn't speak and I didn't even know what to say.
No, no, sí, no podía hablar y ya ni sabía ni qué decir.
所以...但是好吧...
so... but well...
así que... pero bueno...
但好吧，我也有同样的感觉……
But well, I feel the same very...
Pero bueno, me siento igual muy...
非常高兴，我为我所做的一切感到非常自豪。
very happy, I feel very proud of everything I did.
muy feliz, me siento muy orgulloso de todo lo que hice.
你总是想并说，好吧，我本可以多付出一点，好吧，这很正常。
You always think and say, well, I could have given a little more, and well, that's normal.
siempre uno piensa y dice bueno podía dar un poquito más y bueno eso es normal
但是，嘿，我所做的一切我都很高兴。
But hey, with everything I did I am very happy.
Pero bueno, con todo lo que hice estoy muy feliz.
我的意思是，这并不容易
I mean, it's not easy
O sea, no es fácil
现在我已经放弃了我所做的一切，事实是他认为并且......
one now that I have left everything I did, the truth is that he thinks and...
uno ahora que ya dejé todo lo que hice, la verdad que piensa y...
这并不容易，而且中间还有世界杯，也就是说，这不仅仅是停止踢球。
and it's not easy and also in the middle there was the World Cup, that is, it wasn't just about stopping playing ball.
y no es fácil y además en el medio estaba el mundial o sea no era solamente dejar de jugar a la pelota
但没能参加世界杯。
but not being able to be in the World Cup.
sino no poder estar en el Mundial.
那件来自卡塔尔的特定作品是在什么时候掉落的？
At what point did that specific piece, the one from Qatar, fall?
¿Esa ficha concreta, la de Qatar, en qué momento se cayó?
不，好吧，让我们看看，首先显然是要赢得......
No, well, let's see, first obviously to win the...
No, bueno, a ver, primero obviamente que ganar el...
参加世界杯是每个人的梦想。
Going to the World Cup is everyone's dream.
Ir al Mundial es el sueño de todos.
但我很平静，因为我还得知我们赢得了美洲杯。
But I was calm because I had also learned that we had won the Copa América.
Pero yo estaba tranquilo porque me había sacado también eso de que habíamos ganado la Copa América.
所以我已经松了一口气，因为我离开了......
So I was already relieved in the sense that I left with...
Entonces yo ya estaba aliviado en el sentido de que me fui con...
至少这不是世界杯，但我要离开的是美洲杯
with something at least it's not the World Cup but well it was the Copa América that I'm going to have left for
con algo por lo menos no es la de Copa del Mundo pero bueno era la Copa América que me va a quedar para
一生，我相信世界杯之后
for life and I believed that after the World Cup
para toda la vida y yo creía que después en el mundial
我觉得和他们在一起是我的一部分，我想要的就是他们
I felt part of being with them and all I wanted was for them to
me sentía parte de estar con ellos y yo lo único que quería era que
这显然进展顺利，因为我认为
that is obviously going well because because I thought that
que obviamente le vaya bien porque porque yo pensaba que
如果心脏的事没有发生在我身上...
If the heart thing hadn't happened to me...
Si a mí no me hubiese pasado lo del corazón...
我的身体上不会发生任何事情。
and nothing would have happened to me physically.
y no me hubiese pasado nada físicamente.
他有能力参加世界杯。
capable that he was going to be in the World Cup.
capaz que iba a estar en el Mundial.
和男孩们在一起，所以我感觉自己是这个团体的一部分，我认识他们所有人，
with the boys, so I felt part of that group, I know them all and
con los chicos, entonces yo me sentía parte de ese grupo, los conozco a todos y
我觉得如果他们赢了，我也赢了。
And I felt that if they won, I won too.
Y sentía que si ellos ganaban, yo también ganaba.
那是我的头。
That was my head.
Esa era mi cabeza.
但心情却非常平静。
But it was very calm.
Pero estaba muy tranquilo.
紧张是因为世界杯与外界的体验不同。
nervous because the World Cup is experienced differently outside.
nervioso porque se vive el Mundial de otra manera afuera.
但很平静
but it was calm
pero estaba tranquilo
就我而言，我随美洲杯离开了国家队。
For my part, I had left the national team with the Copa América.
por mi lado, que me había ido de la selección con la Copa América.
但世界杯即将到来，我显然希望他们为利奥赢得冠军。
But the World Cup was coming and I wanted them to win it for Leo, clearly.
pero venía el mundial que yo quería que lo ganen por Leo, claramente.
我知道当你做出决定时，有很多人打电话给你，告诉他们退休的消息。
I know that there were many people who called you when you made the decision and informed them about the retirement.
Sé que hubo mucha gente que te llamó cuando tomaste la decisión y la comunicaste del retiro.
你没想到会这样称呼你的人
people you didn't expect to call you that
gente que no esperabas que te llamara así como
和你一样，当里奥在国家队表现不佳时，他就是那个开玩笑的人，也是那个为他创造一个让他开心或分心的人。
Like you, when Leo was bad in the national team, he was the one who made jokes and the one who created a context for him to have fun or be distracted.
como vos cuando Leo estaba mal en la selección era el que hacía bromas y el que le generaba un contexto para que él se divirtiera o se distrajera
当他们当时打电话给你时，谁让你感到惊讶？
Who surprised you when they called you at that moment?
¿Quienes te sorprendieron cuando en ese momento te llamaron?
我不记得了，但是，是的，很多。
And I don't remember anymore, but yes, a lot.
Y ya no me acuerdo, pero sí, un montón.
一支乐队。
A band.
Una banda.
我不知道，告诉你我所知道的。
I don't know, to tell you, what I know.
No sé, por decirte, qué sé yo.
突然托蒂和我说我们一起比赛但是
suddenly Totti and I say well play against but
de repente Totti y digo bueno juegue en contra pero
他不知道怎么办
he don't know how
él no sé cómo
我不知道，消息，数千条消息，但不再是因为我正在回复。
I don't know, messages, thousands of messages, but not anymore because I was answering.
no sé, mensajes, miles de mensajes, pero ya ni más porque iba contestando.
谢谢，谢谢，谢谢。
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Gracias, gracias, gracias.
是的，但我告诉你，是的，有很多教练。
Yes, but I tell you, yes, many coaches.
Sí, pero te digo, sí, muchos entrenadores.
还有很多我从未见过的球员。
and many players that I had not even seen.
y muchos jugadores que yo ni lo había visto.
我的意思是，我从来没有说过话，比如说，但是...
I mean, I never had a talk, let's say, but...
o sea, nunca tuve una charla, digamos, pero...
现实情况是，当...
The reality is that when...
La realidad es que cuando...
我几乎想告诉你，我扔掉了手机，这么说吧。
I would almost tell you that I threw away my cell phone, to put it that way.
casi te diría que tiré el celular, por decirte así.
因为我知道将会有数千条消息到达。
because I knew that thousands of messages were going to arrive.
porque sabía que iban a llegar miles de mensajes.
从这个意义上说，我想保持冷静，但是……
I wanted to be calm, let's say, in that sense, but yes...
Yo quería estar tranquilo, digamos, en ese sentido, pero sí que...
很多玩家都给我写信。
A lot of players write to me.
que me escriben un montón de jugadores.
我不会说出这些名字，因为我要开始谈论关于曼城、关于巴萨的一切。
I'm not going to say the names because I'm starting to say everything about City, everything about Barça.
No voy a decir los nombres porque empiezo a decir todo lo del City, todo lo del Barça.
我在马德里竞技踢过的大部分比赛都是我没有想到的。
most of the Atlético de Madrid that I have played when I was there, which I didn't even expect.
la mayoría del Atlético de Madrid que yo he jugado cuando estaba ahí, que ni me lo esperaba.
独立人民、总统、
independent people, presidents,
gente independiente, presidentes,
很多，政客，一切。
a lot, politicians, everything.
un montón, políticos, todo.
我说了这么多，我说了这么多。
that I said, well, so much, I say.
que yo decía, bueno, tanto, digo.
但是，嘿，很高兴，因为每个人......
But hey, very happy because everyone...
Pero bueno, muy contento porque todos...
他们了解我在足球领域所做的一切。
They knew me for everything I did in football.
Me conocían por todo lo que hice en el fútbol.
这是一件非常好的事情，你参加了三届成年世界杯。
It's something very nice, you played in three senior World Cups.
es algo muy lindo jugaste tres mundiales de mayores
你是两届青年世界冠军，2008年奥运会冠军，也就是说，你有国家队的职业生涯。
You were two-time youth world champion, Olympic champion in 2008, that is, you have a career in the national team.
fuiste bicampeón mundial juvenil, campeón olímpico en 2008, o sea tenés un recorrido en la selección
令人印象深刻，最终您以 2021 年美洲杯的成绩结束了比赛。
impressive and you finish it with the Copa América 2021.
impresionante y lo terminás con la Copa América 2021.
我想让你告诉我那是什么感觉。
I want you to tell me a little about what that was like.
Quiero que me cuentes un poco cómo fue esa
你说美洲杯的庆祝活动意义非凡，但是……
That celebration of the Copa América, which meant something, you said but...
esa celebración de la Copa América, que significó algo contaste pero...
我希望我们能够为你、为利奥、为奥塔、为迪玛利亚，以及加入该团体的男孩们，深入下去。
I would like us to go deeper for you, for Leo, for Ota, for Di María, in addition to the boys who joined that group.
Me gustaría profundicemos para vos, para Leo, para Ota, para Di María, además de los chicos que se sumaron a ese grupo.
是的，我们有，有 Gota、Fideo、我和 Leo
Yes, well we had, well there was Gota, Fideo, me and Leo
Sí, bueno nosotros teníamos, bueno estaba Gota, Fideo, yo y Leo
我和其他人都很大，不是我们四个人，我们四个人
and me and whoever else was very big, there were not four of us, the four of us
y yo y quien más estaba de lo más grande, no éramos cuatro, los cuatro
对我们来说，赢得美洲杯是一种解脱。
For us, winning that Copa América was a relief.
Para nosotros ganar esa Copa América fue un alivio.
这就是我们一直在寻找的幸福。
and it was a happiness that we had been looking for.
y fue toda una felicidad que lo veníamos buscando.
几年前。
years ago.
hacía años.
太好了，我们赢了
So well, we won.
Así que bueno, ganamos
我想，除了塔门迪之外，我们大多数人都赢了。
Most of us all won, except Tamendi, I think.
La mayoría de todos ganamos, salvo Tamendi, creo.
赢得 U-20 世界杯和奥运会的伟大球员。
of the greats who won the U-20 World Cup and the Olympic Games.
de los grandes que ganamos el Mundial Sub-20 y los Juegos Olímpicos.
但与老大仍然一无所获。
but with the eldest still nothing.
pero con la mayor todavía nada.
那届美洲杯对我们来说是……
That Copa América for us was...
Esa Copa América para nosotros fue...
让我们说，一种解脱，一种信心
Let's say, a relief, a confidence that
digamos, un alivio, una confianza que
我们已经在考虑世界杯了，所以这让我们想说，嘿，好吧......
We were already thinking about it for the World Cup, so that made us feel like saying, hey, well...
que lo veníamos ya pensando para el Mundial, o sea que eso nos dio como diciendo, che, bueno...
现在我们可以赢得世界杯，因为确实已经......
Now we can win the World Cup, because it is true that already...
Ahora podemos ganar el Mundial, porque es verdad que ya...
保罗和所有男孩，明白吗？
of Paul and all the boys, see?
de Paul y todos los chicos, ¿viste?
帕雷德斯、巴勃罗、利奥，他们所有人。
Paredes, Pablo, Leo, all of them.
Paredes, Pablo, Leo, todos.
我们本来以为如果我们赢得了美洲杯，就要小心了！
We had thought that if we win the Copa América, be careful!
teníamos pensado que si ganamos la Copa América, ¡ojo!
看，我们可以赢得世界杯，所以我们已经做好了准备，因为......
Look, we can win the World Cup, so we were already psyching ourselves up because...
mirá que podemos ganar el Mundial, entonces ya nos veníamos mentalizando porque...
我们刚刚输掉了很多次决赛，但我们赢了这一场，除此之外，另一年世界杯也来了
We had just lost a lot of finals and we won this one and on top of that the World Cup came the other year
veníamos de perder un montón de finales y ganamos esta y encima venía el otro año el mundial
就像我们认为这是我们的一样。
It was like we thought that this is ours.
Era como que pensábamos nosotros que esta es nuestra.
事实上，美洲杯也在巴西举行
and the truth is that that Copa América was also in Brazil
y la verdad que esa Copa América además que fue en Brasil
我们知道我们必须进入决赛，然后对阵轮到我们的对手。
We knew that we had to reach the final, then against whoever it was our turn.
Nosotros sabíamos que teníamos que llegar a la final, después contra quien nos tocaba.
我们知道，那里可能又是智利或巴西。
We knew that out there it could be Chile or Brazil again.
Sabíamos que por ahí podría ser Chile o Brasil otra vez.
但好吧，我再说一遍智利，但巴西在那里
but well chile again I say but brazil there
pero bueno chile otra vez digo pero brasil por ahí
因为你是本地人，有时你会看到本地选手通常不会进入决赛。
Because you are a local, sometimes you saw that the local player does not usually reach the final.
Por ser local, a veces viste que el que juega local no suele llegar a la final.
我们更关心智利，他们已经输掉了两次决赛。
We were more concerned with Chile, which had already lost two finals.
estábamos más pendientes con Chile, que ya habíamos perdido dos finales.
但是，碰巧是在巴西，在巴西......
but well, it happened that it was with Brazil, in Brazil and...
pero bueno, pasó que era con Brasil, en Brasil y...
但事实是，我看到了孩子们，因为我在另一边，我在那里帮助球队。
But the truth is that I saw the boys because I was on the other side and I was there helping the team.
pero los chicos la verdad que yo lo veía pues yo estaba de otro lado y yo ahí bueno ayudando al equipo
致几场比赛前来的那些人。
to the guys who came a few games ago who were there.
a los chicos que venían hace pocos partidos que estaban ahí.
试图赢得他们逐渐获得的群体的信任
trying to gain confidence with the group that they gradually gained
tratando de que agarren confianza con el grupo que fueron de a poco agarrando
很有信心。
A lot of confidence.
Mucha confianza.
好吧，看看 Polsha 的肩包。
Well, look at Polsha's shoulder bag.
Bueno, mirad de polsha el magarrón del hombro.
但是，我的意思是，我们的关系非常好，而我是最后一个……
But, I mean, there was a very good relationship and I was the final one...
Pero, digo, había muy buena relación y yo la final...
我很紧张，但我看到他们很平静。
I was very nervous but I could see that they were calm.
Estaba muy nervioso pero veía que ellos estaban tranquilos.
当上半场我们1-0的时候
and when the first half we go 1-0
y cuando el primer tiempo nos vamos con 1-0
狮子座感到坐骨不舒服
Leo feels discomfort in his ischium
Leo siente una molestia en el isquio
他走向担架，我走过去说，你还好吗？
and he goes to the stretcher and I went and said, are you okay?
y se va a la camilla y yo fui y le digo ¿estás bien?
他说是的。
and he says yes.
y me dice sí.
在那里我听到斯卡洛尼告诉利奥我们已经所剩无几了。
and there I hear Scaloni telling Leo that we have very little left.
y ahí lo escucho a Scaloni que le dice a Leo que nos falta muy poquito.
我的意思是，我想如果...
I mean, there I thought if...
O sea, yo ahí pensé si...
然后，当然，你开始计算并说，是的，是的，还剩 45 分钟。
And then, of course, you start to calculate and say, yes, yes, there are 45 minutes left.
Y ahí, claro, uno empieza a calcular y decir, sí, sí, faltan 45 minutos.
该死，然后我又去了更衣室，莱昂在那里，担架在浴室附近，然后……
Damn, then I go to the locker room again, where León was, the stretcher was near the bathroom and...
La puta madre, entonces voy al vestuario de nuevo, donde estaba León la camilla era cerca al baño y...
我们都坐的地方，就在它旁边。
where we were all sitting, was there next to it.
donde estábamos todos nosotros sentados, estaba ahí al lado.
没有听到。
It was not heard.
No se escuchaba.
所以，我回来查看了一切，然后说，伙计们，还有 95 岁，是吗？
So, I came back and looked at everything and said, guys, 95 to go, huh?
Entonces, volví y miraba todo y decía, muchachos, falta 95, ¿eh?
仿佛绝望地希望我们能够忍受一切。
As if desperate for us to endure everything as we can.
como desesperado de que aguantemos todo como podamos.
并赢得它但是但是它
and win it but but it
y ganarlo pero pero lo
当一切结束后，事实是，那是令人难以置信的幸福。
And when it was all over, well, the truth is that it was incredible happiness.
Y eso cuando terminó todo, bueno, la verdad que fue una felicidad increíble.
对于每个人，尤其是利奥来说，这就是他所希望的。
for everyone and especially Leo, which was what I was wishing for.
para todos y sobre todo Leo que era lo que estaba deseando
他总是说他想在阿根廷踢球。
who always said he wanted to play in Argentina.
que siempre dijo que quería jugar en Argentina.
这是一个建立起来的团队。
It was a team that was built.
Fue un equipo que se fue construyendo.
我记得2019年美洲杯，球队的开局并不好，而是以不同的方案开始。
I remember the 2019 Copa América, the team is not starting well, it is starting with a different scheme.
Me acuerdo de la Copa América 2019, el equipo no arranca bien, arranca con un esquema diferente.
人们输给哥伦比亚，战平巴拉圭，阿玛尼扑出了点球。
people lose with Colombia, draw with Paraguay, Armani saves the penalty.
gente pierde con Colombia, empata con Paraguay, Armani ataja el penal.
你进来，你离开，你再进来，
you enter, you leave, you enter again,
vos entras, salís, volvés a entrar,
梅西、博西和劳塔罗一起踢球，对阵卡塔尔队
In a match Messi, Bossi and Lautaro play together, which is against Qatar in
en un partido juegan Messi, Bossi y Lautaro juntos que es contra Catar en
这是波尔、帕雷德斯和洛塞尔索当天一起打得最多的第三场比赛。
the third game that Pol, Paredes and Los Celso played the most together that day.
el tercer partido que ese día más jugan de Pol, Paredes y Los Celso juntos.
甚至斯卡罗尼本人也说他和你谈论过切。
And even Scaloni himself said that he spoke with you about Che.
Y hasta el propio Scaloni contó que habló con ustedes respecto de Che.
让你在球场上感觉良好的最佳方式是什么？
What is the best way for you to feel good on the court?
¿Cuál es la mejor forma para que ustedes se sientan bien dentro de la cancha?
你是这个过程的一部分，我希望你能告诉我们一些信息。
And you were part of that process, I would like you to tell us a little.
Y vos formaste parte de ese proceso, me gustaría que nos contaras un poco.
如果你愿意的话，世界冠军是如何诞生的？
How was the birth, if you like, of what was the world champion.
cómo fue el nacimiento, si querés, de lo que fue el campeón del mundo.
是的，不，我读过斯卡洛尼的文章，对吗？
Yes, no, I read what Scaloni had, right?
Sí, no, leo lo que tenía Scaloni, ¿no?
他离我们很近，他会问你问题，如果他看到什么，他会......
He is very close to us and he asks you questions and if he sees something he will...
es muy cercano a nosotros y te va preguntando y si ve algo te...
他告诉你，这对你来说似乎很好，对你来说似乎很糟糕，并且
He tells you that this seems good to you, it seems bad to you and
te dice che esto te parece bien te parece mal y
对我来说，例如，在美洲杯上......
For me, for example, in the Copa América...
A mí, por ejemplo, en la Copa América...
塞尔吉奥告诉我，听着，我不保证你会参加比赛，但是......
Sergio told me, look, I don't promise you that you're going to play but...
Me dijo Sergio, mirá que no te prometo que vas a jugar pero...
我肯定会需要你，并且希望当我需要你的时候你能及时出现。
I'm going to need you for sure and I want you to be available when I need you.
te voy a necesitar seguro y quiero que estés disponible o sea cuando yo te necesite
我说，是的，狮子座，算了，我就在这里，显然当你需要我的时候，我就在这里。
And I said, yes Leo, forget it, I'm here, obviously when you need me, I'm here.
Y dije, sí Leo, olvídate, yo estoy acá, obviamente cuando vos me necesites, estoy.
一切都是如此，我需要你，我想走。
And that's how it was with everything, I'm going to need you, I want to go.
Y así fue con todo, a vos te voy a necesitar, te quiero ir.
就像一一给了他信心或者
It's like one by one it gave him the confidence or
es como que de a uno le iba dando la confianza o
澄清他是否不会参加比赛，因为对于教练来说他打得不太好，这很复杂
clarifying if he was not going to play because with those he did not play so well for a coach it is complicated
aclarando si no iba a jugar porque con los que no jugaba tan bien para un técnico es complicado
但是，从这个意义上说，我的建议是
But well, in that sense I said, that is, my advice was
Pero bueno, yo en ese sentido dije, o sea mi consejo era
狮子座，说出你的感受。
Leo, say what you feel.
Leo, decir lo que sientas.
如果你有这样的感觉，那就继续吧。
If you feel that way, go ahead.
Si sentís eso, dale para adelante.
我记得我们有过一次谈话，我不记得是所有人还是我，但我想...
I remember we had a talk, I don't remember if it was with everyone or if it was me, but I think there was...
Me acuerdo que una charla tuvimos, no recuerdo si eran con todos o estaba yo, pero creo que había...
我们有不少人，不是整个团队，但是......
There were quite a few of us, not the entire team, but...
Éramos bastante, no todo el equipo, pero...
我想就在那时我们告诉他如何做你想做的事。
and I think that was when we told him how to do what you feel.
y creo que ahí fue que le dijimos en todo como hacer lo que vos sientas.
如果您需要与我们交谈或者他需要
and if you need to talk to us or he needs
y si necesitas hablar con nosotros o él necesita
改变是因为你想要改变，或者你需要以同样的方式继续下去，无论如何。
change because you feel like it or you need to continue in the same way, whatever.
cambiar porque tiene ganas o necesita seguir de la misma manera, lo que sea.
这是他的问题
It's his issue and
es es un tema de él y
好吧，他正在一点一点地建设，一点一点地引进球员，观看并......
And well, and little by little he was building, little by little bringing players, watching and...
Y bueno, y él fue de a poco construyendo, de a poco trayendo jugadores, viendo y...
他总是告诉我和年长的人，Fideo
and he always told me and the older ones, Fideo
y él nos decía siempre a mí y a los más grandes, a Fideo
和孩子们一起去，明白吗？
Go with the kids, see?
Vaya con los pibes, ¿viste?
戴尔.
Dale.
他说，是的，对我们宽松。
And he said, yes, easy on us.
Y decía, sí, tranquilo con nosotros.
他想要……
He wanted...
Él quería...
让我们组建一个坚实的团队。
Let's put together a solid group.
que armemos un grupo solido.
场外。
off the court.
fuera de la cancha.
好吧，我告诉他，让我知道，我是这方面的专家。
And well, I told him, let me know, I'm an expert in that.
Y bueno, yo le dije, déjame que yo en eso soy experto.
你也就像所有大男孩的粘合剂。
And you were also like a kind of glue for all the big boys.
Y además fuiste como una especie de pegamento para todos los grandes chicos.
警察马上就来了，第一场比赛，他第一次到达，好吧，他们是从警察那里来的。
From police right away, the first games, the first time he arrived, well, they arrived from police.
De poli enseguida, los primeros partidos, la primera vez que llegó, bueno, llegaron de poli.
汽车、墙壁和一切。
the car and walls and everything.
el autaro y paredes y todo.
和其他人一样，他们更害羞
They were more shy, like everyone else
eran más tímidos, como todos llegas
但墙壁来了，他给了我第一脚，你看，在训练中，我告诉他，啊，看。
But walls came, he gave me the first kick, you saw, in training and I told him, ah, look.
Pero paredes llegó, primera patada me da, viste, en el entrenamiento y yo le dije, ah, mirá.
辣这个，好，准备第二次、第三次
spicy this one, good, ready second, third time
picante este, bueno, listo segunda, tercera vez
他又踢了，我再也受不了了，我告诉他下次听我说
he kicked again and I couldn't take it anymore and I told him listen to me next time
patada otra vez y ya no aguanté más y le dije escúchame la próxima
忍耐一下，嗯。
Bear with me, eh.
Aguántatela, eh.
他告诉我，呃，不，但是抱歉，我不知道是什么。
He told me, eh, no, but sorry, I don't know what.
Me dijo, eh, no, pero perdona, no sé qué.
列表
List
Listo.
因此我们获得了信心。
And so we gained confidence.
Y así nos fuimos agarrando confianza.
只是雀斑吗？
Just freckles?
¿Le pegaste?
我不记得了，但是是的，我想是的。
I don't remember, but yes, I think so.
No me acuerdo, pero sí, creo que sí.
但天气真的很热但是你看
but it's really hot but well you see
pero está re caliente pero bueno viste
他们也是抱着上场比赛的希望而来的。
They also came with the hope of playing.
Ellos venían también con la ilusión de jugar.
但我们对床来了感到非常惊讶
but well we were quite surprised that the bed was coming
pero bueno nos sorprendía bastante que la cama esta que estaba viniendo
它伴随着一切而来。
It came with everything.
Venía con todo.
我认为有必要...
I think it was necessary that...
Creo que era necesario que...
没错，就是这么来的。
Exactly, it came like that.
Exacto, viniera así.
好吧，利奥告诉我...
And well, and Leo told me...
Y bueno, y Leo me dijo...
不，但这很好。
No, but this is good.
No, pero esto es bueno.
我当时想，是的，是的，不，这很好。
And I was like, yes, yes, no, it's good.
Y yo decía, sí, sí, no, es bueno.
我读什么？
What do I read?
¿Qué leo?
步？
Step?
¿Escalón?
不，利奥，利奥，梅西。
No, Leo, Leo, Messi.
No, leo, leo, Messi.
梅西。
Messi.
我说，伙计，他们这样来真是太好了。
I say, chep, this is good that they come like this and such.
Digo, chep, esto es bueno que vengan así y tal.
我说，是的。
And I say, yes.
Y le digo, sí.
好吧，我们就开始抓一点
and well and there we start well grab a little
y bueno y ahí empezamos bueno agarrar un poco
我们之间的信任是因为
of trust between us because
de confianza entre nosotros porque
在我们坐在不同的桌子之前。
Before we sat at separate tables.
Antes nosotros nos sentábamos en mesas separadas.
五人一组，六人一组，埃斯卡隆一起摆满了整张桌子。
in fives, in sixes, and Escalón made an entire table together.
de a cinco, de a seis, y Escalón hizo toda una mesa junta.
显然这是一张长桌，但是，我不知道，例如，我知道什么？
Obviously it was a long table, but well, I don't know, for example, what do I know?
Obviamente igual era una mesa larga, pero bueno, no sé, por ejemplo, ¿qué se yo?
劳塔罗就在我们前面，但是嘿，你们可以聊天。
Lautaro was in front of us, but hey, you could chat.
Lautaro estaba enfrente de nosotros, pero bueno, podías charlar.
在之前的情况下，桌子有 5 或 6 个
In the case before the tables were 5 or 6
en caso antes las mesas eran de 5 o 6
或者七个人和我们七个人聊天，其他六七个人在其他地方，然后......
or seven and the seven of us chatted and the other six or seven somewhere else, then...
o siete y charlábamos los siete y los otros seis o siete en otro lado, entonces...
但是，嘿，斯卡罗尼非常清楚这一点并且有经验。
But hey, Scaloni was very aware of that and had experience.
Pero bueno, eso Scaloni lo tenía muy presente y tenía experiencia.
的选择，也许那不是
of the selection, that perhaps that was not
de la selección, de que quizás eso no era
它没有加起来
it didn't add up
no sumaba
在那里，我们获得了信心，也得到了那些在前线的最前线的人的信任。
and there we gained confidence, also with those at the front who were the most
y ahí fuimos agarrando confianza, aparte también con los del frente que eran los más
最害羞的是，因为他们坐得离我们较远。
The shyest thing, because they sat further away from us.
Lo más tímido, porque se sentaban más lejos de nosotros.
他们就在我们面前，但那是……
We had them in front of us, but it was...
Los teníamos enfrente, pero estaba...
比如那边是迪布，那边是弓箭手。
For example, on the other side was Dibu, there were the archers.
Por ejemplo, del otro lado estaba Dibu, estaban los arqueros.
有佩塞拉，有帕拉西奥，还有德劳、科雷亚、劳塔罗的所有球员。
There was Pesela, there was Palacio, there were all the guys from Drau, Correa, Lautaro on this side.
Estaba Pesela, estaba Palacio, estaban todos los chicos del Drau, Correa, Lautaro de este lado.
但是，当然，那么你已经从前面拉他了，笑话，你明白吗？
But, of course, then you're already pulling at him from the front, joke, you see?
Pero, claro, entonces vos ya del frente le vas tirando, broma, ¿viste?
训练中的守门员等等，但我说我也说当他也开始获得信心时
to the goalkeepers in training fucking and so on but I say I also say when he also started to gain confidence
a los arqueros en un entrenamiento jodiendo y así pero digo también digo cuando empezó también a agarrar confianza
就这样，我们不再阻止了，但它们都很有趣，氛围很好，然后你意识到它们是
That's it, we didn't stop it anymore, but they were all fun, good vibes, then you realize that they were
ya está, no lo paramos más, pero eran todos divertidos, buena onda, entonces te das cuenta que eran
都是非常好的人，所以...
all very good people, so that...
todos muy buena gente, entonces eso...
让每个人都参与进来也容易得多，因为这并不容易，我们有 25 个人......
It was also much easier to be able to involve everyone because it is not easy, there were 25 of us...
era mucho más fácil también poder involucrar a todos porque no es fácil, éramos 25 que...
你看，我们都说让我们相处得很好，而在美洲杯上，现实是这样的
Let's all say let's get along well, you see, and in the Copa América the reality is that
que todos digamos nos llevemos bien viste y en la copa américa la realidad es que
我们并不能很好地处理所有事情。
We don't handle everything well.
Todo no lo llevamos bien.
并不是那个……因为……
It's not that... because...
No es que... porque...
在所有比赛中总会有一些人因为他们不参加比赛
In all competitions you always have some who because they don't play
en todas las competiciones siempre tenés algunos que porque no juegan
他们有一张不好的脸，你看，然后他们就开始向你传递不好的能量。
They have a bad face, you see, then they start to transmit bad energy to you.
están con mala cara, viste, entonces te empiezan a transmitir mala energía.
但这就像我们在 2014 年世界杯上发生的事情一样
but in this one it's like what also happened to us in the 2014 World Cup
pero en esta es como que nos pasó también en el mundial 2014
与2021年类似。
similar to 2021.
parecido al 2021.
几乎是一样的。
It was almost identical.
Fue casi idéntico.
非常好的能量，我们进入了决赛
very good energy, we reached the final
muy buena energía, llegamos a la final
与我们的团队一起，更不用说
with the team we had, let's not say
con el equipo que teníamos que tampoco digamos
可以说，康萨贝拉是最受欢迎的。
Conzabela was, let's say, favorites.
Conzabela era, digamos, favoritos.
但最终阿根廷总是试图赢得一些东西。
but in the end Argentina always ends up trying to always win something.
pero Argentina al final siempre termina tratando de que siempre gane algo.
但在那届世界杯上，我们的目标是进入四分之一决赛。
But in that World Cup, our goal was to reach the quarterfinals.
pero nosotros en ese mundial, nuestro objetivo era llegar a cuartos
亚历山大著名的卢比孔河神父十字架。
The famous Father Cross of the Rubicon of Alexander.
El famoso Padre Cruz del Rubicón de Alejandro.
当然，我们来自世界杯，但没有进入四分之一决赛。
Of course, we came from World Cups that we didn't advance to the quarterfinals.
Claro, veníamos de mundiales que no pasábamos cuartos.
这就是我们的目标，通过然后进入半决赛。
And that was our objective, to pass and then in semi we see.
Y ese era nuestro objetivo, pasar y después en semi vemos.
当我们面对兰达时，我们说，好吧，你可以击败他，这并不容易。
When we faced Landa, we said, well, you can beat him, it's not easy.
Cuando nos enfrentamos a Landa, ahí dijimos, bueno, se le puede ganar, no es fácil.
然后，如果我们通过了，我们就会看到决赛中会发生什么。
And then, if we pass, we see what happens in the final.
Y después, si pasamos, vemos qué pasa en la final.
我们都看到会发生什么，但是......
We all see what happens, but...
Todos vemos qué pasa, pero...
始终怀着阿根廷人的心，让我们走上前线。
always with the Argentine heart of let's go to the front.
siempre con el corazón argentino de vamos al frente.
但是，本届美洲杯也是一样，一切都非常团结，非常......
But well, and this Copa América was the same, it was all very united, very...
Pero bueno, y esta Copa América era igual, era todo muy unido, muy...
如果我们要玩恶作剧，我们就一起玩；如果我们要打台球，我们就一起玩。
If we were going to play trick, we all played together, if we were going to play pool, we all played together.
si íbamos a jugar al truco, jugábamos todos juntos, si íbamos a jugar al pool, todos juntos.
不，事实是，对我来说，2014 年美洲杯给我留下了很多回忆。
No, the truth is that for me that Copa América was a lot of memories from 2014.
No, la verdad que esa Copa América para mí me vino yendo mucho recuerdo del 2014.
我想让我们谈谈亚历杭德罗、萨贝拉，他对团队的意义以及他对你们的意义。
I want us to talk a little about Alejandro, Sabela, what he meant to the group and what he meant to you too.
Quiero que hablemos un poquito de Alejandro, Sabela, qué significó para el grupo y qué significó para vos también.
嘿他
hey he
eh el
他把你纳入了决赛，我什至在聊天中和他谈到过，对阵尼日利亚时你会左右为难。
He includes you in the final, I even talked about it with him in a chat, you will be torn against Nigeria.
te incluye en la final, incluso lo hablé con él en una charla, vos te desgarrás contra Nigeria.
是的，第三场比赛。
Yes, the third game.
Sí, el tercer partido.
然后球队发生了变化，阵型变成了4-4-2。
And there the team changes, it goes 4-4-2.
Y ahí el equipo cambia, va un 4-4-2.
八分之一通过瑞士的屏幕
pass the screen of switzerland in eighths
pasa la pantalla de suiza en octavos
比利时队在四分之一决赛中与荷兰队比赛，事实上，你踢了系列赛中的一个点球。
Belgium in the quarterfinals, you play with Holland, in fact you kick one of the penalties in the series.
Bélgica en cuartos, vos jugás con Holanda, de hecho pateás uno de los penales en la serie.
你在下半场的决赛中替补波乔，他
and you enter for Pocho in the final in the second half and he
y vos entras por Pocho en la final en el segundo tiempo y él
他向我解释说，这一变化与中场老大是斯万·斯蒂格有关。
He explained to me that this change had to do with the fact that the boss of the midfield was Svan Stiger.
me explicó que ese cambio tenía que ver con que el capo de la mitad de la cancha era Svan Stiger
上半场他单打独斗，阿根廷打出4-4-2，他获得任意球。
In the first half he played alone, Argentina played 4-4-2 and he received a free kick.
En el primer tiempo jugó solo, Argentina jugaba 4-4-2 y el recibía libre.
Leo、Pippa 和你已经处于三角关系中，Fantaia 不再那么自由自在
and that with Leo, Pippa and you already in that triangle, Fantaia no longer played so freely
y que con Leo, Pippa y vos ya en ese triángulo, ya Fantaia no jugó tan libre
德国队的比赛通过了LAM，关于你为什么进来和为什么离开的解释非常清楚。
The Germany game went through LAM and the explanation of why you came in and why you left was very clear.
El juego de Alemania pasó por LAM y fue muy clara la explicación de por qué entraste y por qué salió.
他们更多地到外面去，因为这让我感觉就像
They went more outside because it makes me feel exactly like
iban más por fuera porque a mí me pone exactamente era
放...这将是一个...
put... it will be a...
ponerle... será un...
第433章
433 but I'm pulling on the left side a little more inside
433 pero yo por ahí tirándome del lado izquierdo un poquito más por dentro
稍微覆盖中间，如果不是有时的话......
to cover the middle a little and if not sometimes...
para tapar un poco el medio y si no a veces...
然后我们做了四三一二
we made four three one two then
hacíamos cuatro tres uno dos entonces
他把我放在Leo和Pipa后面然后...
He put me behind Leo and Pipa and...
a mí me ponía por detrás de Leo y Pipa y que...
中间就开始麻烦了。
It starts to bother in the middle.
empieza a molestar en el medio.
但他下了很多赌注，想法是
but he was betting a lot, the idea was
pero él apostaba mucho, la idea era
有时也反对那好事，赶紧出去
come out quickly also against that good sometimes
salir rápido también de contra que bueno en algunas ocasiones
非常接近那个
was very close to that by very little
estuvo muy cerca de que por muy poco de
我记得也许是通行证，我们已经见面了，因为德国......
I remember maybe a pass, we were already meeting, because Germany...
Me acuerdo de un pase quizás, ya quedábamos, porque Alemania...
他打得非常靠前，逼抢也非常高。
He played very forward and pressed very high.
jugaba muy adelantado y presionaba muy alto.
当我们拿回球时我们知道
When we recovered the ball we knew that
al recuperar la pelota sabíamos que
3或4次传球可以让我们与守门员一对一。
3 or 4 passes could bring us one-on-one with the goalkeeper.
3 o 4 pases nos podían llevar a mano a mano con el arquero.
我们没有那样的运气或精确度。
and we didn't have that luck or precision.
y no tuvimos esa suerte o la precisión.
找到我们当时还拥有的最后一张通行证
to find the last pass that we still had at that time we had
de encontrar el último pase que aún así tuvimos en ese tiempo tuvimos
三清，我们都有三清，皇宫里的也有
three clear ones, we all had three clear ones, the one in the palace too
tres claras, todos tres claras tuvimos, la de palacio también
我不记得还有一个，但我们确实有过
and I don't remember another one but but we did have and
y no me acuerdo otra pero pero si tuvimos y
对我来说，什么也没有，比方说，阿贝拉……
And nothing, for me, let's say, Abela...
Y nada, para mí, digamos, Abela...
在哥伦比亚，在巴兰基亚的淘汰赛中
in Colombia, in the eliminatory in Barranquilla
en Colombia, en la eliminatoria en Barranquilla
他一直在踢4-4-2阵型，在那里他放了...
He had been playing 4-4-2, there he put a...
él venía jugando 4-4-2, por ahí metía un...
4-5-1 因为有时这会让 Leo 得到......
a 4-5-1 because sometimes it made Leo get...
un 4-5-1 porque a veces hacía que Leo se ponga...
作为一名右手车手，但他在小道出口处进行掩护，因此他将车手留在了很高的位置。
As a right-hand driver but covering at the exit of the trail, he left the driver very high up.
como volante por derecha pero tapando a la salida del trail, lo dejaba al pipas muy arriba.
也许没有太多人到达，假设管道非常孤独
and perhaps there was not much arrival, let's say the pipe was very alone
y quizás no había mucha llegada, digamos el pipa estaba muy solo
在巴兰基亚，上半场结束后，我变得……
And in Barranquilla there, when the first half ended, I became...
Y en Barranquilla ahí, cuando termina el primer tiempo, me hice...
做好准备，塞尔吉奥，你要上场了，我们现在要以 4-3-3 阵型开始。
Get ready, Sergio, you're going to come in and we're going to start now in a 4-3-3.
Preparate, Sergio, vas a entrar y vamos a partir ahora a un 4-3-3.
热爸爸和进入之间很好，我们赢了
well between heat dad and enter and we win
bueno entre calor papá y entre y ganamos
这给了他打4-3-3阵型的信心，从那时起这种情况就没有改变。
And that gave him the confidence to play 4-3-3 and from then on it didn't change.
y eso le dio la confianza a él mía y de jugar 4-3-3 y a partir de ahí no cambió.
更重要的是，他在卡里罗海滩上演讲时告诉了我这件事。
What's more, he told me about it on the beach in Cariló, when he had a talk.
Es más, me lo contó en la playa en Cariló, que tuvo una charla.
和你在一起，安赫尔、利奥和皮帕。
with you, Ángel, Leo and Pippa.
con vos, Ángel, Leo y Pippa.
球队打的是加戈 8 场比赛，比赛 5 场，玛丽亚在左边，你在上面
The team played Gago of 8, Match of 5, María on the left and you on top
El equipo jugaba Gago de 8, Match de 5, de María en la izquierda y arriba ustedes
他们有男孩的小屋。
and that they had the boys' chalet.
y que tuvieron la chalecín de los muchachos.
你想这样玩吗？
Do you want to play like this?
¿Ustedes quieren jugar así?
你喜欢它？
Do you like it?
¿Les gusta?
帮助。
Help.
Ayuden.
不要让哈维尔独自一人，不要让哈维尔独自一人，萨巴莱塔和马可在两侧。
Don't leave Javier alone, don't leave Javier alone with Zabaleta and Marco on the sides.
No lo dejen solo a Javier, no lo dejen solo a Javier con Zabaleta y Marco en los laterales.
你有这样的谈话吗？
Did you have that talk?
¿Tuvieron esa charla?
不，是的，是的。
No, yes, yes.
No, sí, sí.
萨贝洛总是告诉我们...
Sabelo always told us...
Siempre Sabelo nos decía...
当我们没有球的时候，我们会尝试...
When we don't have the ball we try to...
Cuando no tenemos la pelota tratemos de...
在 4-4-2 阵型中我担任左中场
to position ourselves there in a 4-4-2 that I play as a left midfielder
de posicionarnos por ahí un 4-4-2 que yo me tire como volante por izquierda
但一开始这对我来说很困难，因为我
but at first it was difficult for me because I
pero a mí al principio me costaba porque yo
有时候我会想起来，我会想起来……
Sometimes I remembered, I remember that...
A veces me acordaba, me acuerdo que...
我们丢了球，我回来步行
We lost the ball and I came back to walk
perdíamos la pelota y yo volvía para ir caminando
但这是典型的前锋，你看，你走回去，我记得，哦，该死，我必须回去。
but it's typical striker, you see, you walk back and I remembered, oh, shit, I had to go back.
pero es típica delantero, viste, volvés caminando y yo me acordé, uy, mierda, que tenía que volver.
幸运的是，马什...
Luckily, Masche...
Por suerte igual, Masche...
有相当多的...
There was quite a bit of it...
Ahí bastante era el que...
连衣裙，我点了一点，以防我去任何地方，那边也有面条
Dress, I ordered a little in case I go anywhere and noodles on that side too
Viste, ordenaba un poco en caso de que yo me vaya para cualquier lado y fideo también de ese lado
这对我来说非常好，因为我知道 Fideo 经常发起进攻。
It suited me very well because I know that Fideo went on the attack quite a bit.
A mí me venía muy bien porque yo sé que Fideo pasaba bastante al ataque.
如果我稍微关闭一点
if I closed a little as a hitch
si me cerraba un poquito como enganche
他让 Leo 始终拥有 Fideo 的通行证，因为 Fideo 过去了。
He let Leo always have the pass for Fideo, because Fideo passed.
Le dejaba a Leo que siempre tenga el pase para Fideo, porque Fideo pasaba.
但菲迪奥路过又回来了。
But Fideo passed by and came back.
Pero Fideo pasaba y volvía.
这就是 Fideo 所拥有的。
That's what Fideo had.
Eso es lo que tenía Fideo.
一方面，这让我平静了一些，但有时……
On the one hand it left me a little calmer, but sometimes...
Por un lado me dejaba un poco más tranquilo, pero a veces...
当 Fideo 发生如此多的事情时，必须有人来报道……
When Fideo was happening so much, someone had to cover that...
Cuando Fideo pasaba tanto, alguien tenía que cubrir ese...
这对我来说是相当困难的，后来我们又恢复了。
And that was quite difficult for me, and later we recovered it.
Y a mí me costaba bastante eso, que después lo fuimos recuperando.
我适应了这个计划。
I adapted to that scheme.
me fui adaptando a ese esquema.
世界杯即将到来，我们将以同样的方式、同样的战术进行比赛。
The World Cup is coming and we play in the same way, with the same tactics that we had.
Viene el Mundial y jugamos de la misma manera, con la misma táctica que teníamos.
第一场以五人排队开始并在半场进行双换人的比赛。
The first game that starts with a line of five and a double substitution at halftime.
El primer partido que arranca con línea de cinco y doble cambio en el entretiempo.
是的，我们就是这样开始的，然后是第二场，第三场……
Yes, we started like this, then the second game and the third...
Sí, arrancamos así, después el segundo partido y el tercero...
我感觉下面的坐骨有轻微的挤压。
I feel a tiny little pinch in my ischium below.
Siento una pequeña pincha chiquitito en el isquio abajo.
但很小但是我首先想到的是
but very small but well the first thing I thought was
pero muy chiquitito pero bueno yo lo primero que pensé es
我停下来是因为如果我继续下去的话我会更加崩溃，而且如果世界杯没有直接结束的话
I stop because if I continue I'm going to break myself more and if the World Cup isn't over directly
paro porque si sigo me voy a romper más y si ya directamente no se acabó el mundial
然后我停下来告诉他，我有一滴很小的眼泪......
Then I stopped and told him, I had a very small tear that...
Entonces paré y le dije, tenía un desgarrito muy chico que...
虽然需要 15 或 20 天，但好吧，我们会尽力做到这一点，直到我可以在季度或半季度回来。
It's 15 or 20 days but well, we're going to try to get it in until I can come back in quarter or semi.
son 15 o 20 días pero bueno lo vamos a tratar de meter hasta que pueda volver en cuarto o en semi
好吧，这就是我们把他放在的位置，但事实是那届世界杯
And well, that's where we put him in, but the truth is that that World Cup
y bueno y ahí fue que le metimos pero yo la verdad que ese mundial
乔山 CD
Joshan on CD
Joshan en el CD
我一年四季都在小溪里遇到问题。
I had a problem in the creek all year round.
Venía de una molestia en la arroyilla todo el año.
放在 CT 顶部
put on top in the CT
pon encima en el CT
你不能停下来，明白吗？
You can't stop, see?
No puedes parar, ¿viste?
我的意思是，每三天就有一次，如果你停下来一周，你就会错过三场比赛，明白吗？
I mean, it's every three days and if you stop for a week you'll miss three games, see?
O sea, es cada tres días y si paras una semana te perdés tres partidos, ¿viste?
我的意思是，那是...
I mean, it was...
O sea, era...
非常复杂，我去年夏天就有过
very complicated and I had last summer
muy complicado y yo tuve en el verano pasado
我的意思是，上赛季他在季前赛中受伤了。
I mean, last season he had an injury in the preseason.
O sea, la temporada pasada tuvo una lesión en la pretemporada.
一个......在膝盖上，我不知道他们叫它什么，
one... on the knee, I don't know what they call it,
una... en la rodilla, no sé cómo le dicen,
我的膝盖后面有水肿
I had edema on the back of my knee
un edema tenía en la parte de atrás de la rodilla
季前赛我没有这么做，我们直接去了香港，去了中国，然后去了德国，我们到处都去了。
I didn't do it preseason, we went directly to Hong Kong, to China, then we went to Germany, we went everywhere.
No lo hice pretemporada, directamente fuimos a Hong Kong, a China, después fuimos a Alemania, fuimos a todos lados.
我无法训练。
and I couldn't train.
y yo no podía entrenar.
我的意思是，我正在训练，我的方向盘让我很困扰。
I mean, I was training and my wheel was bothering me.
O sea, entrenaba y se me molestaba la rueda.
所以我说不，在我恢复之前我不会训练。
So I said no, I don't train until I'm good.
Entonces dije no, no entreno hasta que esté bien.
联赛开始前三天，我们与纽卡斯尔进行了第一场比赛
3 days before the league started we played the first game with Newcastle
3 días antes que ya empezara la liga jugamos el primer partido con Newcastle
然后曼努埃尔·佩勒林 (Manuel Pelerín) 过来告诉我，你好吗？
And then Manuel Pelerín comes and tells me, how are you?
Y entonces viene Manuel Pelerín y me dice, ¿cómo estás?
我不知道，我一天都没训练，但他告诉我很好
I don't know, I didn't train even a day but he told me well
no sé, no entrené ni un día pero me dijo bueno
如果你能提前一天训练，我就让你参加。
If you can train a day before, I'll put you in.
Si puedes entrenar un día antes, yo te pongo.
嗯，你也看到了同样的情况。
Well, you saw the same.
Bueno, viste el igual.
如果有一天我训练，我周五训练，周六打球，周五训练……
If I trained one day, I trained on Friday, I played on Saturday, I trained on Friday...
Si entrené un día, entrené el viernes, jugaba el sábado, entrené el viernes...
他留在了球队并让我成为首发。
He stayed with the team and made me a starter.
Quedó con el equipo y me puso titular.
晚上在俱乐部，膝盖按摩，只要我能忍受。
All night at the club, knee massage, as long as I can stand it.
toda la noche en el club, masaje en la rodilla, hasta donde aguante.
好吧，我们开始了，我进了一个球，等等。
And well, we started, I scored a goal and well, and so on.
Y bueno, arrancamos, hice un gol y bueno, y así.
打完比赛，冰敷，按摩，我每天都来，一年到头都是这样，我是说我不能……
finish the game, ice, massage, I came every day and like that all year round, I mean I couldn't...
terminar el partido, hielo, masaje, todos los días venía y así todo el año, o sea no podía...
这真是令人难以置信，而且很好，所以我无法停止
It was incredible and good and so I couldn't stop
era increíble y bueno y así no podía parar
好吧，现在也进入了最后一场比赛。
And well, now also reaching the last games.
Y bueno, ya también llegando a los últimos partidos.
他说好吧，我要停下来了，因为世界杯就要开始了。
He said well, I'm going to stop because the World Cup is on.
decía bueno voy a parar porque está el mundial
但这是不可能的，所以我们花了大约20天的时间
but it was impossible, so after we had about 20 days
pero era imposible, entonces después tuvimos unos 20 días
我在那里度过了那20天
that I spent those 20 days there
que yo esos 20 días por ahí
也许我应该继续日常工作，因为
Maybe I should have continued with the routine because
Quizás tendría que haber seguido por ahí con la rutina porque
在那20天里，它会在那一刻杀死你
when for those 20 days it kills you later well at that moment
cuando para esos 20 días te mata después bueno ya en ese momento
你没有意识到，但随着时间的推移，你会意识到停了这么多天
You don't realize it but over time you realize that stopping for so many days
uno no se da cuenta pero después con el tiempo uno se da cuenta que que parar tantos días
尤其是当你每三四天来玩一次时。
especially when you come playing every three or four days.
más cuando venís jugando cada tres o cuatro días.
如果你不加快步伐，你的身体就会开始受到损害。
You don't pick up the pace and your body starts to take its toll.
no agarras el ritmo y el cuerpo te empieza a pasar factura.
在那里的 20 天里，我必须遵循治疗程序、训练、膝盖、力量等等。
And those 20 days there I had to have followed the treatment routine, training, knee, strength, whatever.
Y esos 20 días por ahí yo tenía que haber seguido la rutina de tratamiento, de entrenamiento, de rodilla, fuerza, lo que sea.
而我在那边，为了...
And I over there, for...
Y yo por ahí, por...
他们还为花旗工作，即所有的科学人。
They also for the Citi jobs, that is, all the science people.
también ellos para los oficios del Citi, o sea, toda la gente ciencia.
花几天时间，也许这会让你平静下来，比如说放松你的膝盖。
Take a few days, maybe that makes you calm, let's say relax your knee.
tomate unos días que capaz que eso hace que esté tranquilo, digamos que se relaje la rodilla.
他花了一整天的时间去尝试，然后你尝试得很好，我也尝试过类似的事情，但是
that he spends all day trying and then you try well and I tried something like that but
que está todo el día metiéndole y después vas probando bueno y probé tal pero
当我们回来时，我们在世界杯之前在拉普拉塔进行了一场友谊赛。
When we returned, we played a friendly match in La Plata, before the World Cup.
Cuando volvimos, jugamos un partido amistoso en La Plata, ante el Mundial.
我不记得是哪个国家了，但我们比赛了，我在下半场替补出场。
I don't remember which country, but we played and I came on in the second half.
No me acuerdo contra qué país, pero jugamos y yo entré en el segundo tiempo.
它仍然持续了一点，但然后好吧......
and it still continued a little, but then well...
y todavía seguía un poquito, pero después bueno...
我试着把他放进去，然后...
I tried to put him in and well...
Traté de meterle y bueno...
事实是……
The truth is that...
La verdad que...
这并不容易，因为你看，如果你告诉他，你不知道该怎么办
It's not easy because you see, you don't know what to do if you tell him
que no es fácil porque uno, viste, no sabes qué hacer si decirle
我是或不是，或者我帮忙。
I am or I am not, or I help.
estoy o no estoy, o ayudo.
这非常复杂，我知道萨贝拉非常信任我，但萨贝拉也信任我。
It was very complicated and I knew that Sabela had a lot of trust in me, but Sabela trusted me.
era muy complicado y yo sabía que Sabela tenía mucha confianza en mí, pero Sabela confiaba.
相当
quite
bastante
在我身上，显然我尝试过......事实上，你把自己放入了半决赛和决赛中。
in me and well obviously I tried... In fact you put yourself in the semi and the final.
en mí y bueno obviamente traté... De hecho te pones en la semi y en la final.
没错，当我把半挂放在第一件事上时，我......
Exactly, and when I put the semi on the first thing I...
Exacto, y yo cuando pongo la semi lo primero que...
我被撕裂了，最重要的是它还在延伸。
I was torn and on top of that it was in extension.
Yo estaba desgarrado y encima era en el alargue.
我说，不，我要打破一切。
I said, no, I'm breaking everything.
Yo dije, no, me rompo todo.
当然，因为我没有训练，所以我没有踢过足球什么的。
Of course, because I didn't train, I hadn't played football or anything.
Claro, porque yo no entrené, no había hecho ni fútbol ni nada.
当塞尔吉奥告诉我，来吧，他要进来时，我说，好吧。
And when Sergio told me, come on, he's going to come in, I said, well.
Y cuando me dice Sergio, dale que va a entrar, dije, bueno.
我说，好吧，我不知道，至少每个人都罚丢了点球。
And I said, well, I don't know, at least everyone missed the penalty.
Y yo dije, bueno, no sé, por lo menos todo patía el penal.
忍受一切，如果不能，我就停下来，你明白吗？
Put up with anything, if not, I'll stop, you see?
Aguantar lo que sea, si no alguna me paré, ¿viste?
当你想到的时候。
When you thought.
Cuando pensaste.
我还剩下一些，但我带着那种恐惧进入了那一个
I have some left but I went in with that one with that fear of
alguna me queda pero entré con esa con ese miedo de
我不知道是否要咬一口，因为我什至都没有热身，什么都没有。
I don't know whether to take a bite, because I hadn't even warmed up, nothing, nothing.
No sé si hacer un pique, porque no había entrado ni bien en calor, nada, nada.
但我说，好吧，就这样吧。
But I said, well, that's it.
Pero dije, bueno, ya está.
有一次我想，就是这样，如果我必须打破，我就会打破，但是......
At one point I thought, that's it, if I have to break, I'll break, but...
En un momento pensé, ya está, si me tengo que romper, me rompo, pero...
但我们打平了，所以我说，好吧，如果我们进入点球大战并进入决赛，你看，就像一切都是可见的......
But we were tying, so I said, well, if we go to penalties and go to the final, you see, it's like everything was visible...
Pero estábamos empatando, entonces decía, bueno, si vamos a penales y pasamos hasta la final, viste, es como que todo se veía...
嗯，等等等等，我玩了一段时间，我玩了……
and well, and so on and so forth, I played for a while, I played the...
y bueno, y así y sí, jugué un rato, jugué los...
我不知道是25分钟还是27分钟，我不知道。
I don't know if it was 25 or 27 minutes, I don't know.
No sé si habrá sido 25 o 27 minutos, no sé.
好吧，我刚刚在扩展中进入了那里。
Well, I just entered there in the extension.
pues entré ahí nomás en el alargue.
我不知道我是直接进来的还是延期开始后就进来的。
I don't know if I came in straight away or if I came in as soon as the extension started.
No sé si entré de entrada o si entré apenas empezó el alargue.
我认为延期才刚刚开始。
I think the extension has just started.
Creo que apenas empezó el alargue.
最后，事实是我感觉很好。
In the end, the truth is that I felt pretty good.
en la final la verdad que bastante bien me sentí
我以为我会成为什么
what I thought I was going to be
de que pensé que iba a estar
因为对阵布兰达他是第一个。
Because against Blanda he was the first.
Porque contra Blanda era el primero.
他几乎什么也没做。
He did practically nothing.
No hizo nada prácticamente.
他只踢了点球，但这是值得的。
He only kicked the penalty, but it was worth it.
Solo pateó el penal, pero valió.
这个顺序非常好。
That sequence is very good.
Esa secuencia es buenísima.
因为我已经知道我要拍的地方，也就是我没有拍的地方。
because I already knew where I was going to shoot, which was where I didn't shoot.
porque yo ya sabía dónde iba a tirar, que era donde no tiré.
你要打开脚并将内边缘粘到左侧。
you were going to open the foot and glue the inside edge to the left side.
ibas a abrir el pie y pegarle el borde interno al lado izquierdo.
我的意思是，发生了什么事？
I mean, what's going on?
O sea, ¿qué pasa?
那个弓箭手
that the archer
Que el arquero
是的，但替补门将是纽卡斯尔的。
Yes, but the substitute goalkeeper was Newcastle's.
Sí, pero el arquero que suplente era el de Newcastle.
他已进入哥斯达黎加工作。
who had entered to work with Costa Rica.
que había entrado para trabajar con Costa Rica.
但他，我看见他在聊天
But he, I saw him chatting
Pero él, yo lo vi charlando
所以我说，哎呀，他已经告诉你我在哪里拍摄了。
So I say, oops, he's already telling you where I shoot.
Entonces yo digo, uy, ya le está diciendo dónde yo tiro.
我是说，除了那个该死的妈妈……
I mean, the fucking mother, aside...
Digo, la puta madre, aparte...
可以说，几乎所有内容都在奖项中。
Almost everything, let's say, in the awards.
Casi todo, digamos, en la premia.
我不知道，我在附近射门，结果我被罚了 30 个点球。
I was shooting, I don't know, around the place and I had 30 penalties.
Yo iba tirando, no sé, por el sitio y yo llevaba 30 penales.
30岁、16岁、17岁他就走那条路。
and of the 30, 16, 17 he had gone that way.
y de los 30, 16, 17 había tirado para ese lado.
所以这就像我最喜欢的，我最喜欢的套装。
So it was like my favorite, my favorite suit.
Entonces era como mi favorito, mi palo favorito.
正在告诉你我在哪里拍摄
is telling you where I shoot
le está diciendo donde yo tiro
所以我说准备好了，我不会在那里射击，我会向另一边射击，因为他会认为......
So I said ready, I'm not going to shoot there, I'm going to shoot to the other side because he's going to think that...
Entonces yo dije listo, yo no voy a tirar ahí, voy a tirar al otro lado porque él va a pensar que...
一切都是有顺序的，但当处罚开始时
everything is a sequence but then when the penalties start
todo es una secuencia pero después cuando arrancan los penales
我说，不，我不会把它扔在那里。
I say, no, I'm not going to throw it there.
Yo digo, no, no la voy a tirar ahí.
我会把它扔在同一个地方，因为他会认为我会改变这一切。
I'm going to throw it in the same place because he's going to think that I'm going to change it all.
La voy a tirar en el mismo lugar porque él se va a pensar que yo la voy a cambiar toda.
你有没有看到？
Did you see?
¿Viste?
我的心在跳……处罚正在过去，轮到我的时候，我正在走路，就是这样……
And my heart was going... the penalties were passing and when it was my turn I was walking and that's it...
Y el corazón me iba... iban pasando los penales y cuando me tocó a mí yo iba caminando y ya ya...
他说他要在那里开枪，他要在那里开枪，如果他扔在那里……
He said he was going to shoot there, he was going to shoot there, if he threw there...
decía que iba a tirar ahí, iba a tirar ahí que si tiraba ahí...
他以另一种方式摔倒了，因为在我摔倒他之后，他也摔倒了，他几乎把它从我身上夺走了。
He threw himself the other way because after I threw him he threw himself, he almost took it out of me.
se tiró para el otro lado porque yo después donde tiré él se tiró, casi me la saca.
你越过它，他几乎就把它拿出来了。
You cross it and he almost takes it out.
La cruzás y él casi la saca.
是的，是往下的，正好他跳下去看看是不是爬到一半了。
Yes, it was down, it happens that he jumped down to see if he was going halfway up.
Sí, fue abajo, pasa que él se tiró para ver si iba a media altura.
没什么好事，到了那里我不知道为什么它超出了我的想象
and nothing good, getting there I don't know why it went over my head
y nada bueno, llegando ahí no sé por qué se me pasó la cabeza
不，我不会扔在那里。
No, I'm not going to throw there.
No, no voy a tirar ahí.
我的意思是，还有...
I mean, and...
O sea, y...
这些疑虑，也是我一开始没有陷入困境的原因，因为……
And those doubts, that's also why I didn't start out so cornered, because...
Y esas dudas, por eso también no partí tan esquinado, porque...
当你非常清楚你将把那个点球罚到门柱上时
when you are very clear that you are going to take that penalty to the post
cuando estás muy claro que vas a tirar ese penal hasta el palo
进展非常顺利，转弯时，当你有疑问时，踢得很好
it goes very very well it corners it kicks well when you have doubt
va muy muy bien va esquinado va pateado bien cuando tienes duda
他也不会踢，但他可以进去。
He's not going to kick as well, but he can go in.
no va a patear tan bien, pero puede entrar.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
好吧。
And well.
Y bueno.
当我踢交叉时，我首先想到的是用力交叉向下
When I cross kick the first thing I thought was cross down hard
cuando pateo cruzado lo primero que yo pensaba era cruzado abajo fuerte
没关系，我想做的并不是把它放在这样的角落，因为既然我有疑问......
It doesn't matter, what I was trying to do was not put it in such a corner because since I had doubts...
Da igual, yo lo que intentaba es no meterla tan esquinada porque como tenía duda...
一个不见了，他们用棍子打我，看到了吗？
one is missing and they hit me with the stick, see?
uno falta y me peguen el palo, ¿viste?
好吧，我以为他会走另一条路，面对这一切。
Well, I was thinking that he was going to go the other way, to all this.
Pues yo pensando que él se iba a tirar para el otro lado, a todo esto.
当我看到他那样倾斜时，他几乎把我的气都夺走了。
When I see that he leans that way, he almost takes it out of me.
Cuando veo que él se tira para ese lado, casi me la saca.
我不知道，我想我应该看看我是否有节奏，但是......
I don't know, I think I should have seen if I got a rhythm, but...
No sé, yo creo que ahí tendría que haber visto si me agarró una ritmia, pero...
但不，我的心在狂跳，但是嘿，这些都是在点球大战中发生的事情
but no, my heart was pounding, but hey, these are things that happen in penalties that
pero no no me iba el corazón a mil pero bueno son cosas que pasan los penales que
那很好，然后你就会知道你不应该怀疑，明白吗？
That's good, then you learn that you shouldn't doubt, you see?
que bueno, después uno va aprendiendo que no hay que dudar, ¿viste?
西沃斯风笛...
Si vos bagpipes...
Si vos dudás...
然后当佩普到来时，当我们要进行点球大战或当我们要罚点球时，
And then when Pep arrived, also when we were going to a penalty shootout or when we were going to take a penalty,
Y después cuando llegó Pep, también cuando íbamos a tanda de penales o cuando íbamos a bater un penal,
他告诉我们，不要犹豫。
And he told us, don't hesitate.
Y nos decía, no duden.
我说，没有必要怀疑。
And I said, there is no need to doubt.
Y yo decía, es que no hay que dudar.
他说……
And he said...
Y decía...
砍了砍了，别变。
Chop it, chop it, don't change.
Picala, picala, no cambies.
穿过它，穿过它，打开，打开。
Cross it, cross it, open, open.
Cruzala, cruzala, abierta, abierta.
我不知道，你想成为拉博纳，拉博纳，但我没有改变你的想法。
I don't know, you wanted to be a rabona, rabona, but I didn't change your idea.
No sé, querías ser rabona, rabona, pero no cambie tu idea.
当然，因为当你开始...
Because of course, when you start...
Porque claro, cuando empezás a...
让我们看看它会去哪里以及这个和那个。
Let's see where it goes and this and that.
a ver dónde va y esto y lo otro.
超。
Chao.
你百分百感觉不好。
You felt bad 100%.
Patías mal 100%.
当佩普到来时，佩普的表现非常出色。
When Pep arrives, all the nines with Pep press.
Cuando llega Pep, todos los nueves con Pep presionan.
而且你并没有因为施加压力而在职业生涯中脱颖而出。
And you have not distinguished yourself in your career for putting pressure.
Y vos no te has distinguido en tu carrera por presionar.
然而，佩普最终接受了你的条件，你最终也接受了佩普的一些东西。
However, Pep ended up accepting your conditions and you also ended up accepting some things from Pep.
Sin embargo, Pep terminó aceptando tus condiciones y vos terminaste también aceptando algunas cosas de Pep.
这段关系是如何建立的，因为今天他与你谈论你……
How was the relationship and how it was built because today he talks about you with...
cómo fue la relación y cómo se fue construyendo porque hoy él habla de vos con...
非常自豪和非常高兴。
a lot of pride and with a lot of joy.
mucho orgullo y con mucha alegría.
在与佩普共事的那些年里，你为这个地方付出了很多。
and you gave a lot to the place during the years you shared with Pep.
y le diste mucho al sitio durante los años que compartiste con Pep.
但这是一种立即发生的关系还是需要一段时间才能发生？
But was it a relationship that flowed right away or did it take a while?
Pero ¿fue una relación que fluyó de entrada o costó un poquito?
不，一开始非常好，然后，嗯，这是......
No, at first very good and then, well, it was...
No, al principio muy bien y después, bueno, fue...
我们开始有相当多的东西......
We're starting to have quite a bit there...
empezamos a tener bastante ahí...
压力下说话。
talks in pressure.
charlas en la presión.
好吧，压力问题让我发疯，所以当然，也有一段时间让我摆脱了困境。
And well, it drove me crazy with the issue of pressure, so of course, there came a time that got me out too.
Y bueno, a mí me volvía loco con el tema de la presión, entonces claro, llegaba un momento que a mí también me sacaba.
我们都开始有点紧张
and we both started to have a little tension
y empezamos a tener un poquito de tensión los dos
然后我们要玩一场比赛......
and then there is a game we play against...
y después hay un partido que jugamos contra...
斯托克城，我进了两个球，然后在会议上
Stock City, I score two goals and then in the conference
Stock City, yo hago dos goles y después en la conferencia
并不是说我像...
It's not that I shoot like a...
No es que me tiro como un...
一根坚固的棍子，但我像什么东西一样射击
a strong stick but I shoot like something to
un palo fuerte pero tiro como algo para
塞尔吉奥·阿奎罗没有做到的是什么......
What was it that Sergio Agüero didn't...
que fue que Sergio Agüero no me...
我喜欢他进球，但他有点说他需要我进球
I like him to score goals but he kind of said that he needed me to
me gusta que haga goles pero como que dijo como que necesitaba que
我为团队工作了更多。
I worked more for the team.
yo trabaje más para el equipo.
这就是紧张气氛开始的地方，有一天我去和他交谈。
And that's where the tension started a little and the other day I went and talked to him.
Y ahí empezó un poco la tensión y yo el otro día fui y hablé con él.
我告诉他为什么他说得这么好，他对我说得很好，这是一个完整的问题。
and I told him why he had said that well he had told me well and that was a whole issue.
y le dije que por qué había dicho eso bueno me lo había dicho bueno y ahí fue todo un tema
幸好他没有意识到这一点，幸好我道歉，但是
Good thing he didn't realize it and good thing I apologize but
que bueno no se dio cuenta y bueno pido disculpas pero
但刚开始有一点，然后就没什么了
but there it started a little and then nothing
pero ahí empezó un poco y después nada
一场场比赛我们都试图看看我能如何施压。
Game by game we tried to see how I could press.
Partido a partido fuimos tratando de ver cómo yo podía presionar.
发生的事情是他让我做了三个压力
What happened is that he made me do three pressures
lo que pasa es que él me hacía hacer tres presiones
我不习惯，我在心里说，你让我失去了稍后攻击的精力。
I wasn't used to it and in my head I said, you took the energy out of me to attack later.
que yo no estaba acostumbrado y yo en mi cabeza decía, me sacaste energía para atacar después.
我想拯救自己，这样我就可以进攻，所以如果他们出来打球，我会首先施加压力
I wanted to save myself so I could attack so I made the first pressure if they came out playing it was
yo quería guardarme para poder atacar entonces yo hacía la primera presión si salían jugando era
出去找弓箭手。
Go out to the archer.
Salir al arquero.
然后，如果守门员与后卫一起踢球，则出向后卫。
then if the goalkeeper played with the defender, go out to the defender.
después si el arquero jugaba con el defensa, salir al defensa.
如果后卫回去与守门员比赛，他就必须回到中间，很多时候你会被一支球队抓住……
and if the defender went back to play with the goalkeeper he had to go back to the middle and many times you are caught by a team that...
y si el defensa volvía a jugar con el arquero tenía que volver para el medio y muchas veces que te agarran un equipo que...
守门员得到防守，你就在那里
the goalkeeper is given the defense, you out there
el arquero se le da la defensa, vos por ahí
他告诉我要掩护守门员，这样他就不会回来，但发生了什么？
That's what he told me is to cover the goalkeeper so that he doesn't come back, but what's happening?
es lo que me decía es tapar el arquero para que no vuelva pero qué pasa que por ahí
后卫交给中场，第一个触球的中场交给守门员
the defender is given to the midfielder and the first touch midfielder is given to the goalkeeper
el defensa se le da al medio campista y al medio campista de primer toque se le da al arquero
然后你必须再次回到中间
then you have to go back to the middle again
entonces vos ya tenés que volver de nuevo para el medio
守门员多次让她在那里并与飞行员待在一起。
and the goalkeeper has her there many times and stays with the pilot.
y el arquero la tiene por ahí muchas veces y queda con la pilota.
是时候重新开始了，守门员可以做……
and it was time to start again and the goalkeeper could do...
y era otra vez a arrancar y el arquero podía hacer...
再次左侧或左侧
again the left side or the left
otra vez la lateral izquierdo o el izquierdo
突然，当我要压迫守门员时速度很快，然后我回来了……然后……
Suddenly when I was going to press the goalkeeper was quick, then I came back... then...
de repente cuando yo iba a presionar se le daba rápido el arquero, entonces volví... entonces...
这对我来说很难，因为我要去那里、这里、那里、那里。
It was difficult for me because I was going there, here, there, there.
Me costaba un montón porque yo era para allá, para acá, para allá, para allá.
另外，一切都会咬人。
Plus, everything bites.
Además, todo piques.
他不想让我小跑，他想让我劈砍。
He didn't want me to go trotting, he wanted me to go chop.
No quería que yo vaya al trote, quería que yo vaya a las chop.
我不能，我发誓。
and I couldn't, I swear.
y no podía, te juro.
我说他妈的，然后我抓住了球，它掉了下来，我抓住了球然后......
I said the fucking mother, then I grabbed the ball and it fell, I grabbed the ball and...
Decía la puta madre, después agarraba el pelote y se me caía, agarraba el pelote y...
他会从下面经过，我会说，该死。
He would pass by below and I would say, damn it.
Se pasaba por abajo y yo decía, la puta madre.
直到有一天，有时在比赛中我说，好吧，就是这样，压力就是那样，那样，那样。
Until at one point, sometimes in the game I said, well, that's it, pressure like that, like that, and like that.
Hasta que en un momento, algunas veces en el partido decía, bueno, ya está, presión así, así y así ya.
我就这样呆着，我这样做，仅此而已。
I stayed like this, I do this and that's it.
Yo me quedé así, hago esto y ya está.
我并不是说要下地狱，但是...
I wasn't saying to go to hell, but...
No decía que se vaya a la mierda, pero...
但我认为我想要进攻，我也想要进球。
but I thought I wanted to attack, I also wanted to score goals.
pero pensaba que quería atacar, también quería hacer goles.
依此类推，直到那个冬天他带来了加布里埃尔·热苏斯。
And so on until, well, then he brings Gabriel Jesús that winter.
Y así hasta que, bueno, después él trae en ese invierno trae a Gabriel Jesús.
在那里他开始改变我，轮换我。
And there he began to change me, to rotate me.
Y ahí él empezó a cambiarme, a rotarme.
随后加布里埃尔和热苏斯开始首发。
and then Gabriel and Jesús began to play as a starter.
y después Gabriel y Jesús empezó a jugar titular.
好吧，我已经在那里了，已经在我的脑海里了，我决定，就这样了。
And well, I was already there, already in my head, I decided, that's it.
Y bueno, yo ya ahí, ya mi cabeza, decidito, ya está.
我必须退出这里，因为我不想再玩了。
I have to quit here because I'm not going to play anymore.
Yo ya tengo que rajar acá porque no voy a jugar más.
然后加布里埃尔·赫苏斯操了第五个塔梅尔西亚人。
And then Gabriel Jesús fucks the fifth Tamercian.
Y después Gabriel Jesús se jode el quinto tamerciano.
我认为反对他
I think against him
creo que contra el
博尔穆斯在第30分钟受伤
Bormus is injured in the 30 minutes
el Bormus, se lesiona en los 30 minutos
当我进来时，他们给了他大约三个月、四个月的时间，他错过了这个赛季。
And there I come in and they give him about three months, four months, he missed the season.
Y ahí entro yo y a él le dan como tres meses, cuatro meses, se perdió la temporada.
我在那里说，我是唯一的前锋。
And there I said, I am the only forward.
Y yo ahí dije, soy el único delantero.
我必须比赛，从那时起我就开始比赛，我开始进球、进球、进球，最后我得到了 30 个左右
I have to play and that's when I started to play and I started scoring goals, goals, goals and I ended up with 30 something
tengo que jugar y ahí empecé yo a jugar y empecé a hacer goles, goles, goles y terminé con 30 y pico
前面还有佩佩？
and pepe in front of that?
y pepe frente a eso?
他什么也没告诉我
he didn't tell me anything
no me dijo nada
我们在那里没有说话，这很正常。
We didn't speak there, it was normal.
Ahí no dirigíamos la palabra, era normal.
你没说话吗？
Didn't you speak?
¿No hablabas?
不不，正常聊天，你好，美好的一天，诸如此类。
No, no, normal chat, hello, good day, such.
No, no, charla normal, hola, buen día, tal.
但他不是让你再按一下，做那三个压力吗？
But didn't he ask you to press again, to do those three pressures?
Pero no te pidió volver a presionar, a hacer esas tres presiones?
是的，是的，我不认为这是压力，但是……
Yes, yes, I didn't think that was the pressure, but...
Sí, sí, no me decía tal las presiones, pero...
但事情有点……我想他适应了我。
But it went a little... I think he accommodated me.
pero me fue un poco... yo creo que me fue acomodando él.
他理解我将如何去做。
And he was understanding to me how I am going to do it.
Y él fue entendiendo a mí cómo voy a hacer.
进而...
And then...
Y después...
从那里开始，就不是人们想到的，而是后来的事了
from there it is not that one thinks about that later it is
de ahí no es que uno piensa por ahí después sea
我相信他不爱我，但实际上他是教练，人们今天会想
I believed that he didn't love me, but in reality he was the coach and one thinks today
Yo por ahí creía que él no me quería, pero en realidad él era el técnico y uno piensa hoy
并不是他不爱我，而是事情没有按照他想要的方式发展。
It's not that he didn't love me, it wasn't working out the way he wanted.
que no es que no me quería, no le estaba funcionando como él quería.
它必须得到尊重。
and it had to be respected.
y había que respetarlo.
今天，球员们思考并说，他不爱我。
Today the players think and say, he doesn't love me.
Hoy los jugadores piensan y dicen, no me quiere.
不，他并不是不爱你。
No, it's not that he doesn't love you.
No, no es que no te quiere.
他对一切都非常个人化。
He takes everything very personally.
Se toma todo muy personal.
当然我当时是这么想的，但后来我意识到
Of course I thought that at that moment but then I realized
claro yo por ahí en ese momento pensaba eso pero después me di cuenta
事实并非如此，然后我开始相处得很好。
That wasn't the case and then I started to get along very well.
que no era así y después empecé a llevar muy bien.
后来和他在一起时，他告诉我，很多次他告诉我，留在这里。
And later with him he told me, many times he told me, stay here.
Y después con él ya me decía, muchas veces me decía, quedate acá.
有了这个中锋，我不想让这个中锋打球。
With this center I don't want this center to play.
Con esta central no quiero que juegue esta central.
靠近他。
Stay close to him.
Quédate pegadito a él.
我唯一要求你的就是靠近，我会留在那里。
The only thing I ask of you is to stay close and I'll stay there.
Lo único que te pido es pegadito y yo me quedo ahí.
他后来告诉我，当然，他已经开始明白，当我们进攻时，我们就赢得了比赛。
And he tells me later, of course, he already began to understand that when we attack, we win the game.
Y me dice después, claro, él ya empezó a entender que cuando ataquemos, ganamos el partido.
我们就是这样开始的，然后我们开始建立起非常好的关系。
And that's how we started and then we started to have a very good relationship.
Y así empezamos y después ahí empezamos a tener muy buena relación.
但是，嘿，一开始我们都在那里，这很有帮助。
But hey, it helped that at the beginning we were both there.
Pero bueno, sirvió que al principio estemos ahí los dos.
不是因为生气，我没有感觉到他在生我的气，而是……
Not out of anger, I didn't feel that he was angry with me, but rather...
No de bronca, yo no sentía que él me tenía bronca, sino que...
今天我想，在那一刻他正在寻找......
that today I think, at that moment he was looking for...
que hoy pienso, en ese momento él buscaba que...
由于不施压，他把一切都搞砸了
By not pressing he screwed up everything
al no presionar le jodía todo el
他想要制定的计划，他所需要的所有压力
the scheme he wanted to make, all the pressure he needed to make it
el esquema que él quería hacer, toda la presión que él necesitaba hacerla
如果我做得不好，我就会毁掉一切，这就是我正在做的事情，我会毁掉所有的压力。
If I didn't do it well, I would ruin everything, which was what I was doing, I would ruin all the pressure.
Si yo no lo hacía bien, cagaba todo, que era lo que estaba haciendo, estaba cagando todas las presiones.
好吧，我想，想象一下，他之后会发烧。
And well, I think that, imagine, he gets a fever afterwards.
Y bueno, yo creo que, imagínate, se agarra una escalentura después.
因为我向两边施压，有时我必须关闭中间，我知道我必须关闭中间，但是......
because I pressed on either side, sometimes I had to close the middle, I knew I had to close the middle, but...
porque yo presionaba para cualquier lado, a veces tenía que cerrar el medio, que yo sabía que tenía que cerrar el medio, pero...
当他挂断电话时，他没有闭嘴，他看着我说，塞尔吉奥……
When he hung up, he wouldn't close and he looked at me and said, Sergio...
de colgado, no cerraba y me miraba y decía, Sergio...
我开始说，你想让我做什么？
And I started to say, what do you want me to do?
Y yo empecé a decir, ¿qué querés que haga?
但是好吧，直到康复之前，我一直在学习并且......
But well, until well, I was learning and...
Pero bueno, así hasta que bueno, fui aprendiendo y...
事实上，体育对我来说非常好。
The truth is that for me PE is very good.
La verdad es que para mí PE es muy bueno.
他所做的每一件事以及最后的一件事......
in everything he does and in the end one...
en todo lo que hace y al final uno...
如果你注意他想做什么，他最终会......
If you pay attention to what he wants to do, he ends up...
Si presta atención lo que él quiere hacer, termina...
这很困难
it's very difficult
es muy difícil
一支球队以同样的方式击败了佩普，因为没有
that a team beats pep in the same way because not
que un equipo le gana a pep de la misma manera porque no
这是不可能的，他对一切都研究得很透彻。
It's impossible, he has everything very studied.
Es imposible, lo tiene todo muy estudiado.
而且对手已经知道他要做什么，他马上就知道，比赛一开始。
And the opponent already knows what he is going to do, he knows right away, as soon as the game begins.
Y ya sabe el rival lo que va a hacer, sabe enseguida, apenas empieza el partido.
我给了你一个位置，并告诉你当比赛开始时，我会给他们一个信号，看看是否可以。
I gave you a position and told you when the game starts, I'm going to give them a sign to see if it's okay.
te ponía una posición y te decía cuando empiece el partido yo les voy a hacer una seña a ver si es
他已经把可能发生的一切都想好了。
He already had everything in mind that could happen.
él ya tenía todo mentalizado que podía llegar a pasar.
没有什么，比赛开始了，托佩说，塞尔吉奥，现在去那里。
And nothing, the game started, Topay said, Sergio, now go over there.
Y nada, empezaba el partido, Topay decía, Sergio, ahora vete para allá.
塞尔吉奥，现在站在这里。
Sergio, now stand here.
Sergio, ahora ponete acá.
当他们行动时他就知道一切，但他非常出色。
He knew everything when they were making a move, but he is very good.
Sabía todo cuando ellos iban haciendo algún movimiento, pero es muy bueno.
在我接受的培训中，最好的。
Of the training I had, the best.
De lo entrenado que yo tuve, el mejor.
我进步了。
I improve.
Mejoro.
是的，百分之一百。
Yes, one hundred percent.
Sí, cien por cien.
后来和其他人一起，我有了更多的东西。
Later with others I had more around.
Después con otros tuve más por ahí.
更多的谈论并不意味着他们不好，但他们有不同的策略，例如
more talk that doesn't mean they are bad but they had different tactics e.g.
más charla que no quiere decir son malos pero tenían diferentes tácticas por ejemplo
曼奇尼的防守更加严密。
Mancini was more defensive.
Mancini era más defensivo.
在那里我们以一比零获胜并取得了领先。
and there we were winning one to zero and we took the lead.
y por ahí íbamos ganando un a cero y sacaba lo delantero.
但是，嘿，这就是他的比赛方法。
But hey, it was his method of play.
Pero bueno, era su método de juego.
所以，我们最终成为了英超冠军。
So, we ended up becoming Premier champion.
Entonces, terminamos saliendo campeón de la Premier.
然后佩莱格里尼来了，他与众不同，更加……
and then came Pellegrini who was different, who was more...
y después vino Pellegrini que era diferente, que era más...
中间有更多，更多游戏，什么也没有，买。
have more in the middle, more game and nothing, buy.
tener más en el medio, más juego y nada, compera.
疯狂的是，他没有辞职，也就是说，总是同一个计划。
The crazy thing is that he doesn't resign, that is, it was always the same scheme.
lo loco es que él no renuncia o sea era el mismo esquema siempre
他总是做同样的动作，或者如果他们做了这样的动作，他就会改变它，但是
and he always did the same movement or if they made such a movement he changed it but
y siempre hacía lo mismo movimiento o si ellos hacían tal movimiento él lo cambiaba pero
没有改变，那就是，他和他一起死了。
It didn't change, that is, he died with his.
no cambiaba, o sea, él moría con la suya.
也许其他教练所拥有的就是他们改变了。
Maybe what other coaches have is that they change.
Quizás otros entrenadores lo que tienen es que van cambiando.
他带着这个想法死去了。
He dies with the idea of ​​it.
Él muere con la idea de él.
就是这样。
And that's it.
Y ya está.
我想去 9320，这是马丁·泰勒的预兆。
I want to go to 9320, that omen Martin Taylor.
Quiero ir al 9320, ese agüero de Martin Taylor.
你知道吗，他给了我……现在当我走的时候，他给了我……
Did you know that he gave me... now when I went he gave me the...
¿Sabías que me regaló... ahora cuando yo fui me regaló el...
你怎么说？
How do you say?
¿Cómo se dice?
当他们在比赛前拿起笔记本、做笔记时……
When they, before the game, take the notebook, take the notes...
Cuando ellos, antes del partido, toman la libreta, toman las notas...
他给了我所有的笔记。
He gave me all the notes.
Me regaló todas las notas.
天才，天才。
Genius, genius.
Genio, genio.
我不明白……没什么，神奇宝贝，想象一下。
I didn't understand a... Nothing, Pokémon, imagine.
No entendí un... Nada, Pokémon, imagínate.
最重要的是，所有内容都用英语写在那里。
It had everything written there in English on top of everything.
Tenía todo escrito ahí en inglés encima de todo chiquitito.
数字。
The numbers.
Los números.
我想笔记本应该在某个地方。
I think the notebook comes somewhere.
Creo que viene a algún lado la libreta.
我想我已经发布了。
I think I posted it.
Creo que yo lo posteé.
他把它给了我，我说，哦，看，他向我解释了它。
He gave it to me and I said, oh, look, and he explained it to me.
Me lo regaló y yo dije, ah, mira, y él me explicó.
当然，我们，我，我不知道这一切，你明白吗？
That we, of course, I, I don't know all this, you see?
que nosotros, claro, yo, todo esto yo no sé, ¿viste?
我不知道记者在比赛前会做什么，但今天我很清楚为什么。
I don't know what a reporter does before a game, today I know why well.
que lo que hace un relator ante un partido, no sé, hoy por ahí ya se porque bueno.
我更多地参与了这一切，但是当然，我……
I'm more involved in all this, but of course, and I had...
Estoy más metido en todo esto, pero claro, y tenía...
一切都写下来了，当然，我已经写下了……
Everything written down, of course, I had written down that...
Todo anotado, claro, tenía anotado que...
当然，最后你会觉得自己疯了……
Of course, then you think you're crazy, in the end...
que claro, después uno piensa que loco, al final...
他正在学习。
He is studying.
Está estudiando.
你必须有一个班级，因为你必须有所有的名字。
You have to have a class because you have to have all the names.
Hay que tener una clase porque tenés que tener todos los nombres.
有多少场比赛？
How many games there?
¿Cuántos partidos por ahí?
最后一个进球是什么时候？
When was the last goal?
¿Cuándo fue el último gol?
最后一次黄是什么时候？
When was the last yellow?
¿Cuándo fue la última amarilla?
或者最后一个游戏做了这样的事情或者一切都在那里详细说明
or this last game did such a thing or everything is detailed there
o este el último partido hizo tal cosa o sea todo ahí detallado
太不可思议了。
It's incredible.
Es increíble.
如今有了手机，您就拥有了更多工具。
Today with the phone you have more tools.
Hoy con el teléfono tenés más herramientas.
你有更多的工具。
You have more tools.
Tienes más herramientas.
但他说的是 2012 年，也就是 12 年前。
But he's talking about 2012, 12 years ago.
Pero está hablando del 2012, 12 años atrás.
我想之前已经花了 50 页了。
I imagine before that 50 pages were spent.
Me imagino antes que se gastaban 50 páginas.
嗯，我有一个议程，其中写下了培训课程和其他内容，但我在电话里有很多事情。
Well, I have an agenda in which I write down the training sessions, something else, but I have a lot of things on the phone.
Bueno yo tengo una agenda en la que anoto las formaciones, alguna cosa más, pero tengo muchas cosas en el teléfono.
当然，当然，当然。
Of course, of course, of course.
Claro, claro, claro.
当然，因为今天你可以在电话里看到那里，你可以看到团队。
Of course, because today you can see on the phone there, you can see the team.
Claro, porque hoy puedes ver en el teléfono por ahí, puedes ver el equipo.
是的，团队。
Yes, the team.
Sí, el equipo.
另一件事是关于玩家的一些事情。
And the other thing is some things about the player.
Y lo otro por ahí algunas cosas del jugador.
甚至是实时统计数据，比如你传对了多少次，错了多少次
even live statistics, let's say how many passes you made right, how many wrong
incluso las estadísticas en vivo, digamos cuántos pases diste bien, cuántos mal
嗯，这是为那些认为这很容易的人准备的。
Well, this is for people who think it's easy.
Bueno, esto es para la gente que piensa que es fácil.
这并不容易。
It's not easy.
No es fácil.
而且进球也不容易。
And it's not easy to score goals either.
Y no es fácil meter goles tampoco.
不，都不是。
No, neither.
No, tampoco.
我想去那个地方，伙计。
I want to go to that one, dude.
Quiero ir a ese, güey.
每次我看那场比赛时，有一种东西让我抓狂，那就是踢球前的那一秒停顿。
There's something that drives me crazy every time I see that play, it's that second of pause you take before kicking.
Hay algo que me vuelve loco cada vez que veo esa jugada, es ese segundo de pausa que te tomas antes de patear.
93-20 冠军就在眼前，正如他们在英格兰和美国所说的那样。
93-20 the title, on the line, as they say in England, in the United States.
93-20 el título, on the line, como dicen en Inglaterra, en Estados Unidos.
然后你就开始踢球
and you take that second to kick
y vos te tomás ese segundo para patear
有时候，你有心情说，不，不，再等一秒钟，然后结束它。
There is a moment when you have the mood and say, no, no, one more second and then finish it off.
Hay un momento en el que tenés el tipo y decís, no, no, un segundito más y después rematar.
这是习惯，是自动的，它与你打球的方式有关。
That's habit, that's automatic, it has to do with the way you play.
Eso es hábito, eso es automático, tiene que ver con tu manera de jugar.
并且不是自动的
and not automatic
y no automático
不，不是自动的。
No, not automatic.
No, automático no.
这是很自然的，因为...
It's natural because...
Es natural porque...
如果我这么想的话
If I had thought let's say that
si hubiese pensado digamos que
或者我以为它已经结束了，我内心知道它已经结束了，
or I thought it was already ending, that inside I knew it was ending,
o yo pensaba que ya estaba terminando, que por dentro sabía que estaba terminando,
但我所做的一切都是自然的，否则我就会踢得更早。
but what I did was all natural because otherwise I would have kicked sooner.
pero lo que hice fue todo natural porque si no yo hubiese pateado antes.
所以我所做的是...
So what I did was...
Entonces lo que yo hice fue...
那一刻我知道后卫
At that moment I knew that the defender
En ese momento yo sabía que el defensa
我要迟到了，我已经知道我会先到，但在我的脑海里却是……
I was going to be late, I already knew I was going to arrive first, but in my head it was...
iba a llegar tarde, yo ya sabía que iba a llegar primero, pero en mi cabeza fue...
如果我向前碰她一点，她就会踩到我，这是一种惩罚。
If I touch her a little bit forward, she's going to step on me and it's a penalty.
Si la toco un poquito para adelante, me va a pisar y es penal.
或者如果我踢，可能是我踢得笨拙或踢得不好，也可能是我们两个人之间的事情。
Or if I kick, it may be that I kick awkwardly or badly, or it may be between the two of us.
O si pateo puede ser que patee incómodo o mal, o trabemos entre los dos.
只有我们两个人到达，但我通过把它指向前方一点就知道了
that just the two of us arrived, but I knew that by pointing it a little forward
que llegamos justo los dos, pero yo sabía que punteándola un poquito para adelante
这让我犯罪。
It makes me criminal.
Me hace penal.
我的意思是，我的头脑很犯罪。
I mean, my head was criminal.
O sea, mi cabeza era penal.
但会发生什么呢？
But what happens?
Pero ¿qué pasa?
当我...
When I...
Cuando yo la...
我在前面碰了一点，他碰了我的脚踝，虽然勉强，但非常......
I touch a little in front, he touches my ankle, barely, but it was very...
toco un poquito delante, él me toca el tobillo, apenas, pero fue muy...
他非常温柔地抓住了我，那时我就有时间踢了。
He grabbed me very gently and that's when I had time to kick.
me agarró muy suave y ahí cuando me queda para patear
我的想法是跨越它。
My idea was to cross it.
mi idea era cruzarla.
但可以看出，当你想跨越它时
but it is seen that when you want to cross it
pero se ve que al querer cruzarla
这种事在我身上发生过很多次，我在尝试越过球门时进了很多球，因为通过观察球门......
It happened to me a lot, I have scored many goals trying to cross it, because by looking at the goal...
Me pasó mucho, he hecho muchos goles queriendo cruzarla, porque por mirar el arco...
从我眼角的余光中，球对我来说向前移动了一点
out of the corner of my eye, the ball goes a little forward for me then
de reojo, la pelota se me va un poco para adelante entonces
现在这让我更不舒服，当我踢它时，它总是转到第一个帖子，因为
It makes me more uncomfortable now and when I kick it always goes to the first post because
ya me queda más incómoda y cuando pateo va siempre al primer palo porque
我正在思考拱门在哪里，我用眼角的余光看到了拱门。
I'm thinking about where the arch is, out of the corner of my eye I'm seeing the arch.
Yo estoy pensando en dónde está el arco, de reojo voy viendo el arco.
好吧，我得到了第一根我不想扔在那里的棍子
and well, and I get the first stick that I didn't want to throw there
y bueno, y me sale el primer palo que yo no quería tirarle ahí
我想射第二步，但是嘿，这是一个进球。
I wanted to shoot the second step, but hey, it was a goal.
Quería tirar al segundo paso, pero bueno, fue gol.
它们是自然的东西，这是自然的
They are things that are natural, it is natural that
Son cosas que es natural, es natural que
我还以为我根本没说清楚。
I also thought that I was not clear at all.
también pensé que no tuve ninguna clara.
我说我要下去接整场比赛都没下来的球，所以
I say I'm going to go down to receive the ball that hadn't come down in the entire game so
Digo voy a bajar a recibir la pelota que no había bajado en todo el partido entonces
我不知道，这一切都非常...
I don't know, it was all very...
No sé, fue todo como muy...
很奇怪，或者说有能力，一定是这样，嗯，就是这样。
very strange, or capable it had to be like that, well it was like that.
muy extraño, o capaz tenía que ser así, bueno fue así.
但我下去了，Deshon把它给了我，谁……
But I went down, Deshon gave it to me, who...
pero bajé, me la da Deshon, que...
最重要的是，我们都在该地区。
On top of that, we were all in the area.
que encima estábamos todos en el área.
介质位于外部和中心。
The medium was outside and center.
El medio era para afuera y centro.
一切都是空中球。
Everything was aerial ball.
Todo era pelota aérea.
我不知道为什么我会想到要下去，我说好吧，下来吧，我之前已经告诉巴洛特利了
and I don't know why it occurred to me to go down and I said well come down and I had told Balotelli before
y no sé por qué se me ocurrió bajar y dije bueno bajo y yo le había dicho a Balotelli antes
靠近我，看看我能否把它给你，我们可以建造一堵墙。
Stay close to me, let's see if I can give it to you and we can make a wall.
Quédate cerca mío, a ver si yo te la puedo dar y hacemos una pared.
嗯，他西班牙语说得很好，他告诉我，是的，是的，是的，是的，一切都是。
Well, he speaks Spanish quite well and he tells me, yes, yes, yes, yes, everything yes.
pues habla bastante bien español y me dice, sí, sí, sí, sí, todo sí.
好吧，当我对他这么做时，好的一点是我之前已经说过了，因为……
And well, when I did it to him, the good thing is that I had already said it before, because...
Y bueno, cuando se lo hice, lo bueno es que yo ya lo había dicho antes, porque...
如果我没有告诉他，有时候能说话也很好。
If I hadn't told him that, sometimes it's also good to be able to talk.
Si yo no le hubiese dicho eso, también a veces es bueno poder hablar.
在球场上，因为如果我什么都不说，马里奥可能会把它给他
on the court because if I hadn't said anything, Mario might have given it to him
en la cancha porque si yo no hubiese dicho nada capaz que Mario al sual dársela
马里奥的马忍受它并在外面玩耍，或者忍受它并想要踢
Mario's horse puts up with it and plays outside or puts up with it and wants to kick
el caballo de Mario lo aguanta y juega para afuera o lo aguanta y quiere patear
所以，正如我告诉他的，我们建造了一堵墙，我把它给你，你把它还给我。
So, as I told him, we make a wall and I give it to you and you give it back to me.
Entonces, como yo le dije, hacemos una pared que yo te la doy y me la devuelves.
他说，他会无意识地这么想。
He would have unconsciously thought that, he said.
él eso inconscientemente habrá pensado, dijo él.
如果你给我，我就会给你。
If you give it to me, I'm going to give it to you.
Si me la da, yo se la voy a dar.
事实也是如此。
And so it was.
Y así fue.
一切都变得非常...可以说...
Everything turned out very... let's say...
Todo salió muy... digamos...
一切都很奇怪，但最终对每个人都有好处。
Everything was very strange, but in the end it was good for everyone.
muy extraño todo, pero al final fue bueno para todos.
是的，这很自然，当你考虑定义时我总是告诉你
Yes, it is all natural, when you think about defining I always tell you
sí que es todo natural, uno cuando piensa en definir siempre le digo
我也和我的儿子 Benjal 聊了很多，我说，你们这个地区不......
I also talk a lot with my son, with Benjal, and I say, you in the area don't...
también hablo bastante con mi hijo, con Benjal, y digo, vos en el área no...
你的思考时间不能超过一分半钟。
You can't think for more than a second and a half.
No puedes pensar más de un segundo y medio.
别想了。
Don't think.
No pienses.
又如何呢？
And how?
¿Y cómo?
别想了。
Don't think.
No pienses.
想象一下拱门在你后面，当你在拱门前面时
Imagine that the arch is behind you and when you are in front of the arch
Imagínate que el arco está atrás tuyo y cuando estás enfrente del arco
快点，等一下，想象一下他必须把球扔到哪里，因为该地区没有时间。
Quick, just a second, imagine where he has to throw it because there is no time in the area.
rápido, un segundo, imaginate dónde la tiene que tirar porque no hay tiempo en el área.
只需按一下或按两下
and it's one touch or two touches
y es un toque o dos toques
然后在外面，当你们手牵手的时候，你有时间思考你是否爱他
then outside when you come hand in hand you have time to think if you love him
después afuera cuando venís mano a mano tenés tiempo para pensar si le querés
他攻击它，他想把它钩到外面。
he attacks it, he wants to hook it to the outside.
la embetear, le quiere enganchar para afuera.
在里面，无论你想要什么，你都有更多的时间来思考，或者当你与守门员并肩作战时，你有
inside, whatever you want, there you have a little more second to think or when you go hand to hand with the goalkeeper you have
para adentro, lo que vos quieras, ahí tenés un poquito más de segundo para pensar o cuando vas mano a mano con el arquero tenés
也有几秒钟的时间去思考，但是当该地区有如此多的骚乱时，你就没有那么多的时间去思考，所以
also seconds to think, but when there is so much commotion in the area, you don't have that much to think, so
también segundos para pensar, pero cuando hay tanto alboroteo en el área, no tenés tanto para pensar, entonces
尽你所能踢球，居中，一击。
Kick as you can, center, one touch.
Patía como puedas, centro, un toque.
或停下来踢。
or stop and kick.
o parar y patear.
没有时间，因为我和我的孩子们去看他们踢球……
There is no time because I see and the boys I go to see them play and...
No hay tiempo porque yo veo y los chicos los voy a ver a jugar y...
他们阻止了她，你看，让我们看看会发生什么……不，不，没有时间在该地区。
and they stop her, you see, and let's see what... No, no, there is no time in the area.
y la paran, viste, y a ver qué... No, no, en el área no hay tiempo.
通过经验，人们认识到这一点，我尝试告诉他，以便
and through experience one realizes this and I try to tell it to him so that
y uno por experiencia así se va dando cuenta y yo lo trato de decir a él para que
这样他就知道前锋没有那么多时间思考。
so that he gets it into his head that a striker doesn't have that much time to think.
para que se meta en la cabeza que un delantero no tiene tanto tiempo para pensar.
你喜欢 Benja 是一名足球运动员吗？
Do you like that Benja is a soccer player?
¿Te gusta que Benja sea futbolista?
是的，是的，但我现在很好，我很好，我们聊了很多
yes yes but I'm fine now I'm fine we talk a lot
sí sí pero bueno estoy ahora le estoy bueno hablamos bastante
他已经长大了，他马上就15岁了，是的。
He's already grown up, he's going to be 15 years old and yes.
Ya está grande, va a cumplir 15 años y sí.
显然我喜欢成为一名足球运动员，但我是其中之一......
Obviously I like being a footballer, but I'm one of those who...
Obvio que me gusta ser futbolista, pero yo soy de esos de que...
我想非常认真地做每一件事，因为...
I want to do everything very seriously because...
Quiero hacerlo todo en muy serio porque...
我告诉你，在我的时代，当我开始的时候
I tell you, in my time, when I started
Yo le digo, en mi época, cuando yo arranqué
14岁时我停止了学习。
At 14 years old I stopped studying.
Yo a los 14 años dejé de estudiar.
我停止了学习，因为我的老人抓住了我并告诉我
and I stopped studying because my old man grabbed me and told me
y yo dejé de estudiar porque mi viejo me agarró y me dijo
你在学习还是要去踢足球？
Are you studying or are you going to play soccer?
¿estudias o vas a jugar al fútbol?
他告诉我的第一件事就是足球，我儿子告诉我，你不会错过它。
And the first thing he told me was football and my son told me, you're not going to miss it.
Y lo primero que me dijo fue fútbol y mi hijo me dijo, no vas a faltar.
不训练，不管下多大雨、打雷等等。
to no training, no matter how much it rains, thunder, whatever.
a ningún entrenamiento, por más que llueva, caiga trueno, lo que sea.
你是唯一一个要训练的人，如果有的话，就训练吧。
You are the only one who is going to train, if there is one, train.
sos el único que va a entrenar, si hay uno, entrená.
事实也是如此。
And so it was.
Y así fue.
我开始训练、训练、训练，我从来没有错过过。
I started training, training, training and I never missed it.
Yo empecé a entrenar, entrenar, entrenar y no faltaba nunca.
好吧，这就是我后来到达的方式，一个人可以有才华，但是
and well and that's how I arrived later one can have talent but
y bueno y así llegué además después uno puede tener talento pero
有很多球员，因为他们有很好的天赋，
There are many players who, because they have good talent,
Hay muchos jugadores que, por tener buen talento,
还剩下一些培训课程，他们正在开始……
There are still some training sessions left and they are starting to...
por ahí faltan algunos entrenamientos y empiezan a...
放松一下，结果他们没有到达。
to relax and well they end up not arriving.
a relajarse y bueno terminan no llegando.
嗯，那是我老人家的头，所以我告诉他的是，他有机会
Well, that was my old man's head, so what I tell him is that he has the opportunity
Bueno, esa era su cabeza de mi viejo, entonces yo lo que le digo a él es que tiene la oportunidad
学习。
to study.
de estudiar.
我告诉你的是要充分利用足球，因为......
What I tell you is to take full advantage of football because...
que lo que yo le digo es que aproveche a full el fútbol porque...
如果他去是因为他喜欢这样，这可能会发生在我身上，我去是因为……
If he goes because he feels like it, it could happen to me, I go because...
Si él va porque tiene ganas, a mí te puede pasar, voy porque...
我的老人打球，我的祖父也打球。
My old man played ball and my grandfather too.
Mi viejo jugaba a la pelota y mi abuelo también.
而且我也是……不，我也不是。
And I'm also... No, not me too.
Y yo también quedo... No, yo también no.
他不是我的祖父，我的老人，什么都不是。
He's not my grandfather, my old man, nothing.
No es mi abuelo, mi viejo, nada.
如果你去，那是因为你更喜欢足球，因为你更喜欢训练。
If you go, it's because you enjoy football more, because you enjoy training more.
Si vas, es porque te da más al fútbol, porque te da más entrenar.
因为你想要到达那里，我的意思是，你明白你在说什么吗？你想要到达那里，如果不……
and because you want to get there, I mean, do you understand what you're saying, that you want to get there, if not...
y porque querés llegar, o sea, me entiendes lo que dices, que querés llegar, si no...
别浪费时间了，你也可以学习。
Don't waste time, you can study too.
No pierdas el tiempo, puedes estudiar también.
不，不，我想玩，准备好了。
No, no, I want to play, ready.
No, no, quiero jugar, listo.
如果你想玩，我就陪你。
If you want to play, I'll accompany you.
Si vos querés jugar, yo te acompaño.
好吧，我们到了，但是……
And well, there we are, but...
Y bueno, ahí estamos, pero...
但显然很多人说，呃，但不，不。
But obviously a lot of people say, eh, but no, no.
Pero obviamente que para ahí mucha gente dice, eh, pero no, no.
你强迫他吗？
Are you forcing him?
¿Lo estás obligando?
不，我没有义务。
No, I am not obliged.
No, no estoy obligado.
我希望你认真对待这件事。
I want you to take this seriously.
Quiero que se lo tome serio.
归根结底，足球并不容易。
In the end, football is not easy.
Al final, el fútbol no es fácil.
我不想要的是几年后
and what I don't want is that in a few years
y yo lo que no quiero es que por ahí dentro de unos años
他告诉我，好吧，我不想玩了，你不让我学习，你明白吗？
He told me, well, I don't want to play anymore and you stopped me from studying, do you understand?
me diga, bueno, ya no quiero jugar más y me dejaste de estudiar, ¿entendés?
所以...
So...
Entonces...
或者先想一下。
or think about it before.
o pensalo antes.
所以，你今天要争取的，就是仔细想想你要做什么。
So, what you want to fight for today is to think carefully about what you want to do.
Entonces, el que quieres luchar desde hoy es pensar bien lo que quieres hacer.
我知道之后，显然，你没有问题......
I know that afterwards, obviously, you have no problem to...
Sé que después, obviamente, no tiene problema para...
能够学习任何东西，但你会错过几年的时间
to be able to study whatever but you are going to miss a few years let's say
para poder estudiar lo que sea pero se va a perder unos años digamos
也许我当时无法完成的研究。
of studies that perhaps I could not do at that time.
de estudios que quizás yo en ese momento no lo podía.
我开始学习
I started to learn
Yo empecé a aprender
事情取决于旅行或与老年人一起。
things depending on trips or with older people.
cosas según los viajes o con gente grande.
英语他们什么都不懂，有机会的都是外面的东西
English they didn't know anything and those who have the opportunity are things that out there
inglés no sabían nada y el que tiene la oportunidad son cosas que por ahí
你小时候过着什么样的生活，你想尝试让你的儿子过什么样的生活
what you live as a child you want to try to make your son
uno lo que vive de chico lo quiere tratar de que el hijo
进步，他比我好一点，他确实如此，但有些事情仍然存在
progress, that he is a little better than I was, which he is, but there are things that still
progrese, que esté un poco mejor de lo que yo estaba, que él está, pero hay cosas que todavía
它可以在各个方面得到改进。
It can be improved in every way.
se puede mejorar en todo sentido.
你提到了他的祖父，但他的祖父是迭戈·马拉多纳，而不是任何一个打球的祖父。
You named his grandfather, but his grandfather was Diego Maradona, not just any grandfather who played ball.
Nombrabas a su abuelo, pero su abuelo fue Diego Maradona, no cualquier abuelo que jugaba a la pelota.
呃……
eh...
ehh...
是的，我知道，显然。
Yes, I know, obviously.
Sí, ya sé, obviamente.
但嘿，事实是他处理得很好。
But hey, the truth is that he handles it quite well.
Pero bueno, la verdad es que él bastante bien lo lleva.
你很清楚，比方说，
and you know quite well that, let's say,
y sabe bastante bien que, digamos,
有时他没有意识到，例如前几天他想去某个地方
Sometimes he doesn't realize it, for example the other day he wanted to go somewhere
A veces no se da cuenta, por ejemplo el otro día quería ir a un lugar
大约有 700 人。
that there were like 700 people.
que había como 700 personas.
比如露营地之类的。
like a campsite and such.
como un camping y tal.
我告诉他，来吧，你玩得很开心。
I told him, come on, you had fun.
Yo le dije, anda, divertiste.
你可以说出人们对你的了解。
You can say what people do know you.
Puedes decir lo que sí la gente te conoce.
所以现在以后不要说我吃了，因为已经发生了
so now later do not say that I eat because it has happened that
entonces ahora después no diga que como porque ha pasado que
我过得很糟糕，因为我想留在这里。
I had a bad time because I wanted to be here.
La pasé mal porque quería estar acá.
他来了，他打破了我的球，多么好的照片，多么好的视频，多么小的测量，多么好的视频......好吧，这会发生在你身上，我说......
He came, he broke my balls, what a photo, what a video, what a little measurement, what a video... And well, that's going to happen to you, I say...
Venía, me rompía las pelotas, qué foto, qué video, qué midito, qué video... Y bueno, eso te va a pasar, digo...
我一边走一边享受，但是如果你认为有700个人，700个人有能力……
I walked and enjoyed, but if you think that there are 700 people, 700 people capable of...
Yo andaba y disfrutaba, pero si vos pensás que hay 700 personas, 700 personas capaz que...
另外，在阿根廷，你周围可能有 100 个人。
Plus, here in Argentina, maybe 100 are going to be around you.
Encima, acá en Argentina, capaz que 100 van a estar alrededor tuyo.
向您索要照片或想要制作视频。
asking you for photos or wanting to make videos.
pidiéndote fotos o queriendo hacer videos.
有这么多人，嗯，是的。
There are so many people, and well, yes.
tanta gente hay, y bueno, sí.
好吧，不，那我就待在家里，在游泳池里。
Well, no, then I'll stay at home, in the pool.
Bueno, no, entonces me quedo en mi casa, en la pileta.
当然，无论你想要什么，但是嘿，他现在必须玩它......
Whatever you want, of course, but hey, he has to play with it now that...
Lo que vos quieras, claro, pero bueno, ya tiene que jugar con eso ahora que...
他发生了什么事，他要去某个地方，好吧，什么也没有，只是……
What's happening to him, that he's going somewhere and well, nothing, it's...
que le está pasando, que va a algunos lados y bueno, nada, es...
法律就在那里，我是众所周知的，他的祖父，那个家庭，一切。
The law is there and that I am known, that his grandfather, that the family, everything.
la ley esta y de que yo soy conocido, de que su abuelo, de que la familia, todo.
但他渐渐明白了。
But little by little he understands it.
Pero de a poco lo va entendiendo.
他并没有意识到这些事情。
He doesn't realize those things.
no se da cuenta de esas cosas.
我小时候去看电影时就发生过这种事。
It happened to me when I went to the movies as a kid.
A mí me pasaba cuando yo iba de chico al cine
我喜欢和朋友一起去看电影，然后我们会吃披萨
I like to go to the movies with my friends and then we would eat pizza
me gusta ir al cine y con mis amigos y después comíamos pizza
16岁时，我的心思仍然在做同样的事情。
And at 16 I was in the mind and I was still doing the same thing.
Y a los 16 años yo estaba en el mente y seguía haciendo lo mismo.
但粉丝已经开始了，有的红粉，有的粉丝，什么？
But the fans have already started, some red fans, other fans, what?
Pero ya empezaron los hinchas, unos hinchas del rojo, otros hinchas, ¿qué?
他们开始索要照片和一切，但后来......
They started asking for photos and everything, but then...
Empezaron a pedir fotos y todo, pero después...
越来越时髦，越来越流行，有一次我告诉他，嘿，孩子......
hip more, more, more, and there came a time when I told him, hey, boy...
cadera más, más, más, y ya llegó un momento en el que le dije, che, chico...
我们在家看电影，这是不可能的等等。
We watch a cinema at home, it was impossible and so on.
Vemos un cine en casa, era imposible y así.
这种事发生在我身上，但现在发生在他身上的时间要早​​一些。
That happens to me, but well it's happening to him now a little earlier.
a mi me pasa eso, pero bueno a él le está pasando ahora un poquito antes
但他处理得很好。
but he was handling it quite well.
pero lo estaba bastante bien llevando.
此外，他还接受了再教育。
and besides, he is re-educated.
y aparte es re educado.
你和迭戈有职业关系吗？
Did you have a professional relationship with Diego?
¿Tuviste una relación con Diego profesional?
他是你2010年参加的第一届成年世界杯的教练，甚至
He was your coach in the first senior world cup that you played in 2010, even
fue entrenador tuyo en el primer mundial de mayores que jugaste en 2010 incluso
在参加奥运会时，他更多地是作为这项运动的大使。
Already in the Olympics, he was there more as an ambassador of the sport.
ya en los olímpicos, él estaba ahí más como un embajador del deporte.
他是贾尼娜的父亲，本贾的祖父。
He is Janina's father, Benja's grandfather.
Es el papá de Janina, el abuelo de Benja.
您与他的关系如何？您是如何得知他的去世的？这对您有何影响？
What was your relationship with him like and how did you find out about his death and how did it impact you?
¿Cómo fue tu relación con él y cómo te enteraste de su muerte y cómo te impactó?
嗯，他和我相处得不太好
well he doesn't get along with me very well
bueno él no con el hecho me lleva muy bien
他根本没有参与这段关系或任何事情。
He didn't get involved at all in the relationship or anything.
no se metía para nada en la relación ni nada.
维斯特吉尔说，不，要小心，百万富翁的学习会很糟糕。
And Visteguil said, no, be careful, the millionaires' studies are going to be bad.
Y eso que Visteguil decía, no, ojo, los estudios de las millonarias van a pasar mal.
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
好，好。
Good, good.
Bien, bien.
好吧，如果我在家里抽哈瓦那雪茄，我就浪费了所有的……
Well, if I smoked Habano in my house and I wasted all the...
Bien si fumaba Habano en mi casa y me he tirado todo el...
地板上全是灰。
All the ash on the floor.
Toda la ceniza en el piso.
我什么也没说。
I didn't say anything.
Yo no decía nada.
当我拥有迭戈时，他是个笑柄，他总是整天开玩笑。
When I had Diego he was a laughing stock, he was always joking all day.
cuando tenía a Diego era un cago de risa, siempre estaba todo el día bromeando.
但我一直和他相处得很好，我很少见到他
but I always got along very well with him, I didn't see him much
pero siempre me lleve muy bien con él, no lo veía mucho
我有几次见到他是在阿根廷，当时赛季即将到来，当时已经有假期了。
The few times I saw him were here in Argentina when the season was coming when there were already vacations.
Las pocas veces que lo vi fueron acá en Argentina cuando venía la temporada que ya había vacaciones.
然后他很少去欧洲，肯定去过两三次，但是……
And then he went to Europe very little, he must have gone two or three times, but...
Y después iba muy poco a Europa, habrá ido dos o tres veces, pero...
他们呆在旅馆里，很少有人回家。
They stay in the hotel, very few people came home.
Se quedan en el hotel, venía muy poca casa.
当我在一场欧冠比赛中得知他的死亡时，我想那是……
and when I found out about the death it was in a Champions League match, I think it was...
y cuando me enteré de la muerte fue en un partido de Champions, creo que fue...
我不知道，我们在乌克兰踢球，我想我们踢得很好，就在那时我才发现。
I don't know, we played in Ukraine, I think we were playing and well, that's when I found out.
No sé, jugamos en Ucrania creo que estábamos jugando nosotros y bueno ahí me enteré.
哇！
Va!
我进入网络，我做的第一件事就是“是”
I entered through the networks and the first thing I did was yes
Entré por las redes y lo primero que hice fue si
为了核实，我问本贾的母亲这是不是真的，她说是的。
To check, I asked Benja's mother if it was true and she said yes.
Para chequear le pregunté a la mamá de Benja si era verdad y me dijo sí.
我做的第一件事就是写《La avenja》。
and the first thing I did was write La avenja.
y lo primero que hice fue escribir La avenja.
我的意思是，你在哪里？
I mean, where are you?
Digo, ¿dónde estás?
在那里他告诉我，不，我到家了。
And there he told me, no, I'm home.
Y ahí me dijo, no, estoy en casa.
好吧，那就是时候
And well, that's when
Y bueno, ahí fue que
我告诉他，好吧，然后我不知道是否……当然，如果你认识他的话。
I told him, well, then I didn't know if... Of course, if you knew him.
Le dije, bueno, entonces yo no sabía si... Claro, si le sabías.
我的意思是，我要去看看……因为，嗯，Benja……
I mean, I was going to see... Because, well, Benja...
O sea, yo estaba a ver... Porque, bueno, Benja...
和他相处得很好，玩得很开心。
He got along very well with him, he had a lot of fun.
Con él se llevaba muy bien, se divertía mucho.
因为我是迭戈，但我看到他的次数更多了。
for being Diego, but I saw him more.
por ser Diego, pero yo lo veía más.
除了迭戈之外，我说我的儿子像他的祖父
besides being Diego but I say my son like his grandfather
además de ser Diego pero digo mi hijo como su abuelo
我不知道，我想知道我想和他在一起，你明白吗？
I didn't know, I wanted to know that I wanted to be with him, you see?
No sabía, quería saber que quería estar con él, ¿viste?
不，我在这里，我在电脑上，我自由了，我妈妈走了。
And no, I'm here, I'm on the computer, I was free, my mom left.
Y no, estoy acá, estoy en la compu, tenía libre, mi mamá se fue.
当然，母亲已经走了，但是……
Of course, the mother was already gone, but...
Claro, ya era que la madre se había ido, pero...
但没什么尝试
but well nothing try
pero bueno nada trate de
我们还必须热身，然后我不得不放下电话......
We also had to warm up, then I had to put the phone down and...
Nosotros encima teníamos que entrar en calor, después yo ya tenía que dejar el teléfono y...
好吧，我说好吧，来吧，给我写任何东西，否则我已经传递了联系方式
and well I said well, come on, write me anything or I had passed on a contact
y bueno dije bueno ven cualquier cosa me escribís o yo le había pasado un contacto de
马内尔·埃斯蒂亚特 (Manel Estiarte) 就是我们身边的一位。
Manel Estiarte, who is the one who is with us.
Manel Estiarte, que es el que está con nosotros.
写点什么给他然后...
write anything to him and then...
cualquier cosa escribíle a él y después...
但这是非常
but it was very
pero sí fue muy
我的意思是，我好像不相信。
I mean, it's like I didn't believe it.
O sea, es como que no lo creía.
他们路过并说，这是一个谎言。
They were passing and saying, it's a lie.
iban pasando y decían, es mentira.
但好吧，事实是……
But well, the truth was...
Pero bueno, la verdad que fue...
对每个人来说都感到震惊，显然对刚到达现场的我来说也是如此
a shock for everyone and obviously for me who were just arriving at the field
un shock para todos y obviamente para mí que justamente estábamos llegando a la cancha
我不记得那是什么游戏了，但是降低...
I don't remember what game it was, but lowering the...
No me acuerdo qué partido era, pero bajando el...
下车前5分钟，我就知道了。
5 minutes before getting off the bus, that's when I found out.
5 minutos antes de bajar del micro ahí me entero
事实是，在那一刻晚些时候
and nothing good the truth is that later at that moment
y nada bueno la verdad que después en ese momento
我帮了班杰妈妈很多忙
I helped Benja's mother a lot,
le ayudé mucho a la mamá de Benja,
因为好所以方便
convenient because good
convenja porque bueno
尝试到达那里，尝试帮助他到达......
try to get there, try to help him come...
tratar de allá, tratar de ayudarle que venga este...
和家人一起去，变得更平静等等，但好吧，什么也没有。
to go with my family, to be calmer, etc., but well, nothing.
para ir con mi familia, para que esté más tranquilo, etcétera, pero bueno, nada.
有时你不能从那里做很多事情，但是嘿，我尽力做到最好。
Sometimes you can't do much from there, but hey, I tried to do my best.
A veces de allá mucho no se puede hacer, pero bueno, lo intenté hacer lo mejor.
最重要的是本贾……
and above all Benja who...
y sobre todo Benja que...
他过得很糟糕。
that he was having a pretty bad time.
que él estaba pasando bastante mal.
我明白了他为什么...
I realized why he...
Yo me daba cuenta porque él...
在我看来，他也不喜欢表露自己的情绪。
It also seemed to me that he doesn't like to show his emotions.
también pareció a mí que no le gusta mostrar sus emociones.
敏感，但我意识到了这一点，直到片刻之后......
sensitivity, but I realized it and until a moment later...
sensibilidad, pero me daba cuenta y hasta que un momento después...
然后我想四五天过去了。
Then I think four or five days passed.
Después creo que pasaron cuatro o cinco días.
关于迭戈，在说话的那一刻，他开始哭了，你看，后来。
that about Diego and there, in a moment of speaking, he started to cry, you saw, later.
que lo de Diego y ahí, en un momento de hablando, se puso a llorar, viste, después.
但是，这非常困难。
But well, it was very hard.
Pero bueno, fue muy duro.
在你的职业生涯中你必须做出很多决定。
You had to make many decisions in your career.
Tuviste que tomar muchas decisiones en tu carrera.
你是从独立开始的。
You started in Independent.
Arrancaste en Independiente.
童年当然对你有影响并塑造了你的个性
with a childhood that of course had its conditioning for you and forged your personality
con una infancia que por supuesto tuvo sus condicionamientos para vos y forjó tu personalidad
然后，当谈到选择第一个欧洲目的地马德里竞技时，比赛就会告诉自己，曼城......
then when it comes to choosing the first European destination, Atlético de Madrid, then the race tells itself, Manchester City...
después a la hora de elegir el primer destino europeo, Atlético de Madrid, después la carrera se cuenta sola, Manchester City...
在国家队中，你认为你最大的体育赌注是什么？
In the middle of the national team, what do you think was your biggest sports bet?
en el medio de la selección, ¿cuál crees que fue tu mayor apuesta deportiva?
你在这里所说的选择在我看来，我不知道我是否把我的未来置于危险之中，但是
A choice that you said here seems to me that I don't know if I put my future at stake but
una elección que vos dijiste acá me parece que no sé si pongo en juego mi futuro pero
但是，是的，回顾过去，了解你的职业生涯非常重要，塞尔吉奥。
but yes, looking back it ends up being very important to understand what your career was like, Sergio.
pero sí, mirando para atrás termina siendo muy importante para entender cómo fue tu carrera, Sergio.
我的比赛跑得很快。
My race was very fast.
Fue muy rápido mi carrera.
但我认为最重要的赌注
but I think the most important bet
pero creo que la apuesta más importante
我所采取的就是去城市。
What I took was to go to City.
que tomé fue en irme al City.
是的，因为...
Yes, because...
Sí, porque...
我在马德里竞技队，那里仍然非常好，我感觉很舒服。
I was at Atlético de Madrid, which was still very good, I was very comfortable.
Yo estaba en Atlético de Madrid, que aún así estaba muy bien, estaba muy cómodo.
他们对我很好，我没有遇到任何问题。
They treated me very well, I had no problems at all.
Me trataban muy bien, no tenía problemas para nada.
但我觉得我必须寻找别的东西。
but I felt like I had to look for something else.
pero sentía que tenía que buscar otra cosa.
进步
to progress
para para progresar
我自己，在那一刻，当我停止演奏时，我想......
Myself, I thought at that moment, when I stopped playing...
Yo mismo, yo pensaba en ese momento, cuando deje de jugar...
我多么希望我的孩子和人们能够认出我。
how I wanted my children and people to recognize me.
cómo quería que me reconozcan mis hijos y la gente.
我是为了赢得冠军。
I was to win titles.
Yo era ganar títulos.
赢得冠军并让俱乐部表现出色，所以我想到的第一件事是
win titles and for the club to do well, so the first thing I thought was
ganar títulos y que al club le vaya bien, entonces lo primero que pensé era
在体育运动中。
in the athletic.
en el atlético.
皇马和巴萨均获胜。
Real Madrid and Barça all won.
Real Madrid y Barça ganaban todos.
我的意思是，还有...
I mean, and...
O sea, y...
我有机会，一年前我收到了切尔西竞技队的报价。
I had the opportunity, I had received an offer a year ago from Atlético de Chelsea.
Yo tuve la oportunidad, me había llegado una oferta hacía un año antes del Atlético del Chelsea.
一年半前，俱乐部拒绝了，我也很平静
a year and a half before and the club said no, I was calm too
un año y medio antes y el club dijo que no, yo también estaba tranquilo
我的想法是不搬家，因为我看到俱乐部也在努力。
The idea was not to move because I saw that the club was also making an effort.
La idea no era moverme porque veía que también el club estaba haciendo un esfuerzo.
参加冠军联赛并且...
to be in the Champions League and...
para estar en Champions y...
赢得欧冠冠军，但至少获得欧冠资格并达到……
to win the Champions League, but at least to qualify for the Champions League and get to where...
para ganar la Champions, pero por lo menos para clasificarte en Champions y llegar hasta donde...
让我们到那里吧。
Let's get there.
Lleguemos.
后来，一年半过去了，我的脑子就这样想了，那就是，
And later, when that year and a half passed, that's where my head went, that is,
Y ya después cuando pasó ese año y medio ahí fue mi cabeza, es decir,
我23岁了，我说我必须...
I turned 23 and I said I have to...
Yo cumplía 23 y dije tengo que...
寻找另一种赢得冠军的选择。
to look for another alternative to win titles.
que buscar otra alternativa de ganar títulos.
而那个时候几乎所有的事情都已经和年轻人解决了。
And at that time almost everything was settled with the youth.
Y en ese momento estaba casi casi todo arreglado con la juventud.
突然，城市出现了。
and suddenly City appears.
y de repente aparece el City.
我喜欢这个地方的原因是我首先想参加英超联赛
What I liked about the place is that first I wanted to play in the Premier
que lo que me gustó del sitio es que primero yo quería jugar en la Premier
我一直很喜欢它，每个人都知道我喜欢它
I always liked it and well, everyone knows that I liked it
siempre me gustó y bueno, todo el mundo sabe que a mí me gustaba
利物浦，但不是因为我是利物浦球迷，而是因为欧文踢球，我喜欢利物浦，迈克尔·欧文
Liverpool, but not because I'm a Liverpool fan, but I like Liverpool because Owen plays, Michael Owen
Liverpool, pero no porque soy hincha de Liverpool, pero me gusta Liverpool porque juega Owen, Michael Owen
只是有一天我看见他了……你说的是吗？
It's just that one day I saw him and... Did you say it?
Es que un día lo vi y... ¿Lo dijiste?
不，他很清楚。
No, well he knew.
No, pues él sabía.
他知道我已经说过了，他拥抱了我，我们都笑了。
He knew I had said it and he hugged me all over and we were laughing.
Sabía que yo lo había dicho y me abrazó todo y nos quedamos de risa.
我告诉他，你进球时我不高兴。
I told him, I'm not happy when you scored the goal.
Le dije, no estoy contento cuando hiciste el gol.
这是我在 98 年世界杯上对阵他时打进的一球。
There was the goal I scored against him in the World Cup, '98.
Estaba el gol que le hice en el Mundial, el 98.
我记得是因为我当时还小……他打进了那个伟大的进球。
I remember because I was little there and... The great goal he scored.
Yo me acuerdo porque era chiquito ahí y... Al golazo que hizo.
但从那时起我就已经……我想那届世界杯上他进球了，就像……
But from there I already... I think that there was that World Cup when he scored a goal, like...
Pero ya de ahí yo ya... Creo que ahí ese Mundial cuando él hace gol, como que...
我看到了他打球的地方，就在那时……因为
I saw where he played and that's when... because
vi de él dónde jugaba y ahí fue que... porque
我的意思是他还小，书变红了，我独立了。
I meant that he was little, the book turned red, I was independent.
Yo me refería a que él era chiquitito, el libro voltó rojo, yo estaba independiente.
我开始喜欢他，我更认同他的打球方式，他个子小，速度快，就是这样。
I started to like him and I identified more with how he played, that he was small, fast, like that.
Me empezó a gustar él y me identificaba más como él jugaba, que era chiquitito, rapidito, así.
然后什么都没有
and well nothing then when
y bueno nada entonces cuando
当曼城到来时，我正在这里参加 2011 年美洲杯，
When City arrives, I was here in the 2011 Copa América,
Cuando llega el City, que yo estaba acá en la Copa América del 2011,
在阿根廷
in Argentina
en Argentina
我告诉我的代表，如果我能解决这个问题就更好了。
I told my representative that if I can fix it much better.
Le dije a mi repre que si lo puedo arreglar mucho mejor.
因为我更喜欢去那里，除了特维斯之外，还有萨巴莱塔
because I prefer to go there and apart from that there was Tevez, there was Zabaleta
porque prefiero ir ahí y aparte estaba Tevez, estaba Zabaleta
还有……还有那个……
and... and that...
y... y que...
不，这么说吧，这取决于曼奇尼是否希望我走。
No, there, let's say, it depends if Mancini wants me to go.
No, ahí, digamos, depende si Mancini quiere que vaya.
最好不要，不，曼奇尼希望他来，就是这样，就是这样。
Better not, no, Mancini wants him to come, that's it, that's it.
Mejor no, no, Mancini quiere que venga, listo, ya da.
然后他就去了，我们修好了一切，然后我就离开了。
and there he went and we fixed everything and I left.
y ahí fue y arreglamos todo y me fui.
但就在你离开之前，那里的地方在2011年才赢得了F杯。
but the place there had only won the F-Cup in 2011 just before you go.
pero el sitio ahí había ganado solo la F-Cup en 2011 justo antes de que vos vayas.
是的，2000 年...是的，2010 年，我想，对吧？
Yes, 2000... Yes, 2010, I think, right?
Sí, 2000... Sí, 2010, creo, ¿no?
这是一个会一点一点进步的俱乐部
It was a club that was going to progress little by little
Era un club que iba a progresar de a poco
他们赢得了一切，而且……
They won everything and...
ganaban todo y...
好吧，没什么，我和他一起去的……当……
And well, nothing, I went with him... when...
Y bueno, nada, fui con el... cuando...
我看到了欧冠联赛的球队，他们告诉我......
I saw the team that is in the Champions League and they told me...
Vi el equipo que está en Champions y me dijeron...
我和俱乐部的人交谈，有很多人说西班牙语。
That I talk to the people at the club, that there are many people who speak Spanish.
que yo hable con la gente del club, que hay mucha gente que habla español.
当然，他们是俱乐部的负责人，他告诉我，这是我到达时他们的想法。
who run the club and told me, of course, that was their idea when I arrived.
que manejan el club y me decían, claro, esa era su idea cuando yo llegué.
三四年才能获奖。
three or four years to win the prize.
a tres o cuatro años ganar la premia.
所以赢得英超冠军是疯狂的。
So winning a Premier was crazy.
Entonces ganar una Premier era una locura.
我们赢了第一年。
and we won the first year.
y ganamos el primer año.
他开始带来更多的援军，一点点成长。
He began to bring more reinforcement and grew little by little.
Empezó a traer más refuerzo y fue creciendo a poco.
我们赢得了英超联赛，然后第二年我们赢得了杯赛。
and we won the Premier, then the following year we won the Cup.
y fuimos ganando la Premier, después el siguiente año ganamos la Copa.
第二年之后，我们再次赢得了英超冠军。
The next year later we won the Premier again, then again.
el siguiente año después volvimos a ganar la Premier, después otra vez.
杯赛、超级杯等等英超联赛，然后……
the Cup, the Super Cup and so the Premier and then came...
la Copa, la Supercopa y así la Premier y después vino...
佩皮诺·佩莱里尼，总理，然后是总理，总理，总理......
Peppino Pellerini, the Premier, then Premier, Premier, Premier...
Peppino Pellerini, la Premier, después Premier, Premier, Premier...
事实上，这是一个可能会出错的赌注。
and the truth is that it was a bet that could have gone wrong.
y la verdad que fue una apuesta que me podía haber salido mal.
但我感觉……那个……
But I felt that... that...
Pero yo sentía que... que...
我想象赢得一两个奖项，对我来说是......
I imagined that winning a prize or two, for me it was...
Yo me imaginaba que ganando por ahí una premia o dos, ya para mí era...
这是历史性的，对吧？
It was historic, right?
Era histórico, ¿no?
但是，嘿，我最终赢得了很多冠军。
But hey, I ended up winning quite a few titles.
Pero bueno, terminé ganando bastantes títulos.
这很好，这就是为什么我说我非常非常高兴，但这是一个很大的赌注。
That's good, that's why I say I'm very very happy but it was a very big bet.
que bueno por eso digo estoy muy muy contento pero fue una apuesta muy
非常困难，因为年轻人也落后了，而且......
very difficult because the youth was also behind and it was...
muy difícil porque también estaba la juventud atrás y era...
也没什么
nothing, too
nada, también
一个想法，你知道尤文每年也为冠军而战吗？
One thought, do you know that Juve also fights for titles every year?
Uno pensaba, ¿sabes que la Juve también pelea todos los años títulos?
这是一个相当糟糕的赌注，但这让我感觉好多了，因为
It was a pretty shitty bet, but it made me feel better because
Era una apuesta bastante jodida, pero me tiró más porque
因为那是英超，我觉得在英超踢球
because it was the Premier and I felt that playing in the Premier
porque era la Premier y sentía que jugando en la Premier
这将给我另一个层次的跳跃
It was going to give me another level jump
me iba a dar un salto más a mí de nivel que
其他联赛没有。
that other leagues don't have it.
que por ahí otras ligas no lo tiene.
除了许多人看重的内容之外，流媒体对你来说也是一种治疗。
Streaming is a kind of therapy for you too, in addition to content that many people there value.
Streaming es una especie de terapia para vos también, además de un contenido que mucha gente de ahí valora.
对我来说是的，因为更重要的是，有时你会...
For me yes, because what's more, sometimes you do...
Para mí sí, porque es más, a veces haces...
我做的时间很少，但是大约两个小时，两个半小时。
I do very few hours, but I do about two hours, two and a half hours.
yo hago muy pocas horas, pero hago por ahí dos horas, dos horas y media.
我最终还是累了回到家。
and I end up home as tired.
y termino yo a casa como cansado.
现在，现在，你看到在这次演讲之后，你不想睡觉，你看到，小睡一下。
Now, now, you saw that after this talk, you don't want to sleep, you saw, a nap.
Ahora, ahora, viste que después de esta charla, no querés dormir, viste, una siesta.
我有时会发现，如果我不在家里呆两个小时，我就死定了。
It happens to me that sometimes, if I don't stay home for two hours, I'm dead.
Me pasa que a veces, si no me sigo en casa dos horas, estoy muerto.
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
嗯，我...很多人都说，真的吗？
Well, I... and a lot of people say, really?
Bueno, yo... y mucha gente dice, ¿en serio?
是的，因为...
Yes, because...
Sí, porque...
你谈论一周内没有谈论的一切。
You talk about everything you didn't talk about in a week.
charlás todo lo que no charlaste por ahí en una semana.
我的意思是，你正在与人交谈。
I mean, you're talking to people.
O sea, estás pa pa pa hablando con la gente.
是的，我认为这是一种
And yes, I think it is a kind
Y sí, yo creo que es una especie
的治疗有帮助，因为
of therapy that helps because
de terapia que ayuda porque
有时候，当你什么都没有的时候，就像发生在我身上，我心情不好或者......
Sometimes when you're, nothing, like, it happened to me, I was in a bad mood or...
A veces cuando estás, nada, puesta de, yo me pasó, estaba en mal humor o...
我一无所有，我打开了直播，它彻底改变了我。
I had nothing, I turned on the stream and it totally changed me.
No tenía nada, prendí el stream y me cambiaba totalmente.
我的意思是，难以置信。
I mean, incredible.
O sea, increíble.
他一边直播，一边闲聊，一边开玩笑。
He streamed, fooled around for a while, joked.
Hacía stream, boludeaba un rato, bromeaba.
我女朋友有时告诉我，你看起来像个混蛋。
And my girlfriend sometimes told me, you were looking like an ass.
Y mi novia a veces me decía, tú estuviste con cara de culo.
你整天都在直播，笑得前仰后合。
All day long and you stream and you're laughing your ass off.
Todo el día y haces stream y te estás cagando de risa.
我告诉他...
And I tell him...
Y yo le digo...
我不知道我发生了什么事，但是嘿，我知道什么，明白吗？
I don't know what happened to me, but hey, what do I know, see?
No sé qué me pasó, pero bueno, qué sé yo, ¿viste?
这就像...
It's like...
Es como...
但他告诉我这没什么，但并不是我们昨天在这里，我和我的曼波在一起。
But he told me well as a little bit of nothing, but not that we are yesterday, I was with a mambo of mine.
Pero me lo decía bien como un poco de nada, pero no de que nosotros estamos ayer, yo estaba con un mambo mío.
因为我是从这个网站开始的。
because I started on the site.
porque yo arranqué en el sitio.
有时他会来，我不知道，因为他对训练很生气，因为他很累等等。
Sometimes he came, I don't know, because he was angry at training, because he was tired and such.
A veces venía, no sé, enojado el entreno, que estaba cansado y tal.
我看到了那里的显示器和电脑，我说：“男孩，我要去玩了。”
And I saw the monitor and the computer there and I said, "Boy, I'm going to play."
y veía ahí el monitor y la computadora y dije, chata, me voy a jugar.
或者我玩电子游戏，它分散了我的注意力，但当然，这是......
or I played video games and it distracted me, but of course, it was...
o jugaba los videojuegos y me distraía, pero claro, era...
对我来说，做直播就像......
For me doing the stream was like...
Para mí hacer el stream era como...
人们感到宽慰
a relief in feeling that people
un alivio en sentirme que la gente
在那里互动，人们问你事情。
interact there, people ask you things.
interactuar ahí, que la gente te va preguntando cosas.
对我来说，这不是 100% 的治疗，但它会让你放松一点……
And for me it is, it is not 100% therapy, but it takes you out a little...
Y yo para mí sí es, no es terapia 100%, pero te va sacando un poco...
那天的坏心情。
of that bad mood that came from the day.
de ese mal humor que por ahí venía del día.
难道相反的情况没有发生在你身上吗？也许在直播时你心情不好？
And doesn't the opposite happen to you that perhaps while streaming you get in a bad mood?
¿Y no te pasa al revés que quizás dentro del stream te pones de mal humor?
不，我玩的时候心情不好。
No, I get in a bad mood when I play.
No, me pongo de mal humor cuando juego.
如果他输了
if he lost
Si perdés.
如果我玩小游戏，是的。
If I'm playing the little games, yes.
Si estoy jugando los jueguitos, sí.
所以我离开了一些比赛，现在我只是偶尔聊天，看一些视频，但是……不，不是现在，但是……输掉比赛会让你心情不好。
That's why I left some games, now I only sometimes chat and watch some videos, but... No, not now, but... Losing in games made you bad mood.
Por eso dejé algunos juegos, ahora solo a veces charlo y veo algunos videos, pero... No, ahora no, pero... Te ponía mal humor perder en los juegos.
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
例如，我离开了国际足联。
I left FIFA, for example.
Dejé el FIFA, por ejemplo.
我玩过《FIFA》，然后就停了，因为我弄坏了很多球。
I played FIFA and I stopped because I broke a lot of yotis.
Yo jugaba al FIFA y dejé porque rompí mucho yostis.
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
有一天，我在曼彻斯特把一只约斯蒂扔出窗外，它就留在那里。
One day I threw a yosti out of the window in Manchester and it stayed there.
Un día tiré un yosti afuera por la ventana en Manchester y quedó ahí.
他在这个角色上呆了大约10天。
He spent about 10 days in the role.
Quedó como 10 días en el rol.
你打开窗户并向他开枪。
You had the window open and you shot at him.
Tenías la ventana abierta y le tiraste.
哦不，我打开了它，我打开了窗户，然后我把它扔了出去。
Oh no, I opened it, I opened the window and I threw it out.
Ah no, abrí, abrí la ventana y lo tiré.
但与之无关，那我想，这和yosti有什么关系呢？
But nothing to do with it, then I think, what does the yosti have to do with it?
Pero nada que ver, después pienso, ¿qué tiene que ver el yostio?
除了那个yotio...
Apart from that yotio...
Aparte ese yostio...
打网球弄坏了80个球拍，我不应该笑。
and broke 80 rackets playing tennis, I shouldn't laugh.
y rompió 80 raquetas jugando al tenis, no debería reír.
但我发誓人们会明白这是在电子游戏中，但是......
But I swear that people are going to understand that it's in video games, but...
Pero te juro que la gente lo va a entender que está en los videojuegos, pero...
国际足联就是垃圾，你知道吗？
FIFA is crap, you know?
El FIFA es una porquería, ¿sabes?
我的意思是，它很可爱，但很糟糕，它会让你很反感。
I mean, it's very cute, but it's crap, it turns you off badly.
O sea, es muy lindo, pero es una porquería, te calienta mal.
但除此之外...
But apart from that...
Pero aparte porque...
你一个人玩，当然，一切都取决于你。
You play alone and of course, everything depends on you.
Vos jugás solo y claro, todo depende de vos.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
比如说网球、高尔夫，你明白吗？
Let's say tennis, golf, you see?
Vamos a decir el tenis, el golf, ¿viste?
能不能玩得好就看你了。
It's up to you to play well.
Depende de vos que juegues bien.
当然可以，但是你在网上与其他人对战，而且你也打得很好。
Sure, but you are playing against someone else online and you also play well.
Claro, pero vos estás jugando contra otro online y también juegas bien.
对手也上场。
The rival also plays.
El rival también juega.
好吧，当然，他打了你，你想，但是这个死人打了我，你看到了，打的是我的头。
And well, of course, and he beats you and you think, but this dead man beat me, you saw, in the head.
Y bueno, claro, y te gana y vos pensás, pero este muerto me ganó, viste, en la cabeza.
你有多糟糕？
How bad are you?
¿Qué malo que sos?
但他打败了我。
But he beat me.
Pero me ganó.
我认为这最能让你兴奋。
And I think that turns you on the most.
Y eso creo que más te calienta.
比如说还有其他的游戏...
For example, there are other games...
Por ejemplo, hay otros juegos...
他们是一个团队，而且已经是一个团队了......
that they are a team and well, already a team...
que son en equipo y bueno, ya en equipo...
你可以说，如果另一个更糟糕，你明白吗？
You can say, if the other one was worse, do you understand?
Puedes decir, si el otro era más malo, ¿entendés?
这是别人的错，他没有帮助我。
It's the other person's fault, who didn't help me.
Es culpa del otro, que no me ayudó.
在这种情况下，只有胡安一人，不责怪他就不能责怪任何人。
In this case with Juan alone, by not blaming him he cannot blame anyone.
En este caso con Juan solo, al no le echarle no puede echar la culpa a nadie.
但是的，我离开了，除了我什么都没有
but yes I left and nothing but me
pero sí dejé y nada pero me
现在我很开心，我嘲笑别人。
Now I have a lot of fun, I laugh at people.
Ahora me divierto bastante, me cago de risa con la gente.
但是，嘿，我们已经与那里的人进行了沟通。
But hey, we already have communication with the people there.
Pero bueno, ya tenemos ahí una comunicación con la gente.
每次我打开它，他们就会立即开始扔水果。
Every time I turn it on they immediately start throwing fruit.
que cada vez que prendo ya enseguida empiezan a tirar fruta.
你进入了老大哥的政治圈，你总是喜欢它
you got into big brother, politics, you always like it
metiste gran hermano, política, siempre te gusta
我想，但是为什么呢？
I think, but why?
Opino, pero ¿por qué?
如果有一千个白痴对任何事情有自己的看法而没有人告诉他们任何事情，那么有自己的看法就是错误的。
It's wrong to have an opinion, if there are a thousand idiots who have an opinion on anything and no one tells them anything.
que está mal opinar, si hay mil boludos que opinan cualquier cosa y nadie le dice nada.
是的，确实如此，有人有任何想法，而我......
Yes, it's true, there is someone who thinks like anything and I...
Sí, es verdad, hay uno que opina como cualquier cosa y yo...
我认为，就我所见而言。
I think, let's say, from what I see.
Yo opino, digamos, de lo que veo.
显然现在，前几天，我发表了我对老大哥的看法，但因为……
Obviously now, the other day, I gave my opinion about Big Brother, but because...
Obviamente ahora, el otro día, opiné de Gran Hermano, pero porque...
是因为……我陷入了混乱，比如说，而不是问……
It was because... I got into a mess, let's say, instead of asking...
Fue por... me metí, digamos, al pedo en vez de preguntarle a...
就我的朋友来说吧。
To my friend, let's say.
A mi amigo, digamos.
因为当然，我最好的朋友是他的兄弟，但我从小就认识他，而且我和他的兄弟相处得很好。
Because of course, my best friend is his brother, but I knew him as a child, but I get along very well with his brother.
Porque claro, mi mejor amigo es el hermano, pero yo lo conozco de chico, pero yo me llevo muy bien con su hermano.
他是我最好的朋友，我们和他分享很多事情、旅行，但是……
He is my best friend and with him we share a lot of things, trips, but...
que es mi mejor amigo y con él compartimos un montón de cosas, viajes, pero...
我想象着他会是什么样子，但我没有问他我是否可以说这句话，而是把它发给了他。
I imagined how he would be, but instead of asking him if I can say this, I sent it to him.
Yo me imaginé cómo estaría él, pero en vez de preguntarle si puedo decir esto, me la mandé.
好吧，然后他告诉我不，因为
and well and then he told me no because
y bueno y después él me dijo no porque
操，你为什么这么说，但是……这让你大吃一惊吗？
Fuck it, why did you say that, but well... Did it blow your mind?
Al pedo, porque dijiste eso, pero bueno... ¿Te acabó al pedo?
不，但他告诉我说不...
No, but he told me like no...
No, pero me dijo como que no...
那是我应该问他的地方。
That's where I should have asked him.
que por ahí le tenía que haber preguntado.
我告诉他，是的，事实是他把它寄给了我。
And I told him, yes, the truth was that he sent it to me.
Y le dije, sí, la verdad me la mandé.
我说，对不起，布莱恩。
I say, sorry, Brian.
Le digo, perdón, Brian.
我告诉他，好吧，现在...
I tell him, well, now...
Le digo, bueno, ahora...
现在我必须直播，我道歉。
Now I have to stream and I apologize.
Ahora tengo que hacer stream y le pido disculpas.
然后，做你想做的事，这是你的问题，你的决定，但是......
Afterwards, do what you want, it's your problem, your decision, but...
Después, haz lo que vos quieras, ya es un problema tuyo, decisión tuya, pero...
但没什么，那就是我进入的地方，我不必进入的地方。
But nothing, that's where I got into where I didn't have to get in.
Pero nada, ahí me pasó por meterme en donde no tenía que meterme.
但如果是其他人，例如，我会说，我说什么了？
But if it was someone else, for example, I will have said, what did I say?
Pero si era otro, por ejemplo, voy a haber dicho, ¿qué he dicho?
在艾伦之外还是在……之外我不知道……
outside of Alan or outside of... I don't know...
afuera de Alan o afuera de... no sé...
因为我不知道还有谁在那里。
because I don't know who else was there.
porque no sé quién más estaba ahí.
好吧，我没看到，但我发现是因为我的朋友......
Well, I don't see it, but I find out because my friends...
Pues yo no veo, pero me entero porque mis amigos...
我们聊过，好吧，事情正在发生，我，嘿，你看到了这个......
We talked and well, things were happening and I, hey, you saw this and...
Hablamos y bueno, iban pasando cosas y yo, che, viste esto y...
好吧，没什么，在我看来就像是在说
and well nothing, it seemed to me like saying that
y bueno nada, me pareció como que decir eso
就像一个朋友，我想象这对他不好，但是，我不知道他会怎么样。
It was like a friend, I imagined that it was bad for him, but well, I don't know how he would be.
Era como amigo, me imaginé que a él le estaba mal, pero bueno, no sé cómo estaría él.
我应该问他，嘿，怎么了？
I should have asked him, hey, what's up?
Yo tenía que haberle preguntado, che, ¿qué onda?
你好吗？
How are you doing?
¿Cómo está?
我发给我了。
I sent it to me.
Yo me la mandé.
就像我说政治时一样。
Like also when I say politics.
Como también cuando digo política.
但你一直感兴趣吗？
But were you always interested?
Pero siempre te interesó?
对我来说不不不不不我也不感兴趣
no to me no no no no no I'm not interested either
no a mí no no no no no no me interesa tampoco
令我困扰的事情是......
What bothers me out there are things that...
Lo que me molesta por ahí son cosas que...
这么说吧，那不适合我。
that don't fit me, let's say.
que no me cuadran, digamos.
例如，我总是强调……的问题。
For example, I always highlight the issue of...
que por ejemplo que siempre remarco por el tema de...
财富税
of wealth tax
del impuesto al patrimonio
我认为不仅是阿根廷，在我看来还有很多国家......
I think that not only Argentina, there are in many countries that it seems to me...
Yo creo que no solo Argentina, hay en muchos países que me parece...
很多人可能会说，是的，好吧，但这是为了帮助......
many may say, yes, well, but it is to help what...
muchos pueden decir, sí, bueno, pero es para ayudar a lo que...
如果你告诉我这是为了某些事情，你说这有帮助，很好，但对国家没有帮助。
If you tell me that it is for something, that you say that it helps, fine, but not the country.
Si vos me decís que es para algo, que vos decís que ayuda, bien, pero el país no.
或者说，那些收取此费用的国家并没有达到应有的水平。
or the countries that charge that, are not, let's say, as they should be.
o los países que cobran eso, no están digamos como tienen que estar.
让我烦恼的是你赚到的就是你得到的
and what bothers me is that what you earned is what you
y yo lo que me molesta es que vos lo que vos ganaste
你已经交税了，为什么还要继续拿出来呢？
You already paid tax, so why do you have to keep taking it out?
Ya pagaste impuesto, entonces ¿por qué te tienes que seguir sacando?
如果你没有工作，他们就会不断地夺走你的工作。
If you don't have a job, they keep taking it from you.
vos si no tenés laburo, te lo siguen sacando.
在我看来...
That seems to me...
Eso me parece que...
对我来说，这似乎是错误的，在许多国家他们都有这种做法，但这是错误的。
To me it seems wrong and in many countries they have it and it is wrong.
para mí me parece está mal y en muchos países lo tienen y está mal.
例如，美国就没有。
The United States does not have it, for example.
Estados Unidos no lo tiene, por ejemplo.
利润要交很多税吗？
Does the profit charge a lot of tax?
¿Cobra mucho impuesto la ganancia?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
好吧，赚更多，因为如果你有工作，那是因为你做得很好。
Well, earn more because if you have a job it's because you're doing well.
Bueno, cobra más la ganancia porque si vos tenés laburo es porque te está yendo bien.
我认为通过税收，我会告诉你，这是为了改善国家等等。
And with that tax I think so, I would tell you, well, it is to improve the country, etc.
Y con ese impuesto yo creo que sí, te diría, bueno, es para que mejore el país, etcétera.
如果你看到一些不起作用的东西，那么你会很烦恼，因为我住在别墅里。
If you see things that don't work, then it bothers you because I lived in the villa.
Si ves cosas que no funcionan, entonces te molesta porque yo viví en la villa.
村里没有人帮助我们。
and no one helps us in the village.
y a nosotros en la villa nadie te ayuda.
他们利用我们。
They use us.
Nos usan.
你在书中谈到了很多。
You talk about it a lot in the book.
En el libro lo contás mucho.
发生的事情是人们认为...
What happens is that people think...
Lo que pasa es que la gente piensa...
有很多人在发表意见时并未进过村子。
There are many people who, when they give their opinion, have not been in a village.
Hay mucha gente que cuando opina no estuvo en una villa.
并且在一个非常主要的别墅里......
and be in a very main villa...
y estar en una villa bien principal...
在一个村庄里，我们，例如，当我在那儿时，我的家人......
Being in a village, we, for example, when I was there, my family...
Estar en una villa, nosotros, por ejemplo, cuando yo estaba ahí, mi familia...
我们很好，我们很高兴。
We were fine, we were happy.
Estábamos bien, estábamos contentos.
镇里有我们的超市、肉店和蔬菜水果店。
Inside the town we had our supermarket, our butcher shop, the greengrocer.
Adentro de la villa teníamos nuestro supermercado, nuestra carnicería, la verdulería.
一切都是别墅的价格。
that everything was a villa price.
que todo era un precio de villa.
显然，如果从达维尔去巴勒莫，花费要贵七倍。
Obviously, if you go from Daville and go to Palermo, it costs seven times more.
Obviamente, si vas de Daville y vas a Palermo, vale siete veces más.
你活着，就是说，你在那里活得很好，很平静，因为
You live, that is, you are there living well, calm, because
Vos vivís, o sea, estás ahí viviendo bien, tranquilo, porque
当你被包围时，这就是你的方式。
It is your way where you are surrounded.
es tu manera donde vos estás rodeado.
但没有人考虑我们是如何在那里的。
But no one thinks about how we are there.
Pero nadie piensa cómo estamos nosotros ahí.
到来的人警告现实他是幸运的
he who comes warns the reality that he is lucky
el que viene avisa la realidad que tiene suerte
或者成为一名足球运动员或者有一个你认识的人
or be a footballer or have someone you know who
o ser futbolista o tener un conocido que
帮助你在这样的地方工作，但你仍然无法工作，因为......
to give you a hand to work in such a place, but you still can't work because...
que te dé una mano para que labures en tal lugar, pero aún así no puedes laburar porque...
因为在公司里，如果他们告诉你住在哪里，而你说如果你住在城里，他们不会接受，所以你必须......
because in the company if they tell you where you live and you say if you live in the town, they don't take it, so you have to...
porque en la empresa si te dicen dónde vivís y decís si vivís en la villa no te lo toman, entonces tenés que...
给他一个你不住在城里的朋友的地址。
Give him an address of a friend of yours who does not live in the town.
pasarle una dirección de un amigo tuyo que no vive en la villa.
这是一个不是从现在开始的完整话题。
It is a whole topic that is not from now.
Es todo un tema que no es de ahora.
从五六岁开始，一直活到14岁，一直都是这样。
since I was five or six years old, I lived until I was 14 years old and it's always the same.
desde que tenía cinco o seis años, que vivía hasta los 14 años y siempre es igual.
我和我在社区里也有联系的人谈过，情况仍然如此。
And I have spoken with people that I also have contact in the neighborhoods and it remains the same.
Y yo he hablado con gente que también tengo contacto en los barrios y sigue igual.
所以，如果我们要这么说的话……
So, if we are going to say that well...
Entonces, si vamos a decir que bueno...
他们给你一些可以帮助的东西，我会帮你买，但是...
They get you something to help, I'll buy it for you, but...
te sacan algo para ayudar, te la compro, pero...
我看事情不是那样的。
I see that the thing is not like that.
Veo que la cosa no es así.
它会让你对很多事情感到愤怒。
It makes you angry about many things.
te da bronca por muchas cosas.
我不感兴趣，比如说，我在想一些
and I'm not interested, let's say, I think about something that
y no me interesa digamos, yo opino de algo que
我赢了，我说，你为什么要从我这里夺走它？
I won and I say, why do you want to take it from me?
Yo gané y digo, ¿por qué me lo querés sacar?
我的意思是，因为我在国外赚了很多钱，所以我必须来到这里，我必须把所有这些钱给你，因为......
I mean, because I earned a lot of money abroad, I have to come here and I have to give all this money to you because...
O sea, porque gané un montón de guita afuera tengo que venir acá y toda esta guita te la tengo que dar a vos porque...
或者如果你愿意的话，如果你告诉我，好吧，这就是我去的原因，我去社区......
or if you feel like it, if you tell me, well, that's why I go, I go to the neighborhoods and...
o se te antoja, si vos me decís, bueno, para eso voy yo, voy yo a los barrios y...
我正在帮忙。
and I'm helping.
y voy ayudando.
我帮助过很多基金会。
I have helped a lot of foundations.
He ayudado a un montón de fundaciones.
我什至不需要说，因为我不喜欢说我做了什么。
I don't even need to say it because I don't like to say what I do.
que no me hace falta ni decirlo porque no me gusta decir qué hago.
我这样做是因为我感觉到了，而且我不必告诉谁我在帮助谁。
I do it because I feel it and I don't have to tell who I'm helping.
Lo hago porque lo siento y no tengo por qué decirle a quién ayudo.
但也别让他们把我当傻子。
But don't let them take me for a fool either.
pero tampoco que me tomen de boludo.
让我们结束吧，在结束之前我想问你两件事。
Let's finish, I want to ask you two things before closing.
Vamos terminando, quiero preguntarte dos cosas antes de cerrar.
世界杯之间
between the World Cup
entre el Mundial
2014 年和 2021 年美洲杯是 2018 年俄罗斯世界杯。
2014 and the Copa América 2021 was Russia 2018.
2014 y la Copa América 2021 estuvo Rusia 2018.
在对阵冰岛和法国的比赛中，他分别打进了球队的第一个也是最后一个进球，比分是4-3。
He had to score the team's first and last goal against Iceland and against France, 4-3.
Le tocó hacer el primer y último gol de la selección contra Islandia y contra Francia, el 4-3.
这是混乱，这是夸张，这是误解。
It was a mess, it was an exaggeration, it was a misunderstanding.
fue un quilombo, fue una exageración, fue un malentendido.
您如何定义2018年俄罗斯？
How do you define Russia 2018?
¿Cómo definís vos Rusia 2018?
如果你想要更短的搜索引擎优化，是的，它是一公里。
If you want the shorter seo, yes, it was a kilometer.
Si querés la seo más corta, sí, fue un kilómetro.
是基伦博吗？
Was it a quilombo?
¿Fue un quilombo?
到此结束，完成。
It ends there, done.
Se termina ahí, listo.
如果不是的话，大家都知道这件事发生在2018年的某一天，而且相当混乱。
If not, everyone already knows that it happened on one day in 2018 and it was quite a mess.
Si no, ya todos saben que pasó en un día de 2018 y era todo un quilombo.
但事实并非如此
but it's not not
pero no no es
这很困难，因为人们想在阿根廷获胜。
It is difficult because one wants to win in Argentina.
Es difícil porque uno quiere en Argentina ganar.
但现实是俄罗斯的一切都很复杂
but the reality is that everything in Russia is very complicated
pero la realidad es que está muy complicado todo en Rusia
现实就是如此
and the reality that was all
y la realidad que fue todo
从任何意义上来说都是一团糟。
a complete mess in every sense.
todo un quilombo en todo sentido.
尽管我进了球，但我很高兴，很高兴，因为打进世界球并不容易。
Even though I scored the goal, I am very happy, very happy, because scoring world goals is not easy.
A pesar de que hice el gol, estoy muy contento, muy feliz, porque hacer goles mundiales no es fácil.
但这一切都是美好的。
but it was all a good quilombite.
pero sí que fue todo un buen quilombito.
你在那里设置了 quilombos 还是他们已经到达 quilombos 了？
Did you set up the quilombo there or had they already arrived in quilombos?
¿Armó el quilombo ahí o ya habían llegado en quilombados?
听着，我不...不，对我来说...
Look, I don't... No, for me...
Mirá, yo no... No, para mí...
根据我的记忆，我认为它已经在那里了。
From what I remember, I think it was already there.
Por lo que yo recuerdo, creo que ya fue ahí.
是的，是之前，但告诉你，一个半星期前。
Yes, it was before, but to tell you, a week and a half before.
Sí, fue antes, pero por decirte, una semana y media antes.
因为一切都已经出现了问题，很明显......
because everything already came with a problem, it was already clear that...
porque ya todo venía con un problema, ya se veía que...
这将成为那届世界杯的一大主题。
which was going to be a big theme of that World Cup.
que iba a ser todo un tema de ese Mundial.
因为我记得也有一些东西出来了
because I remember that something came out too
porque me acuerdo que salió algo también
反对，已经一周前，
against, already a week before,
en contra, ya una semana antes,
在 AFA 有一个...
In the AFA there is one of the...
En la AFA hay una de las...
他在 AFA 工作，给圣保罗带来了麻烦，我们已经从那里开始了……
who worked at the AFA, making a problem for San Paolo, and we already started there with...
que trabajaba en la AFA, haciéndole un problema a San Paolo, y ya empezamos ahí con...
这就是整个话题的开始。
That's where a whole topic started.
Ya ahí empezó todo un tema.
话虽这么说，这是一个很大的话题。
And well, that being said, it was quite a topic.
Y bueno, dicho eso fue todo un tema.
后来呢，好吧，我没玩，但是我玩了。
Afterwards, well, I didn't play, but I played.
Yo después, bueno, no jugué, pero jugué.
你玩了，你就出来了。
You played, you came out.
Jugaste, saliste.
我打球，我出去，我回来，但什么也没有。
I played, I went out, I came back in, but well, nothing.
Jugué, salí, volví a entrar, pero bueno, nada.
教练已经知道我的想法了。
The coach already knows what I think.
Ya sabe lo que pienso el entrenador.
你和他说话了吗？
Did you talk to him?
Hablaste con él?
不，我没有说话，但你很清楚……不，在世界杯上是的，但不……
No, I didn't speak, but you know well that... No, in the World Cup yes, but no...
No, no hablé, pero sabe bien que... No, en el Mundial sí, pero no...
我没什么可说的，在我看来……我完全理解。
I have nothing more to say, it seemed to me... I understand perfectly.
No tengo más nada que decir, me pareció... Entiendo perfecto.
现在，除了与教练的混乱之外......
Now, beyond the mess with the coach...
Ahora, más allá del quilombo con el entrenador...
该组织说，我们有一个 quilombo。
The group says, we have a quilombo.
El grupo dice, tenemos un quilombo.
我们该如何解决它？
How do we fix it?
¿Cómo lo arreglamos?
你无法在那里修复它。
You can't fix it there.
No lo puedes arreglar ahí.
没有机会了。
There's no chance.
No hay ninguna chance.
你会怎样做？
What are you going to do?
¿Qué vas a hacer?
我们该怎么办？
What do we do?
¿Qué hacemos?
换球员？
Change players?
¿Cambiar jugadores?
你不能。
You can't.
No puedes.
所以球员们更换教练是不可能的。
So the players change coach, you can't.
Tan los jugadores cambian entrenador, no puedes.
没什么，就是...
Nothing, it's...
Nada, es...
等待阵容出现并进行比赛。
Wait for the lineup to appear and play.
esperar que dé la alineación y jugar.
在没有沟通的情况下，了解一个人所知道的和熟悉的事情。
to what one knows and well, without communication.
a lo que uno sabe y bueno, sin comunicación.
没有想法，没有任何东西，这就是我们所知道的
without ideas, without anything and well that's what we know and
sin ideas, sin nada y bueno es a lo que nosotros sabemos y
并在场上命令我们自己。
and ordering ourselves on the field.
y ordenándonos dentro de la cancha.
那是我们的世界杯。
That was our World Cup.
Ese era el Mundial de nosotros.
我们以二比一对阵法国。
We are two to one up against France.
Estamos dos a uno arriba contra Francia.
八分之一。
in eighths.
en octavos.
如果最后一场比赛你可能打成4比4平。
If the last play maybe you tied 4 to 4.
Si la última jugada quizás empatás 4 a 4.
也许会过去，如果我们去法国，
maybe passing, if we pass to France,
capaz que pasando, si pasamos a Francia,
这场事故似乎让你被排除在外，因为这届世界杯已经注定了……不可能有好的结果。
It seemed like you were left out in the accident because it was already destined that this World Cup... There was no way for it to turn out well.
pareía que quedas afuera en el accidente porque pues ya estaba destinado que ese mundial... No había forma de que saliera bien.
这是不可能的，这是不可能的。
It was impossible, it was impossible.
Era imposible, era imposible.
请注意，当他们输给法国队时，我们的脸
Notice that when they lost to France, our faces
Fijate que cuando perdió con Francia, las caras de nosotros
如果有其他世界杯上出现的图像，其他世界杯上的图像
If there are images that are out there in other World Cups, in other World Cups
si hay imágenes que por ahí en otros mundiales, en los otros mundiales
有悲伤。
There was sadness.
Se notaba una tristeza.
看看所有玩家的摄像机。
And look at the cameras of all the players.
Y vos fíjate en las cámaras de todos los jugadores.
就好像这件事即将发生一样。
It was like this was going to happen.
Era como cara de que esto iba a pasar.
很热，但是不，不……就像你以为这会发生一样。
hot, but no, no... It's like you thought it was going to happen.
caliente, pero no, no... Es como que vos pensás que iba a pasar.
也稍稍松了口气。
A little relief too.
Un poco de alivio también.
这已经超出了被排除在世界杯之外的愤怒范围。
It's over beyond the anger of being left out of the World Cup.
Se terminó más allá de la bronca que significa quedarte fuera del Mundial.
是的，一切都结束了，那时 AFA...
Yes, it was all over and that was when the AFA...
Sí, se terminó todo y ahí era que la AFA...
从此开始奔向下一届世界杯。
start heading from then on for the next World Cup.
empiece a encaminar desde ahí en adelante para el siguiente Mundial.
以最好的方式。
in the best way.
de la mejor manera.
到底发生了什么？
What was it that happened?
¿Qué fue lo que pasó?
幸运的是很多...
Luckily many...
Por suerte muchos...
没有人知道斯卡罗尼会是什么样子。
Nobody knew what Scaloni was going to be like.
Nadie sabía cómo iba a ser Scaloni.
但事实是他适应得很好，零经验。
But the truth is that he adapted very well, zero experience.
Pero la verdad es que se fue adaptando muy bien, cero experiencia.
他非常清楚自己的目标。
He was very clear about his objective.
Tenía muy claro el objetivo de él.
很轻。
Very light.
Muy claro.
是的，但是在那里，无论是第二名还是第三名，都不一样，因为他……
Yes, but being there is not the same, or being second or being third, because he was...
Sí, pero el estar ahí no es lo mismo, o ser segundo o ser tercero, porque él era...
如果你想称其为第三，那就是BKZS。
If you want to call it third, there is BKZS.
Si quieres llamarlo tercero, está BKZS.
这不一样，因为狮子座已经更......
And it's not the same because Leo was already more...
Y no es lo mismo porque Leo ya era más...
他来和我们一起玩，他和我们做爱，他打牌......
He came to play with us, he fucked with us, he played cards...
se metía a jugar con nosotros, jodía con nosotros, si jugaba a las cartas...
这是别的东西，当他们给予它时
It was something else and when they give it
era otra cosa y cuando le dan
茶的力量，显而易见
the power of being tea, obviously
el poder del ser de té, obviamente que
我们正想看看他会如何带我们，但是……
We were watching to see how he was going to take us, but...
estábamos viendo a ver cómo él nos iba a llevar, pero...
没什么，他很认真，我们已经迈出一步了......
nothing, he got serious, that we had a step there and...
nada, se puso serio, que nosotros teníamos ahí a escalón y...
他一直在惹我们生气，但是好吧，好吧，教练很认真。
He's messing with us all the time, but well, well, the coach got serious.
que está todo el tiempo jodiendo con nosotros, pero bueno, bien, el entrenador se puso serio.
他穿上工作服，说这就是我要做的，仅此而已。
He put on his work suit and said this is what I'm going to do and that's it.
Se puso ahí el traje de trabajo y dijo esto voy a hacer y se acabó.
好吧，尊重他所说的，但什么也没有
and well and to respect what he said but nothing
y bueno y a respetar lo que él lo que él dijo pero nada
事实是，不只是我这么说，很多人都这样告诉我。
The truth is that it's not just me who says it, many people tell me it.
La verdad que no lo digo solo yo, me lo dicen muchos.
很多球员认为那届俄罗斯世界杯，事实是那届世界杯并没有
many players that that World Cup in Russia, the truth is that it was not
muchos jugadores que ese mundial en Rusia la verdad que fue no
如果我们能走到最后或者进入决赛，那就是一个奇迹。
It was a miracle if we made it to the end or to the final.
Era un milagro si paseábamos en el final o a la final.
别笑。
Don't laugh.
No te rías.
无论是面具还是诚实。
Whether it's a mask or whether it's honest.
Que sea careta o que sea honesto.
你必须考虑。
You have to consider.
Hay que considerar.
如果没有的话，那我就傻了。
If not, well, I'm stupid.
Si no, bueno, soy carete.
如果没有，我们做得很好，但运气不好。
If not, we're doing great and, well, tough luck.
Si no, estamos muy bien y, bueno, mala suerte.
不，我们已经很忙了，仅此而已。
No, we're on the ass and that's it.
No, estamos para el culo y ya está.
最后一个问题。
The last question.
La última pregunta.
我对你的职业生涯有什么印象吗？
Do you have any image that I have of your career that is...?
¿Tiene alguna imagen que yo tengo de tu carrera que es...?
你即将进入 Independiente 0-San Lorenzo 1 球场，大头的 Bulleri 拥抱着你，给你最新的指示。
You are about to enter that Independiente 0-San Lorenzo 1 and the big-headed Bulleri hugs you and gives you the latest instructions.
estás por entrar en ese Independiente 0-San Lorenzo 1 y te abraza el cabezón Bulleri y te da las últimas indicaciones.
我建议
I propose that
te propongo que
作为结束语，让我们想象一下这一点。
By way of closing, let's imagine this.
A modo de cierre, imaginemos esto.
大头并没有给你指示。
The big head is not giving you instructions.
No está el cabezán dando te indicaciones.
现在是你了。
It's you now.
Estás vos ahora.
35 岁时与年仅 15 岁的塞尔吉奥 (Sergio) 交谈。
at 35 years old talking to Sergio who was just 15.
a los 35 años hablando con Sergio de apenas 15.
你对他说什么？
What do you say to him?
¿Qué le decís?
你知道塞尔吉奥即将进入独立的圣洛伦索。
You know that Sergio who is about to enter that independent San Lorenzo.
vos este cún a ese Sergio que está por entrar en ese independiente San Lorenzo.
好吧，我会告诉你......
And well, I would tell you that...
Y bueno, yo le diría que...
冷静地玩很有趣
play calmly it's fun
que juegue tranquilo que es divertite
你在这里是因为你应得的，因为你很健康，但是......
You are here because you deserve it, because you are fit, but...
estás acá porque te lo merecés, porque estás en condiciones, pero...
进来做你一直在做的事情。
Come in and do what you've been doing.
Entra y haz lo que venías haciendo.
享受游戏吧。
Enjoy the game.
Disfruta del partido.
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
我认为...
I think that...
Yo creo que...
奥斯卡的话也有两三句话，或许
Oscar's words were also two or three that perhaps
también las palabras de Oscar fueron dos o tres que quizás
或者想想如果是的话，你不能告诉他更多的事情，因为......
or think if yes, you can't tell him more things because...
o pensar si sí, no puede decirle más cosas porque...
他当时15岁，或者任何一个15岁就要成年的男孩，或者也是16岁。
He was 15 years old, or any boy who is going to adult at 15 years old, or 16 too.
Tenía 15 años, o cualquier chico que va a adultar con 15 años, o 16 también.
你不能对此抱有太多的怀疑。
You can't put too many doubts into it.
No le puedes meter muchas dudas.
没有太多疑问，但要填写一些东西，因为你开始怀疑，这是你的责任。
Not many doubts, but filling things in because you begin to doubt and it is your duty.
No muchas dudas, sino llenarle cosas porque se empieza a dudar y es su deber.
在生活中，当你和塞尔吉奥交谈时，你已经知道了一切。
And in life, when you talk to that Sergio, you already know everything.
Y en la vida, vos cuando hablás con ese Sergio, ya sabes todo.
你知道他在这20年里将要经历的一切。
You know everything he is going to experience in those 20 years.
Sabes todo lo que él va a vivir en esos 20 años.
你会对他说什么？
What would you say to him?
¿Qué le dirías?
就像准备地面一样。
Like preparing the ground.
Como preparándole el terreno.
什么，看。
What, look.
Che, mira.
呃……呃……
Uh... uh...
Eh... eh...
事实是，是的，我会说......
The truth is, yes, I would say that...
La verdad que sí, le diría que...
训练中的一切，所有比赛的一切。
that of everything in training, of all the games.
que de todo en el entrenamiento, de todos los partidos.
最重要的是，成为一个好伴侣。
and above all, be a good companion.
y que sobre todo sea buen compañero.
那不是
that's not
que eso no
前同事继续给您写信，这将永远伴随您。
That will stay with you forever, that former colleagues continue writing to you.
Eso te va a quedar para siempre, que ex compañeros te sigan escribiendo.
和？
and?
y que
并让糟糕的时光继续下去……
and let the bad times continue...
y que los malos momentos sigan...
继续相信你的才华、你的能力
keep trusting in your talent, in your
siga confiando en su talento, en su
在他一直做的比赛中
in his game that he always did and
en su juego que siempre hizo y
什么也没有，因为总会有这样的时刻
and nothing because there are going to be moments that
y nada porque va a haber momentos que
总会有糟糕的日子，这就是你必须找到前进的力量的地方。
There are going to be bad days and that is where you have to find the strength to move forward.
Va a haber malos días y ahí es donde tiene que sacar la fuerza para seguir adelante.
并继续相信
and continue believing that
y seguir creyendo que
你将会实现你想要的目标。
that you are going to achieve the goal you want.
que vas a conseguir el objetivo que querés.
成功并让人们、你的家人和全世界认可你......
succeed and have people and your family and the whole world recognize you for...
triunfar y que la gente y tu familia y todo el mundo te reconozca por...
感谢你这20年来所做的一切。
for what you did in all those 20 years.
por lo que hiciste en todos esos 20 años.
他把它放进去，我认为这是最重要的，我认为
that he puts it in, I think that's the most important thing and I think that
que le meta, creo que eso es lo más importante y yo creo que
从长远来看，遵守纪律并尊重
that in the long run being disciplined and being respectful of
que a la larga siendo disciplinado y ser respetuoso con
与队友和教练一起，从长远来看，我认为一切......
With teammates and coaches, in the long run, I think everything...
con los compañeros y entrenadores a la larga todo creo que...
你最终会得到回报。
you end up having your reward.
terminás teniendo tu recompensa.
任务完成了，对吗？
Mission accomplished, right?
Misión cumplida, ¿no?
确实，任务完成。
Exactly, mission accomplished.
Exacto, misión cumplida.
谢谢爸爸，很高兴。
Thanks dad, a pleasure.
Gracias papá, un placer.
不客气。
You are welcome.
De nada.
这就是我们的结局。
This is how we end.
Así terminamos.
伟大的结局。
Great ending.
Gran final.